Welcome back folks. We were going to do
some GUI programming and explore those
libraries in this section, however we're
actually going to do a different section
first and this is going to be about
essential modules and packages to extend
the programming language of Python
further from what I can do
out-of-the-box, and to accomplish some
common tasks by using Python. So, the
first one we're going to be covering is
called requests and this is an HTTP
library. It's not the only one and it's
not the best one, but it will be the
first one that you'll be introduced to
when learning Python as demonstrated
here in this course. So, what we're going
to do when you actually jump into
terminal here and as you can see I've
already installed it, but if you haven't
already manually installed it just type
"pip3 install requests" it's that simple, and
i'm going to get an already satisfied
message because I've already got it
installed. Now once you get it installed
you can import it so let's go ahead and
create a new Python file here. and I'm
just going to call it "requeststests" You
can name this file whatever you want,
just please follow along, and we're going
to make a very simple HTTP request,
and get some data back, and do stuff with it. So, let's go ahead and import requests,
and now we can use that class. So, let's
go ahead and create a variable called
"r = requests.get( )" Now there's a few things you can pass
into this, you can pass in the URL, the
parameters we will be going over that in
the next video, and then also some
headers which can tell the server what
kind of response you want or exactly what
you want. So let's go ahead and we're just
going to ping google here, so "(http://google.com")"
there we go. So, essentially we're going
to request the web page associated with
google.com. So if I were to open up a
browser here and go to google.com,
this is the page I will see. Now, of course this also
has external resources like the logo,
style sheets, and stuff, but we're not going
to be grabbing those we're just gonna be
grabbing straight HTML, and if those
assets are not included in a relative
path for example google.ca/images/
image.PNG and instead they're included
using a local path, we're not going to be
able to get these back, and you'll see
what I mean in just a moment.
Now once we've got the request made we
still haven't done anything with it, so
first we want to see the HTTP status
code of this request. So, let's go ahead
and "print("Status:", )" and how you access this the type of response is we're
going to use the "r" variable that we created we're going to go and then
we're just going to type in "r.status_code" So let's save it and
let's run this script...
oops...let's do it through here quest
tests,
there we go. If you know anything about
HTTP statuses, and even if you don't
we're gonna go over right now,
200 is what you want to see. 200
basically means it was found, it was
returned, no problem occurred. So as you see there's, not 200,
authoritative information, etc. Now 300
refers to redirects, 400
represents client errors, so this is
errors on your, so these are errors on
the client side. For instance,
forbidden if your client, if your machine
does not have access to certain
resources. 500 is server errors and so on
and so forth. We're not going to go too
in depth here it's just this gives you kind
of an idea of what you're looking at in
terms of a status code. Well, that's neat, but what
else can we do with this request? What
what do we actually have? So if you type
"r." you can see all the I guess methods or variables of this
object, and we can actually do quite a
bit of this. So, we can actually get the
URL, and this is going to give us the exact URL that we got the response from. So let's
go ahead and save and run it, and you'll
see that it populates all this, and if I
go back to the browser and go to Google,
click in here, we actually don't see all
that, but that's what we get returned
when using a Python. So, the next thing
we're going to do is actually get the
content of the page that we've requested and
this is the most, I guess the most,
important use case here.
So what you do is you're just going to
access the text variable it's built into
this object. Let's go ahead and run this
and you'll see it prints out the HTML
which we're not going to parse through,
that's going to be another module that
we're going through called beautiful
soup, and what that can do is we can then
pass r.txt in to beautiful soup and
we can parse it and it makes it really,
really simple to do stuff with it, so
that's cool. What we're going to do is
we're going to write this response into
an HTML file and then we're going to
load it up in a browser and see what it
looks like.
So we're going to go "f = open("./page.html", "w+")"
and then "f.write(r.text)" Let's go ahead and
save this and run it again. Now you'll see
we've got a new file here, so let's go
ahead, and I don't think I can open it in a
browser from here,
open a browser,
alright let's go ahead and open it in
the Safari here, and this is the webpage
that i have just essentially pulled off
the servers and saved to a file here. If
I inspect the element here you're going
to see that the image is a background
image and it's a local path, so what this
is doing now is it looking at the
root of our computer in this path for
the file and we don't have it, so it
shows up like that. I think it would also
show a lot of not found errors in the
console. So, that is an introduction to
requests. We're going to be going quite a
bit further with this and learning a lot
of awesome stuff that we can do with the
requests package.