So in the last video we learned how to
make a request to Google and returning
the homepage isn't really useful because we don't, I mean it's just a blank page.
So what we're going to learn about in this
video is parameters and how to pass get
variables, which they're known as in PHP,
into a web page. So if I do a search here,
let's go to google, the actual google, and
let's search for "pizza" if I click up in
here you'll notice that this gets added
to the are the URL, and if I do that
it also does. So, what we're going to go
ahead and do, is this working? There we go.
What we're going to go ahead and do is copy this, let me just see if I put the
question mark in before that,
ok that works too. Alright so we're going
to go ahead and copy this, this is the
URL that we want, so what we're going to
do is we're going to add a parameter
with the name of that, and it's going to be
equal to pizza. So, let's go over here, let's
create a new variable called "params = " this is going to
be the name of the variable, and then
actually don't need to add this,
going to be searching for "pizza" and then
we're going to put a comma here and
we're going to type ", params=params" and what this means is this is
the key word that's going into this method, this is the argument, and this is
our variable that we just created. So, if
we go ahead and save this and run it
again, we should now get a different
webpage returned to us, and what I'm
going to do it the page HTML i'm going
to go ahead and open it in Safari again,
and that did not work. So let's go ahead
and troubleshoot this a bit.
Let's go ahead and print the URL. So, see
what we're getting as a response here
from the URL. So it's still adding this.
Google might be a bad example for that,
let's go over to Bing. Let's try it with this.
Let's search for "pizza" on Bing, let's look at the URL how its structured, if I remove
everything but the pizza keyword it's
going to return it,
so that's what we want it to do. So let's go
ahead and q=pizza so
bing.com/search is the URL we're going to use, and simply is going to be Q equals
pizza, so let's go ahead and save, rerun
this file, and now if I open page.HTML in
the browser we should see a results page.
So I guess the way that Google
uses javascript to generate the results, I guess that was interfering with the actual
request that we were making to it, it just
returned blank page instead of the page
with the content, and we actually can
account for JavaScript rendered data not
by using request but using a few other
libraries that we're going to look at a
bit later.