Welcome back. So, what we're going to do now in order to demonstrate the
requests package ability to manage
binary data, instead of just the text
data that we were able to use to dump an
HTML page in the first video of this
subsection, the requests package
is able to manage its able to manage a
lot of different types of data but
specifically the one we're interested in
this video is going to be binary data. So
what we're going to do, we're going to
need actually another package installed
go ahead and open up terminal type "pip3
install pillow" and this is a image
processing library for Python. So, once
you've got that installed we can
actually important it. So of course the
first thing we need is "import requests"
and then we're actually going to also
need to import bytesIO and this is a
class that is going to help us actually use
the byte data. So "from io import BytesIO"
Iand then "from PIL" which is the
pillow library we just installed "import
Image" So we're good to go.
The first thing we obviously need to do is
make requests to the image that we want
to get, and it's going to go right there. Now I don't have an image yet but let's just
look up epic wallpaper.
Let's grab this one, actually it isn't a
full-size one, let's grab a large one.
Go ahead and view image, alright. So let's
just copy the image address. Normally if
I wanted to save an image I would just
right click &amp; save-image-as right there,
save to downloads, that wouldn't be
very useful to what we're trying to
demonstrate here today, so we're going to
do it using Python. Again, go ahead
and copy the image address, come back
over to our Python file here, and just
paste that in here. So it's a JPEG
image as we can see. Let's print out the
status code so "print("Status code:, r.status_code)" just to make sure if any error happens we want to
make sure we can you know tell what
error it is so "r.status code" Now
what we're going to do is actually
create an image from the binary data
that's returned from the request that we
made. So let's go ahead and type "image = Image" is
going to be a variable that contains the
image, we're going to use the image class
and the method ".open" from the image class. Now we need to use the "(BytesIO( )"
and we use that, we pass into that the content of the request. So
instead of using r.text, which will
return text responses, we're going to use
the "(r.content)" this is binary data right
here. So we're going to pass into BytesIO,
it's going to allow us to
use it by going with Image.open, this
is going to convert it into an image
that we can then use and save. So i'm
going to go ahead and type the path of
the image that we're going to save it. So,
"path = "./image.jpg" and for right now I'm just going
to print out some data about the image
so "print(image.size, image.format, image.mode)"
"print(image.size, image.format, image.mode)"
Go ahead and save this and then run
this file, and you see what we get is
Status code: 200 because we were able to access the image, we get the size so (1600,
900), then we are able to get the format
which is jpeg, and the mode which was
RGB. So, that's awesome. What we can do with the image itself though we can
actually save it to the current, we're
going to save it to the current
directory, so where I made that path
right there. So we're going to use a try
except. So let's go "try:image.save(path)" and then just the past we want to save it to
and then the format. So we're going to
save it in,
ah I forgot to skip a line there, there we go, going to save it to JPEG. Now another thing
that you could do is if we move this to
under the print statement right there
where we print out the format, i'm
actually going to copy that right there,
and what we're going to do is that,
whoops. So it's going to be called
"path = "./image." + image.format" whatever format that is, so we'll be able to save PNG, gif images, etc. and then
what we're going to do is we're going to
save it again with the format. We're
going to "except IOError:" this
basically means that we just weren't
able to do whatever is in the try block
of code, and so I'm just going to print
out "print("Cannot save image.")" that should be enough.
So let's go ahead and save this and
let's run the file again. As you can see
image.JPEG saved right here, and if I go
ahead and open it it's the exact image that
I selected back here. Let's go ahead and
try
and find a PNG wallpaper,
just make sure that it does save in the
correct format. Is this PNG? Awesome.
It's quite large too it looks like. Let's go ahead and choose one that's not so large, I
guess, this one right here.
My internet connection must be bad right
now look how long, this reminds me of
back in the mid-nineties when you go to
a web page and you wait and this is how
the images with load on the webpage. I
think it's done now so i'm going to do
is go ahead and copy the image address,
come back over here, going to paste this in
here which is a PNG image, so we should
see and i'm going to change this to image1
so our original image doesn't get overwritten, and let's go ahead and run this again,
and just wait because it is a large image, and this is actually the same thing as
loading in browser. Our computer
is using our internet connection so it's
going to be a little slower and as you can
see the saved as a PNG image. So let's go
ahead over here and open image1.PNG, we could convert this to lower case as
well, however we're not really gonna
worry about that right now, let's
go ahead and just end the video here.
We're going to be doing a few more
things in the next video regarding the
requests package, so thank you guys for
watching and I'll see you guys in the
next video.