So far we've been using the requests
package to the extent of getting data,
but what happens if we actually want to
post data? So, when you build an HTML form
there's two types of ways that the form
can submit, basically there's a get and
post. Let's say you have a forum with
name and email address setup, and the
names of each input is name and email. If
you set the form type to get. then
basically what's going to happen is when
you hit submit all of the parameters are
going to be added to the URL similar to
how we did the to get request on Bing
for images last time, or a search query.
So that's a get request, basically they
go into the URL, but a post request
is not shown in the URL so it's
information that's sent in the headers
only. So we can actually use the requests
package to do that. So let's go ahead and
open up
PyCharm here, let's remove this we
actually don't need anything except
requests for this, and let me open up
Safari. So I have found a page that has a
simple form and it posts to I think
itself, does it post to itself? No, it posts to
welcome.php, so this is the URL that we
need.
So let's go ahead and create a request, so
r = requests.post" So this time we
are not using get, we're using post. Going
to enter the URL here that we want to
post to, and then we're going to add in
the data. So, data is going to be equal to
my data "data=mydata" Let's go ahead and create "my_data = " and I believe that the two inputs
here are named name and email, as my example, they are name and email so let's go
ahead and add a name and email.
So "{"name": "Nick"," and
"email": "nick@example.com"}"
So these are the two variables that
we're gonna be sending in a post format
to this URL which is welcome.php,
and we're actually going to capture the
response so let's go ahead and actually
just save it into, do we have an HTML file?
Let's just save it into an HTML file. So,
let's go ahead and open, actually,
"f = open("myfile.html", "w+")" and "f.write" and we're going to write
"(r.txt)" Let's go ahead and save
this and then run the file, and what
we're going to get is this myfile.html. Now where PHP is rendered on the
server side we should get this page that
says Welcome Nick, Your email address is:
nick@example.co, and that's the same as if we enter that information here, I just cannot
spell my name is today, you'll see that
that's the exact same thing. So that's a
way to post specific data to URL, and
that's going to be useful if you're
working with API's and whatnot.