Hey guys, welcome back. What we're going to do now is get a JSON response from
requests, and it's basically the same as
just parsing regular JSON. Now what you
see on my screen here is the Google URL
shortener, and if you go to developers.google,
if you go to this domain right here
url-shortener/v1/getting_started
Woah, i'll put that link in the discussion
on the side there. You'll see this page
basically that explains how to use the
the shortener via well, first you have an
example using curl, we're going to go
through and make this work with Python,
basically. So here's the URL that we need
to post to right here, that's the
content-type, and then we also need to
post this variable, and then whatever URL
we're trying to shorten.
So let's go ahead we're going to copy the
URL of the URL shortener, I'm just going
to come up here and we're going to
"import simplejson as json" first, and then we're going
to create a payload of data and what
that and with that generally refers to
in programming is basically the data
that you're sending to a URL, it's a
payload. So what we're going to do we're
going to create that now. So the
"payload = {"longUrl":"  and that's going to be, let's go with...
I need a domain here...
this is not still up so it won't show if it
works or not. Now, okay, we need a domain that does work so let's just go ahead
and go to example.com, good stuff. So this is the URL we're
going to shorten. We should be able to
access this from within our code
basically. So let's go ahead and remove this, paste that in there "http://example.com" So that's the
payload that we're going to set up, now we actually need to create the request. So
"r = requests.post( )" and the
request URL is going to be that right
there, so let me copy that, set that to
URL right there. So simply i'm going to
send "(url, )" and then the JSON data. What we're going to do is we're going to
"json=payload)"
So, what we're going to do here, and let's see if that works we may actually need to
convert this into JSON before sending
it over as JSON and I believe this is
yeah, content type is JSON. So let's go ahead and add a header here in the
content-type and I add headers using
requests, very similar, "headers = {"Content-Type":
"application/json"}" there we go.
So we've just built a request basically it's
the same as this. We're sending over
headers telling it what content type it
is, then we're also sending along data
and this is a JSON formatted, and we're
accessing that URL. So, this basically
should work and we should be able to get
a response, so
let's go ahead and "print(r.txt)" Let's
see what we get is a response, let's go
ahead and run this. So as you can see we
get an error that's in JSON format, so
we can actually load that string. Where
is JSON, and then you can see it's
displayed a little different, I can go
"["error"] ["code"]"
"code"])" As you can see it's able to
traverse the Jason data that we're
getting back. Now, obviously, I haven't
set up an API key for this URL so it's
going to give me that bad request,
however we've sent all the data
along that and as you can see, let me go
over here, if we didn't send the correct
information over it would actually be a
different error code. It would basically
say the message required parameter is
not included, and
that's because here in the URL in the
browser we did not actually post any
data to it.
In our script here we do post the data and
we post it as JSON, so it's giving us
not the error message that we
didn't do it correctly, but just that the
daily use has been exceeded and that
basically means that we would need to
set up an API code and the yeah, in
order to get that work. So, that is how to
both send JSON data and to receive
JSON data, and how to traverse it
using requests.