Hey guys, the last part of requests
package that we're going to be
discussing is the headers. So, we've been
sending very few headers here and
there's actually quite a few more you
can send. If you're not familiar with
headers i recommend reading up on them,
there's a lot of different ways you can
spoof rendering engines and browsers if
you need to, you can spoof quite a bit of
information, or just configure the post
request or get request to how it needs
to be sent by using headers, but we
didn't discuss is actually how to get
headers back and how to look at those. So,
basically it's really simple you just
print out or do whatever you want with
the request object at the headers
property.
So let's go ahead and save this and run
this again, and you'll see that we've got
quite a few headers sent back from the
server. So, max-age=0, Transfer Encoding,
chunked, etc., and if this is all
gibberish to you that's ok, that's not
really what we're focusing on, but if you
do need it then it's all right there if
you want to debug some stuff, or if you
just want to capture it save it
somewhere.