Hey guys, welcome back. So we're done
with section 2. Section 2 is basically
basic concepts that we needed for
programming with Python, and so we
learned some stuff enough to actually
build a program, and now we're going to
get into more advanced things. So the
first thing I wanted to start out with
is the pep guidelines, and this is
because throughout this course you're
not only going to have to get use to the syntax of Python, but you're going to have to
get used to writing it properly. So let's
go ahead and get started. First, let's
cover imports because that's going to be
at the top of the file. So when you
import something let's say we wanted to
import two modules we want to import OS
and sys "import os, sys" which are two modules that Python includes, or it actually ships with,
so you have these two modules right away. What you're seeing there is bad, so it
will actually underline it and it says
unused enforce statement, that's not the
reason it's bad,
we're actually comma separating
different modules entirely. So we don't
want to do that. What we want to do
instead is actually import on separate
lines, multiple modules.
However, if you're importing
multiple classes from a module, you can
actually comma separate the values. So
you type from my module include foobar
"from MyModule include foo, bar, foobar"
and this is underlining it red because I
don't have a module named "MyModule"
and I also I don't have any of these
created, but you should be able to
do it like this using comma separated
values for an import statement and actually, I
accidentally typed include "import" So
from the module that you want to import,
import, and then a comma separated list,
or comma separated string of what you
want to include, so that's okay like that.
Now from this point we need to drop down
not one line, but two lines, so I've got
two black lines there, and then we can
start with defining classes and
functions if we want. So what we're going
to do is let's create a couple of
functions. "So, I def my_function( )"
there's a few things that I want to
point out here. First, let's go ahead and
give this function some parameters "(one, two, three, four, five, six)"
Now, once we've got a bunch of parameters we want to keep this readable ,and so
sometimes it's necessary to break each
to break it down to a few lines. This is
how it should look where the parameters
are start being instantiated should be
the beginning of each next new line. So
for instance, that would not be correct,
right, that would definitely not be
correct. I think it will actually unline it
underline, yeah, so visual indentations
what it's talking about. Alright, let's go
ahead and create another function called
"def second_function( ):" It's going to take no
parameters, but it is just going to "print("Second function")" There's a problem with this is
well because there's only one line
between these two declarations of
functions or definition, so we need to
add two lines between top level
functions
and top level classes as well. So,
between the end of one function and the
definition of another function you need
two blank lines. Now, the indentation that
I showed you up in my function here,
that's also true for lists. So if I want to
create my list which is going to be a
list of numbers and I wanted to break
each item in the list down, it should be
indented the same way which means,
basically think of like a width kind of
thing of this list. It starts here and then
the entire list is like, what, three or
four columns. It's 1, 2, 3, 4 and then that, and so the end of it should be visually
indented, I mean you do this, you wouldn't
do that, and you wouldn't do
that, and know you this is how the
proper indentation should look. Now
let's go ahead and jump into PyCharms
preferences for the next one, code style,
here we go.
So in PyCharm again go into
preferences.
Once you're there, you're going to see
tabs and indents, and so this is another
pep guideline, basically it's recommended
that you use four space characters like
1, 2, 3, 4, and you can tell because, i'm not
sure if you guys can see this but,
there's little dots here under each one,
and also you can go left and right along
them. So when using the tab key what it's
going to do is insert 4 spaces instead
of actually the tab character. However,
you can change this to use the tab
character instead, and you'll see that
when we go left and right it's a width
four spaces, so it will work with Python.
But, we don't want to do that unless the
code that you're working on somebody
else already did that,
then you should do it the same way, and
that's just for consistency within the
code you don't want to
mix &amp; mash. So for right now just set your tab size to fou,r indent to four, and
continuation indent to 8, I guess, yeah. So,
click OK there, and that's all we're
going to talk about indentation, really.
The maximum line length should be 79
characters, this should be already set in
in PyCharm. So another one that we
should talk about here is over usage, i'm
going to remove that because that red
line is getting annoying, over usage of whitespace. Some people think it makes it look more
readable, but it doesn't. So, for instance,
this is bad. If we remove the the
white space around the string here
that's good.
Don't put any white space between, just I mean use your logic a bit, you
wouldn't also do this, and leave no
whitespace because that's not how we use
a comma i guess in the English language.
So, it should feel natural when you're
writing Python code to do things a
certain way. Now the same is true if I
have this list right here and I wanted
to reference the first item in it.
What I would do is "my_list" here's how I
would instantiate it,
that is correct, that is not correct,
that's too much white space so we just
don't add white space there. Same is true for
functions. Don't use too little, but then
also don't use too much, you know.
Again, it should feel like you're writing
in English, so that's pretty neat
regarding Python there. I mean it
just by nature feels more natural.
This is also true
for math equations. So, if I wanted to set "x = 3 * 52 + 7" you might think,
oh, well, this looks perfectly fine. So, in
this instance the reason that this white
spacing is incorrect basically I mean
use your own judgment, but here if you
want to add any white space to this
equation, you should add it at the
lowest priority operator. So in this case
the multiplication is going to have a
higher priority than the addition which
means that's going to happen first and
also if we put it like that. So "7*2"
and "3*52" hold a higher priority than
in addition, so both of these are going
to be evaluated as multiplication first
and then added together, which means the addition sign here has a lower priority
than the multiplication, so you can
separate, you can play space
around the low priority operator there,
and this is good, but this is not good,
and also keep your white space, keep
everything consistent. If you do one
thing in one place, and the same
circumstances are true in another place, do
the same there. Now regarding if
statements and how it should look, "if
check is True:" what we need to do now is
drop down to the next line and "print(
"This is true")" and we're just going to
define "check = True" here. So, you guys
already know how this is going to run,
but this is how you should be writing it.
You might want to put a extra line there.
You should not be writing if statements
like this, this is just, I mean it's just not
good.
Now when you're calling a function, you
could let's say if check is true, and we're
going to continue in this statement here,
or actually let's just write it outside of the
statement. So, again, this is incorrect,
you don't wanna write it like this. Let's
say we're going to call three functions.
So, "func_one( ) ; func_two( ); func_three( );"  However, don't do
this, it's is just bad. So if you're going
to call multiple functions, do it on
different lines. So that's all I want to
talk to you guys this point about pep
guidelines.