Alright, so what we're going to talk
about now is some while loop additional
functions, or additional handlers let's
say. So I've created a project here
called attack and i'm just going to
create a new Python file again called
attack, and what this is gonna do think
of think this as a part of a
battle system. So this is just going to
be very straightforward and very simple
right now, but actually when we get to
the end of this section or module of videos
we are going to be creating an entire
battle system using what we're going to
be learning in the next few videos as well
about classes, and whatnot. So, for right
now let's just go ahead and talk about
how to handle certain attacks and stuff. So, the
first thing we're going to do is create
a variable called a "playerhp = 260"
to be equal to let's say 260. Now we're
going to create an enemy attack power, so
what we're going to do is just set the
"enemyatk = 60" and
this is going to be, actually let's
create a range for enemy attack. So
"enemyatkl = 60" and then
"enemyatkh = 80" So this is
going to be used to create a random
number between these two values. So what we're going to do we're going to
actually have to import random, so "import random" I nearly spilled my coffee there.
Alright, so what we're going to do is we're
going to generate a random attack power
between 60 and 80 on each attack, I guess, so we need to create a while
loop. So let's go ahead and say "while
playerhp &gt; 0:" so as
long as the player has health
they're going to be attacked. So, let's go
ahead and say, let's first generate the
attack power. So how we do that is by
using the random range.
Hold on let me open a terminal right quick.
Okay, that's random range, cool. So, "random.randrange( )" and we're going to enter two
numbers here, and the first number is
going to be the starting point, and the
second number is going to be the high
point. So let's go ahead and enter
"enemyatkl, enemyatkh)"
So, we're going to assign this to a
variable of "dmg =" for damage, so this is going
to be the damage that the player takes.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to take the player HP and we're going to
subtract damage from it. So, let's go
ahead and new HP, actually let's just set
it to player HP, so "playerhp = playerhp
- dmg" So let's go ahead and
now make a print statement, so
"print("Enemy strikes for", dmg, "points of
damage.
Current HP is", playerhp)" So this is going to work right down to
the point where the players HP is a zero.
So if it becomes 0, or less than 0, it's
going to stop the loop.
So what we can do is we can save this right now. Let's go ahead and configure a run
here, there. So what we see here is the
first attack enemy strikes for 77 points
of damage, current HP is 183. Then enemy strikes for 73, current HP is 110, etc. and
this goes right down to the point where
his health becomes negative -30. Now, what
we want to do here we want to actually
handle this a bit, so what we can do is
"if playerhp &lt;=0:" "playerhp = 0" Let's go ahead and
save this again, and this is going to make
it so that if it does go down to
-30 it's just going to say it's 0. So let's go ahead and
rerun this and we're going to see that
does actually take effect. So if it's
zero, "if playerhp == 0:"
we're going to print out another message
"print("You have died.
You cannot respawn, as you are dead.")" My fingers do not want to type today.
We rerun it and you can see what
happens you you would be able to guess
what happens, however this will work as a
basic while loop and this would work for
an attack process, but
let's say in the game we're making we
don't want the players help to be able
to reach zero because that's immersion breaking. So what we want to
happen is if the players HP gets low,
they will be
magically teleported to the nearest
medical center, or inn if it's in a
fantasy type of role playing game. So
let's go ahead and do that.
So, what we need to do is, let me see here, if player HP less than or equal,
"if playerhp &lt;= 30" ok. So we're going to set a minimum hit points here of 30. So if it's
30 we're going to do something, if it's
not 30 we're going to do something else.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to print, actually we're going to print
the same thing, so let's go ahead and
copy this, move this. Actually, so we're
still going to print out this statement
because we still want to see the HP
update and whatnot, but then we're
going to do down here is we're going to
say "if player hp == 30:"
let's "print("You have low health. You've been teleported to the
nearest inn.") So if we save this,
there we go. It's going to continuously
run and that's a problem because
what happens is we say as long as player
HP is more than zero do all this, but
then we reach a point where we don't
allow the players HP to reach zero and
this is why we need a break. So let's go
ahead and add this in here. All you need
to do is literally call the word "break"
let's rerun this and it should not
endlessly run, and you can see that's
that's what happened, so.
So what it does basically again let's go
through this from the top. We're importing
random here so that we can generate a
random number between two values, so the
two values that were generating is the
low attack power which is 60 and high
attack power which is 80. We're setting
the players hit points by default to 260.
Then we're actually creating the loop
here, so what we're doing is we're saying
while player HP is more than 0, do
this, and in here we generate the damage,
we calculate the players new HP, and then
we say if it's less than or equal
to 30 it's going to be equal to 30, and
then we do this so we print the
basically the attack details, and then we
say if player HP is 30, because that's
the lowest it can go right here, then we
say you have low health, etc., and then we
break out of the while loop. So that's
how to use the break statement in a
while loop, in the next video we're going
to be going a bit further into this
while loop.
We're going to be using the keyword,
continue.