Alright guys, so let's talk about the
continue statement which is the opposite
of break, and to best explain what this
does what i'm
going to do is use the existing code
that we have here for this attack system,
and what I'm going to do is I'm just
going to change it a little bit. So right
now what happens,
let's run this, and what it does is it
starts the loop, it generates a number of
damage, and then it subtracts that from your current HP, and then it just runs loop
over again, until if your HP becomes
less than or equal to 30 it sets it to
30, that's the lowest the HP
can go, and then it prints out you know
etc. So the minimum that your
HP will print out at is 30,
and then what it does after is it does this
print statement that says if the player hit
points equals 30, then you have low
health, you can teleport to the nearest
inn, and then it breaks out of the loop.
But what can do is actually do this
exact same thing just a bit differently.
So what we're going to do is move these
two statements out of that if, and drop that down here. Now if we run this code right now
it's going to give an error, because we
have an empty if statement. If you have
an empty block of code, Python will freak
out because it doesn't know what to do
with empty block code. So also here's a
bonus statement it's called pass. So if you
want to create an empty block of code,
instead of leaving it empty, just type
"pass" Now this will run once actually,
regardless because we don't
actually have this in an if
statement. So at the end of the first
loop it it automatically says you have
low health even when you don't. So what we're going to do, is we're going to
change this from "if playerhp = 30:" to "if playerhp &gt; 30:"
and what we're going to do here is type "continue" and I'm going to run this
and it's going to do the exact same
thing that it did last time but it's a bit
different. So
to explain a bit better what's happening
is it's running this block of code and
then it says is the player hit points
more than 30, if it is then continue. So
what this continue statement does is it
it ignores everything after that in the
in the loop, and it just continues from
the beginning right away. So we won't
reach this if we call continue before
this. So that's just a different way of
doing the exact same thing. Now in the
next video we're going to get started on
classes, and what classes are, and why we
should use them, and then you know by the end of this module again we're going to
be using classes to do a full on role playing game battle system.