Alright guys, so let's start talking
about classes and objects and what those
are. So in order to do that I'm going to
change this script a bit so we have two
enemies attacking us. We're actually
going to create full-fledged enemies by
using a class. So, let's go ahead and
create a class and how you do that is
use the keyword class, and then you name your class similar to how you would name
a function, so let's go ahead and "class Enemy:" You actually don't need the parentheses
there. What we're going to do is we're
going to set attack power within this
class, so all enemies are going to have
attack equal to let's say sixty "atkl = 60" and
again we're going to set two. So attack high is going to be 80 "atkh = 80" So a class is a
blueprint for objects, so rather than
having to create manually the same
object over, and over, and over we can
use a class to set certain
variables and functions that are going
to be the same across all instance
instantiations of this class called an
object. So, you guys will see what I mean
here pretty soon. So what we have here is
a class, and each, well hold on, let's
just create a function here called
"def getAtk(self):" and you'll notice that as soon
as I create the parentheses there at the
end of any function within a class it
passes itself the self variable, and what
that is basically it's the entire
object that we instantiate from this
class, and you'll see what I mean but what
we can do is we can print out this
"print(
let's say the attack low variable "print( )" Now you might be
thinking ok, just print "atkl" that
wouldn't work actually because there's
no variable outside of this class named
that.
So what we need to do is we need to use
"self" So think of self as this instance
of the object, so we're going to print
this instances attack low-end,
"(self.atkl)" So what we can do there,
I'm going to comment out the rest of my
code, we're gonna be reusing it, but we're
not reusing it right now. So, let's just get
rid of that for now, and what we're gonna
do is we're going to, we're going to get
the attack power of the class. So, if we
were just to run "getAtk" it's not
going to be able to find it because this
doesn't exist in the global scope of
things. What we need to do first is we
need to instantiate the enemy class into
it's own object, so what we're going to do
is we're going to type "enemy1 = Enemy( )" and now what we can do is we can
call "enemy1.getAtk( )" and as
you'll see it
autocompleted that because it knows what we're doing. So let's save this and run
it, and we'll see that one time it
prits out 60 because there's one
instantiation of this class. Now what
happens if we create another object
"enemy2" and we also get the attack
power of that enemy? So what we're going
to do is hit the play button here, the
start button, and it's going to run on
this class well it's going to
instantiate the class twice so it's
going to create two objects, and then for
each one of those it's going to, it's
going to run this function which prints
out it's attack power. So
that's how to create a
class and how to create an object from
that class. I hope that you guys can kind
of understand what we're doing, we're
going to get more into this actually in
the next few videos, and we're going
to be using classes for the final
project at this module as well.