Alright, so we just learned how to create
objects but these are very static
because everything is statically coded,
so how can we create two different
enemies with different attack powers
using the same class?
Well, all we need to do is use what's
called the init function. So what we're
going to do is remove these because we
don't need them right now. I'm going to
"def__init__(self):" and I actually need to "def" that. So, again
this is a function so you need to
precede it with the word def, and then two
underscores, the word init, two
underscores, and then you also pass
itself. So what we're going to do in this
init function is we're going to accept,
and this this code runs when
the class has been instantiated or when
an object has been created from this
class, so what we're going to do is we
are going to pass two other variables
into this initiation function which is
going to be "atkl, atkh"
What we're going to do is we're going
to set "self.atkl = atkl "
and "self.atkh =atkh"
So what this is going to do is as you can see down here we're calling the self attack
low, but if we don't specify it
within the class here as a variable it
doesn't get created, so what we do in order to make this more
dynamic is we use an initiation function
or an initialization function,
we pass variables into here, and then we
can use these variables to set object
properties here. So, let's go ahead and
see what this is going to do. We're not
calling the the class properly now and
what you'll see is if i save this, and
run, it's going to freak out because we're
trying to instantiate it here, passing no
values through, and you'll see on the
screen here is parameter atkh
unfilled. So it's expecting
these two parameters to be passed
through in the instantiation of that
class. So what I'm going to do, we're going to set the attack low of this enemy and
that is going to be equal to let's say
40, let's say he's a week enemy, and then
the high is going to be 49. And then for
the second enemy we're going to call,
while we're going to pass in the parameters 75 and 90. So now what we'll get when
we hit ctrl or command + s, or when you
save the file and we run it,
it's going to print out the low attack
power for each instance
of this class, and so you can see that by
using the init function we can make this
more dynamic and now each instantiation
of this class can have its own
properties and it can be its own object.