Alright, so I wanted to talk about the
two different types of variables that
you can set within a class because we've
already set both of them but they both do
very different things. So, an instance
variable is a variable that is different
or can be different for every instance
of the class, so for instance we're
setting "self.atkl" which means this
instance the attack low, but in the
previous set example and what if we want
to set HP of the enemy to let's say 200?
So every enemy is going to have 200 hp.
So let's go ahead and create a function
to get HP "def getHp(self): and let's
"print("Hp is", self.hp)" and here we're going to say "print("atk is", self.atkl)"
So what we can do down here is we can
run "enemy1.get Hp( )" and we will also run
"enemy2.getHp( )" and hit save, and what
we'll see the first enemy has an
attack power of 40 and HP of 200, and the second enemy has attack of 75 and HP of
200 as well because we're setting sort
of a static variable with class.