So something we haven't discussed yet is
how to make comments in your code, which
is very important when you are getting
into any type of coding. Now, this is
important for a few reasons. First off,
you know you might write a ton of code
one day and just to try to get as much of
its can, and then you come back to later
and it seems maybe you can't you know
remember why you did something, and so
this is a way to leave notes for you to
look at in the future, or for other
developers to be able to kind of
understand what you're doing as well.
So let's go ahead and open the first
program here. Now there are two types of
comments you can leave in Python, one is
a single line comment, and the other is a
is a multi-line comment. So for instance,
let's go ahead and at the very top of this
program let's add a multi-line comment.
How you do that is you create ' ' '
quotes, and then anything inside these
three quotes is going to be interpreted
as a comment. So, for instance, we can
write "Program: Magical Calculator"
"Author: Nick G" "Copyright 2016" and so that's how you can add multi-line comments and
you can do this anywhere in your code on
a new line. Now, for a single comment
you're just going to do it like this, so
for instance let me indent here, just
put a hash sign "#" there, and then anything after this hash sign on the single line
will be interpreted as a comment. So, "# if
user quits --&gt;" this kind of explains the
next block of code here so anybody
looking through the code will realize
okay well if the user quits
that's what this relates to. So, let's go
ahead and add another one here,
"# If there has been a previous calculation, use that result as the prompt" there we go,
and so as you can see comments are going to become really useful as we code.