Alright guys, what we're going to do
before we get into the role playing game
battle script program is we're going to
learn how to import modules that we define
ourselves from relative paths. So what I
mean by that is this is just to keep
your code readable, you shouldn't define
classes inside of your main file,
that does get pretty messy and it makes
it hard to read through it, where if you
have like if you break it up into
multiple files it's going to make it a
lot easier. So what we're going to do is
we are going to create a class. So we're
going to go ahead and create a new
directory,
we're going to call it classes, and then
inside this classes directory what we
need to do to be able to import classes
from this directory, we need to add an
empty file with the name
"__init__"  So just like
the class method for the init
function this is just going to be an
empty file so we just create it. Now in the
classes directory we can start to create
our class, so what we're going to do is
create a file called "enemy" and then in
this file
we're going to just define "class Enemy:"
and "def __init__(self, hp, mp):"
What we're going to do is we're going to set "self.max_hp = hp"
and "self.hp = hp" and "self.max_mp = mp" "self.mp = mp"
and if any of you are not role-playing
game fans this is just the HP is your
health and the MP is your magic points, and magic spells cost magic points. So, we're
just going to create one more function
in here the class method called "def get_hp(self):"
and what this is going to do is just
going to "return self.hp" Let's go ahead
and save this, let's go back to our
attack script. So, before we can start
using that enemy class within our script
we need to import it. So how we do that
we need to first tell python that it's a
relative import, so we're going to say
"from classes.enemy import Enemy" To break this down a bit
you might think well he should'nt that be a slash? No, that's not how imports work with Python.
So what we do is instead of putting "/"
there as a relative path you put a "." and
then from here we're just going to
instantiate the "enemy = Enemy(200, 60)"
"enemy = Enemy(200, 60)" and then just to confirm that we've got
that imported correctly we're going to
"print(enemy.get_hp())" and save this and run
the file, and we see 200. So, I'm actually
going to just put ""HP:" make it a little
cleaner, save it, run it again, there we go. So, that shows the current HP of the enemy.