Hey guys, welcome back. In this section of videos, or this subsection because we're
still on section 5, this will be 5.3 I
guess, we're going to be covering a
package called PyMongo and what it is
a Python binding for the program
Mongo or MongoDB. So if you don't know what Mongo is or MongoDB you're probably
going to love it, and if you do know
what it is you probably already love it,
so let's get into it. For those of you
who don't know let me bring up a browser
here. and let's go to "mongodb" So, MongoDB is a NoSQL database driver, so if you've
done any work in PHP you've probably
used my MySQL, and that's I mean it's
just it's a relational database that has
to have a certain structure, so each
table needs to have a certain amount of
columns, and then when you insert data
you need to like if information isn't
sent in for a specific column the column
still exists it's just blank, and so you
have to follow the same structure, but
with MongoDB you can really you don't
have that limitation so it's a bit
different in that regard. If you guys
don't have it you're going to need to
install MongoDB on your computer.
With Windows you should be able to
just come to the site and open-source
I believe download, alright there is a
great big button right there.
Alright, so, you can get it for free
with different platforms, the
installation is going to be a bit
different for each one. If you're using
Linux you should be able to go through
your package manager and install it by
default, so if you you know you can
install it through yum, I believe you can
install it with apt-get as well. With OS 10
we're going to be installing with
homebrew,
so I'm not gonna be downloading this. On
Windows you are going to be downloading
the installer and you're gonna be
running that. So, I've already got this,
so you need to install two things to use
with Python, you need to install
MongoDB itself and then you need to
install the Mongo bindings for
Python. So to install MongoDB on OS 10
basically we're going to using homebrew
again, so jump in the terminal type "brew
install mongodb" is it or mongod?
It is one of the two sometimes they use
different package names specifically.
Alright, so it is MongoDB and I already
have it installed so I'm going to get this
message.
You guys probably don't or if you do
awesome. Once you get MongoDB installed
you need to start it, so go ahead run
"brew services start mongodb" and
mine is already started I guess it's
configured to start on boot, so that's
awesome.
Now once you've got all this setup you
have Mongo installed you should be able
to type "curl http://localhost27017" So if you get
this message it means that MongoDB is
setup and configured properly. If you
have any other issues I could try to
help you out but not doing this course
specifically on MongoDB, but I will do my
best
you should also be able to find support
on the documentation they should also
have a support page on the website as well.
Now once you do have Mongo setup you
need to install a Python package called
PyMongo. So go ahead run "pip3 install pymongo" and now I don't have
it installed yet and that's how quick it
is to install, so just grab the, grab the
file, have it installed, and now we're
good to go. So I'm going to clear this.
Now if I open back up the browser you
should just be able to Google "pymongo"
and it should
here we go that's the API. Here's a
tutorial database API documentation,
alright. So here's some documentation
this should be a full referenced so if
you need any help with Mongo or
PyMongo you should be able to get the
help here. So, MongDB's official
website api.mongodb.com/python/current/api
Alright, now let's jump into a Python shell, so "python3" and
we're good to go.
First thing we need to do obviously
we're going to need to "import pymongo"
just like that, it's that simple,
and then let's go ahead and run a Mongo
client. So what we need to do is now
import "MongoClient( )" I believe.
Let's check this out if it's not already
installed, alright it's not defined. So
what we need to do is "from pymongo
import MongoClient" and it's camelcase.
Once you get Mongo client imported you
now need to actually instantiate the Mongo
client, so basically it's really simple
to instantiate it. Create a variable
called "client = MongoClient( )" and
its class, and we just created an object
from that. Now alternatively this is
going to connect on the default host and
port which means writing that is
essentially the same as writing this. So
if you have it set up to run on a
different port or a different host, you
will be able to connect like this, change
the port or the house
accordingly. Now, additionally, you can use a mongo URL. So what a mongo URL is, is a
specific URL that Mongo can use to
connect to a machine. So how you are gonna do
that is rather than using HTTP which are
common protocols you now have
access to a new protocol called
"('mongodb://localhost:27017/')" So no matter
which one of these ways you get
connected, the idea should be that
you are connected to the Mongo service
which means that you are now able to
connect to a database. So we're going to
connect to a database and we're going to
be ending the video there and then we'll
continue in the next video. So to get
connected to a database, i'm not sure if
we actually need one set up first or if
it will create on the fly here, so let's
go ahead and try. We're going to set "db =
client." whatever database we want. So,
let's say it's going to be called
".pytests" and that's how to create a
collection, nothing
the collection doesn't exist yet because
we haven't or the database doesn't exsist
yet because we haven't put anything into
it, and so that's what we're going to be
going over the next video. We're going to
be going over the collection or what a
table is in Mongo, and how to set one up.