Alright guys, welcome back. So, in the
previous video we learned about what
PyMongo is and what mongodb is and how to get a basic setup on your machine going.
So, what we're going to do here we're
going to set up another script and we're
actually going to connect to a database
and we're going to be inserting a
document into a collection. So let's go
ahead and start a Python shell here.
We're going to "import pymongo" and "from pymongo import MongoClient" So we've
imported everything that we need to
right now, let's go ahead and set up a
client. So again this is going to
establish a connection to the mongodb
instance which is system-wide, it's the
mongodb service that's running on your
machine.
So let's go ahead and create a variable
called "myClients =
MongoClient( )" and we're going to let it
connect on the default hosting port,
but if you didn't want to you'd connect
essentially like this, host and port. The
host you would have to wrap in
quotations because it's going to be a
string, chances are. So now that we've got
a client instantiated we're going to be
creating a database, so how we do that is
we can access the database as an object.
So the client is an object let's go
ahead and write "db" this is going to be
our database "=myClient."
because we're accessing a method in this
class, and the method is just going to be
the name of our database. Now you can do
it in two different ways. You can either
access it like this with the "." and so
you're going to type "mydatabase" or
if you don't want to access it like that
for instance if you have dashes in it
you're going to access it like this so
"["my-database"]"
Let's go ahead i'm going to use a
standard approach here and i'm going to
write "mydb" Now that we've got the
database happening we can get a
collection. So if you've done any mySQL at all, or any database stuff, you
know that in the database
there's another level down called tables,
and the tables you can have a
user's table, a posts table, settings table,
and each table would have a different
number of columns. So, in the user's table
you might have username, email address,
and password so there would be three columns for each entry into that table, and each
entry would be essentially in Mongo what
we call a document. So in Mongo the table
is called a collection, so let's go ahead
and create a collection called users. So
in order to instantiate a collection you
just create a variable and you access DB
and then your collection, so in this instance it's going to be users "users = db.users" So we've
got our collection created and just as
in defining the database if you have
dashes in here, you can access it in the
way that a dictionary is accessed so
using square brackets and quotations.
So now that we've gotta a collection
created this is what we need to do
really to be able to insert documents. So,
in order to insert documents let's just
go ahead ahead and create a user
object. So, this is going to be equal to
"user1" we're going to store in that
variable and it's going to be a
dictionary, so let's go ahead open up the
dictionary with ""
let's add "username": "nick", "password": "myverysecurepassword",
"favorite_number": 445"
Alright and let's also add a list inside of inside of this document.
So as you can store lists in dictionaries in Python, you can also
store lists as a value, for a key, in a
dictionary, in a Mongo collection. So, you'll
see what I mean if you don't, I think I've
explained it pretty straightforward. So,
"hobbies":
let's go ahead and I have more than one hobby, so instead of opening this with quotes we
actually need to use square brackets
here and create a list. So, i'm going to
write ["python", "games", "pizza"]}" so these are my hobbies. Now I'm going to hit enter
and this is going to create the user1
variable which we can now use to import
well to insert a document into our
database. So, our collection here is
called users so what we need to do, what we're going to do, is
we're going to insert it, but also the
inserted object that has just been
inserted into the database is going to
be, is going to return the posts ID. So
let's go ahead and insert one document
here. So, in order to do this let's create
a variable called"user_id =" because again
what's going to be returned from this
insert function is the ID of the user
as it's put in. So, "user_id = users.
insert_one( )" and it's a method of the
collection. So we just pass in the
document here that we just created or
the dictionary. So we're going to pass in "user1"
And now we can, well this is the part
that returns the the ID of the inserted
documents, so I'm just going to type
".inserted_id" here. Now if I access
"user_id" you'll see that it's object,
etc. So i'm going to go ahead and open
RoboMongo which is a program that
allows you to browse the data which is
in your database. So I'm going to connect
here, and as you can see my database has been created. So let's go into
collections and you'll see users here,
let's go in here, and we have an item
right here, and this is all the data that
we just put into the
collection. Now you can also add that
multiple times, so if i wanted to add
another user i'm going to come up here,
i'm just going to change the name for
now just because i'm very lazy and I
don't want to retype the whole thing,
although waiting for this cursor to get
back to the right point is a little annoying
as well.
This user name is going to be "another_user" very creative, and then i'm going to
insert that one. Did I just insert it,
ok cool. If i refresh and in PyMongo the way that you do that is
command + r and you're going to see the second item right there, and you'll see that this one
is another user, and this one is Nick. That's how to insert one document, in the
next video we're going to be going over
how to find a document.