Alright guys, welcome back. In the last
video we learned about inserting
documents but we actually only learned
about inserting one at a time, so this is
probably going to be a quick video, but
this is how to insert multiple documents
at the same time. Let's go ahead and open this, going to define "users =" and i'm just
going to make the table a
username, not the table the document, a username and the password, but before we
even get started
how do you insert multiple documents into a collection? Again, think
about this is Python, you would use a
list, and inside the list you would
create objects.
So let's go ahead and create an object with "[{"username": "third",
"password": "12345"}" and then the second document that i'm
going to insert going to be here, and you
probably guess you're able to stuff
however many in that you want to at a
time. So this "{"username":
"red", "password": "blue"}]" that's all we need to do. So we've
got users, so now what we can do is let's
go ahead and capture, let's just insert
the posts. So, I "inserted = users.insert" and then
we pass our variable into here "(users)" Alright,
that did not work, insert takes exactly only two arguments, alright. So, what we're going to
do is actually "insert_many" list object has no attribute, users is a collection...
let's...oh.
So as you can see I set the users
variable, which was our collection in
Mongo, I set that to the list here that
we want to insert, so what I'm going to
do now is I'm going to create a
"Users
= db.users" Now what we're
going to do is "inserted = Users.insert_many(users)"
which includes our users, and now you can run "inserted_ids"
oh...
so "inserted.inserted_ids" and the reason it's that is because I
named the variable to actually stuffs
those documents into the collection, I
name that inserted, so we access that
variable.inserted IDs and it's going
to print back the object ids of each
item that was added in here, and
basically if I run command + r here it's
going to reload and I'll see that the
documents that I have in here,
there's two new one. So that's how you
would bulk insert data.