Hi guys, welcome back. So I already did
this video but there was a problem with
mic so I have to do it again, so if you
guys see documents in here that you
don't recall that I created, that's why,
we're going to go ahead and recreate
them. Anyway, so let's jump into it. Now I
realize that in the last video I mean we
learned a basic amount to effectively use
PyMongo in an application but there's
a few more things that I want to talk
about, so this video is going to contain a
few of those, and actually i'll go
through one by one so I'm going to break
this up into a few videos, now. So the
first thing we're going to talk about is
counting documents. So let's go ahead and start a python3 shell, let's "import
pymongo" and "from pymongo import MongoClient" Now let's set up our client "client
= MongoClient( )" and again this is
going to connect on the default host and
port. I've already got mongodb started, if
you don't just go ahead and run "brew
services start mongodb" On Windows it's a little bit different, but you should be
able to find information on how to start
mongodb on Windows. So, once we've got the client created let's go ahead and create
the database variable. So i'm just going
to write "db = client.mydb" and
again this is the name of my database.
Also, if you guys don't have RoboMongo
I don't think I showed you guys where to
get it, I mean maybe you figured it out" so
"robomongo.org" and you just come here
and download it. They've got versions for
every system I believe, you're probably
only going to see versions for your
system here.
Yeah, okay. So they've got Windows, Mac, and Linux, if you guys run react OS or
anything not listed there then you're
not gonna have much luck with that, but
that's besides the point.
So let's go ahead and access our
collection here, so i'm going to create a
variable called "Users = to db.users"
my icloud approval. So, let's go
ahead and talk about counting documents.
I'm just going to do something really
simple here and just count all the
documents in here. So "Users.find( ).count( )" we
can see that I've got 8 documents.
Now, I have few documents with the
favorite number equal to 445, so if I
type "Users.find().count( )" that number is going to
be different. So you guys can see
probably already the practical
applications of this, let's say you're
trying to sign up accounts with a
Python script,
let's say a user opens it up, it asks what
username they want to use the answer, they enter it,
and here you can do a count of you know
you can search for that username in the
users collection, and if the count is
greater than zero you know that it already
exists and they shouldn't be able to use
that, so then you could route them back.
So that's what counting is and basically
you just find a document,
however you would normally, and then just access this method from that object.