That last video was really quick. So
that's neat, I thought that was going to
do that included in another video, but
it is it's own thing so where I didn't talk about
it I just thought I would. Now in this
video we haven't learned about datetime
I don't think it all in Python yet, so
we're going to break away from PyMongo
for a moment to learn a bit about
datetime, and then we're going to learn
how to use datetime with PyMongo. So
normally when you insert an object into
the database or into Mongo here you
would want to capture the date that it is
entered. Now let's say I'm running a blog
and every time I enter a blog post I
obviously want to have the datetime
of when that post was posted, and then we
can use that to organize and just find
certain dates, so it makes it easier for
the user to navigate it.
You can also use this when using stuff
like PyDjango or Webpy which we're
going to be getting both into those in
the future as well. So let's go ahead and
learn about datetime. What we need to do
is import datetime, so "import datetime" here.
Datetime is a pre-packaged Python package, it ships with it by default so you don't
need to install anything. Now, let's set
the current date here in a variable and
that's not very "peppy" so "current_date
= datetime.datetime.now( )"
If we print out "current_date" it's going
to print the exact date that it is right
now, for example it's (2016, 9, 1, 11, 33, 26) and
not too sure what that one is, but that's
beyond the scope of what we're going to
be using with for. So, that's how to
create a current date and now you can
also pass these arguments into a
date to create a very specific date. So
let's go ahead and create
"old_date = datetime.datetime(
2009, 8, 11)" Then this is going to
build an old date of August 8, 2009. So what we're going to
do is we're going to insert a document
with the current date, and then we're
going to find all documents
newer than this date. So it's going
to find the documents that we've
inserted with currently current date. We're
going to insert this object right here
"uid = Users.insert({
"username": "ffie", "date": current_date})" Let's go ahead and
insert that. Just make sure that it got
inserted and it did, and we see that the
date has been set to today.
Now this gets translated into a Mongo
Date Stamp, and that's you can see that
here the type is a date stamp, so that's neat. Now we're going to go ahead and
talk about different operators, less than
and greater than basically. Let's go ahead
and try and find users here, we're just
going to count the objects that we get
back. So "Users.find( )" and all we're going
to be looking for in here is
"date": and then you put
another dictionary object here as the
value for the date "{"$gt": and if you type "gt" that means
greater than, and write "old_date}})"
that's our object. So gt means greater
than so any date any object or document
that has a date greater than this is
going to be returned.
You can use "gte" which means greater than or equal to, you can use "lt" for less
than, or "lte" for less than or equal to. So for right now we're going to find all
documents that are newer than
old date and we're gonna ".count" them
for now, and you can see we have two and
that's this one right here, and I believe
that one right there as well, this one
was inserted in the last video. So that's
how you can use dates to find a document.
Now, let's say we want to find all
documents with a date less than that.
It's going to return 0 and so in these
documents up here we don't have a date
at all, so the non-existence of a date
does not correlate to a less than date,
it just means there's no date. So, what
happens when we want to find documents
based on if a field exists or not? And so
that's basically what we're going to do
next.
So let's go ahead and type "Users.find({"date":" and then we're going to go ahead
and also add another dictionary object
here "}).count( )" we're going to count these as well,
and what we're going to do is use the keyword which starts with a "$exists":
and then type "True" this needs to be the
boolean operator of Python, and you'll
see that we have 2 documents. Now,
another thing that I want to talk about
is if something is not equal to
something. So we have I believe two
objects with the username of yet
another, let's go ahead and find a
document or any documents that have a
username that doesn't equal yet another.
So, let's go ahead and type "username" and then open up another dictionary object
here, "" and then
the term that you want to find that it is
not equal to. So, again this basically
means we're going to be looking for the
field username, so that's all this is
concerned with, and we need to find
documents where the user name is not
equal to yet another. Let's go ahead and
to return that. So, that's a few more
things that are going to make us a lot
stronger with PyMongo going forward,
and in the next video we're going to be
learning about indexes.