Alright guys, welcome back. So to continue along with PyMongo there's one very
important thing that we need to talk
about and that's scalability. Now if you don't
know what scalability is it's basically
like when you start an app. When you first
release an app you might have like 10 or 20 users, and so your database only contains
the content of those 10 or 20 users, but
as time goes on you know your goal
should be to increase your user base and
so you're going to need to scale up to
accommodate more users. Now, this you need to kind of focus on every part of your
app from the network side of it, to the
programming, and the database
management in order to get a good
scalability factor in your app. Now, we're
not going to be discussing ways to scale
your app you know via network controls
and stuff that you can do in terms of load
balancers and whatnot, but that is
something you should definitely look
into. In terms of PyMongo this indexing
is what makes a big difference. So to
explain this let me bring up RoboMongo
here so as you'll see I have
9 documents and there's at least
three fields in each one and some of them
have more, and so when I run a command
like find and i'm looking for something
specific,
let's say that I always want to be
able to search just by username. So if I
were to find based on user name like
this, and we're not going to see a huge
drastic improvement in the speed of this
because it's still pretty small. So let's
say I'm looking for a "users.find()" What this has to do in order to
find objects as it starts from position
one and then it scans the entire
document that looks for that field and
that value. So it will check this field,
and then this one, then it will drop down
here and check that,
that, and that,  and then, and then that. And then it will move on to the next document. Now as
you can see this isn't really efficient,
and if we knew that our
application searched for users based on
the ID or the username, an ID is an
automatic index in Mongo, so what that
means is you don't need to create
an index. What an index does when you
create them it indexes a certain list of
documents based on certain columns or
fields, so in this instance we would want
to create an index for the field
username, and this would compile a
separate list which would be it would
only contain usernames and then point to the
entire document, and as you can guess
traversing all that data to find a
specific user name is going to make a
lot more sense and it's going to be a
lot faster. An then also, we could flip the
resulting index list alphabetically,
etc. and I mean if you wanted to
store by date created if that's a common
search functionality that you're going
to be using within your app is to search
users based on when they were created
you can index the date and then you know
ascend or descend that. So we're gonna
be creating an index for username here
and again we're not going to see a big
difference in the speed, but you will
when you start getting bigger databases.
So, how to create the index is really
simple.
Let's just go ahead and type "db.users.create_index( )" and now what we need to do
is pass it a list, and then also an
object. So let's do this "[( )]" then
we're going to pass in some parameters.
So in this instance the first thing that
we're going to be doing is we're
targeting the column username, so that's
what you're going to put in here "username" and actually you can see right here in
the background to that it's going
to have more information as well. We're
going to sort ascending
for now, so how you do that is just type
", pymongo.ASCEDNING" then after this you
can, you can do a lot more stuff with
this including making it more unique, so
for the usernames that's going to make
sense because if we try to insert a
document that has a duplicate username
we can just return an error rather than
having to write more logic to count you
know if any user names already exist. So
let's type "unique=True" and I got a error
there and that's because I put that in
the wrong spot, so that goes around there,
the square bracket it just wraps around this right here
which is comma separated list, and we're going to add this after it. So go
ahead and create. So, it already found
duplicate username, so
let's just go ahead and do that without
unique sets true,
there we go. So we've created an index
here and basically what that means is
when we search by username like this, againg we're not going to see a drastic
improvement here but it is going to
actually do it a lot faster. Once you get
a thousand documents in a collection or
more you're going to start to notice
that it might slow down and this is how
to improve the speed based on that. Now,
that's all we're going to touch on for
now. We make you more PyMongo or we may
move right on to Webpy I and how to you
know either build an API or something
maybe.