Alright guys, so first off what we're
going to be doing in this video is
simply learning how to play audio files,
and this is just a very basic part
of what our program is going to be, and
basically the playing of the audio files
it's just going to play a notification
sound when we begin recording, and when
we end the recording, and so that way we
always know if it is listening
we can tell. So, let's go ahead and what we
need to do is jump on over to
notificationsounds.com. I have gone to
notification sounds and then page 7 is
where I want my stuff. I want this one to
play after the audio, and this one played
before we start to record. So, I've
already downloaded those, just click on
the link there for each one and click
download, you're going to be downloading
as mp3. Once you've got those downloaded,
I'm not sure where mine went so let me
jump in here and have a look. So I'm
going to show you guys two ways to do
this because those sounds are neat. This
one and this one. Alright, I'm going
to copy all these over to our, no wait, yes
over to PycharmProjects, and we've
created one called audio I believe,
assist. So I'm going to create a new
folder here called audio, and here I'm
going to paste my items.
So once you've got those pasted in there
we're going to be using two libraries
and that's because one of them is going to
play a WAV file, one of them is going to
play an mp3 file, so we are actually
going to use the WAV files when
we actually play, when we actually build
our system. But, if you guys have mp3
files instead I want to show you guys
how to do this. So go ahead and import,
well we need to install the library
actually. So, pip3 install pyglet.
It's called piglet, pretty sure that's
how it's pronounced. So here we're going
to import pyglet, I'm not
sure if that's how it's pronounced. It says it
doesn't find it but it definitely should,
maybe it needs to refresh or something.
Let's run it and just make sure it's, yeah.
Let me see...which interpreter did I use
for this, because I just installed some
interpreters. It's using Cellar 3.5, and
pretty sure the version I installed was
3.5, yeah
it's 3.5.2. So I did install 3.5.3 but I've
also got 3.6. So, let me just go ahead and
make this easy and project interpreter,
going to choose 3.5, yeah 3.5 right
there. This should be the 3.5.3
that I'm trying to use.
So I need to wait for these two
processes to run, and it's updating the
interpreter it's just looking through
all the stuff we have I guess, so we gotta
wait for that.
My computer here is sounding like
an airplane...it's terrible. So, yeah,
we're going to run this here, and as you
can see now it did find the right one.
Okay, so, what I've done is I did look at
being able to compile our
programs and that is something we're
going to go over as well, so what I've
done was I installed multiple versions
of Python. So now aside from the
3.5.2 that we began with
i also downloaded a mac OS installer for
3.5 which installed 3.5.3,
and I also downloaded the
Installer for 3.6. Now you'll notice that
these are in very different places. So
when you install I believe when we
started we installed through cellar or
homebrew, I think it was homebrew, we
installed Python through, and so it
installed it here. When you download the
actual installers for mac OS from python.org
it installs them to the frameworks
library. So, if you haven't installed a
bunch of different interpreters you will
not have this problem, so it
should import correctly. So what we're
going to do is we're going to get our
file, and we're going to say it is equal
to pyglet.resource.media, and
here we're going to import from audio/
wet.mp3. So,
we've now just obtained the audio and
now we're just going to say file play.
Then down here let's run pyglet.app.run.
Save this, play this again, and we've got
an issue...AVbin is required to decode compressed
media. Alright, so,
okay let's try audio_end.wav...not a WAV file. Audio_end is
definitely a WAV file. Alright, let's
try with pyaudio because I never had a
problem with that before. I guess let's
just use wav files. So, go ahead
and import pyaudio, and import wave,
and now down here what you're going to
do is let's create that method I was
talking about. So, def play_audio,
and we're going to pass in a
file. We're going to set the chunk
size to 1024, that's a neat number. The
actual file which is going to be
abbreviated as wf for WAV file is going to
be equal to wave.open filename, and we're going to
read it and write it, well we're just
going to read it actually as binary, and
then we're going to instantiate pyaudio.
Som pa is going to be equal to pyaudio.
PyAudio, that's the class that
we're instantiating, and then we're
going to create a stream from this file.
So basically what a stream is, is it's
a data stream within the app, so within
memory so we're actually loading the
file into some sort of binary object
that we can then use. So, go ahead and
create a variable here called stream and
it's going to be equal to pa.open,
and here we're opening a file. So we need
to pass in arguments so what we're going
to be doing is we're getting the format
from the width of the file, so from the
files basically, so pa.get_format_
from_width,
and then in here we're going to say
wf.getsampwidth. We're going to get the
number of channels from the file, so
channels equals wf.getnchannels.
The rate, this is going to be the frame
rate which the file moves at, so again
just going to say wf.get framerate,
and then output is going to be true. Now
that we've got our stream we can now
read the frames from it. So we're going
to create a new variable called data
stream, and this is only to be the actual
stream. So wf.readframes and we
need to pass in a chunk number. This
isn't going to do anything just yet, not
only because we didn't call the method,
but also because we didn't actually do
anything with the data stream. So let's
go ahead and type while data_stream. So
while there is more stream to read we're
going to say stream.write, and we're
going to write the data_stream to it, and
then data_stream is going to be
wf.read, readframes in chunk again. So,
basically what this is doing is we're
defining the chunks that we're reading at
at 124, or 1024, we're opening the file as
a binary wave file here, and we're
instantiating the pyaudio class. We're
now creating a stream and this stream is
going to be used
to actually stream the audio,
that's what it means there it's creating
a data stream. So we're
opening the file through pyaudio here,
through our pyaudio class, we're opening
a file and these are the
variables or the arguments we're passing
it. So we're getting the format, we're
getting the number of channels, we're
getting a frame rate, and we're seeing
output equals true. Then we're creating a
data stream variable which is equal to
read frames. This is the initial chunk
which is 1024, so it's 1024 bytes or
kilobytes not sure which, I think bytes
of this file then we're reading it, and
then while there is some left we're also
going to just continue reading it at the
next chunk of frames. So what we need to
do after is we need to close the stream,
and then we need to terminate our
pyaudio, and that's all we need to do there.
So now we can just run this method by
passing an audio file to this method. So
open file, and then I'm going to say
audio/audio_end.wav. Oh, I didn't
call it open file I called it play_audio.
There we go. So now when I run this you
guys didn't hear that I don't think
because it's difficult to be able to
record system sound along with
microphone sound through quicktime, which
is what I'm using to record, but it did
play it. Maybe I'll try and capture that
sound as well. So that is how to play WAV
files within Python, and this is exactly
what we're going to be using when we're
recording, and we're going to be getting
to that in the next video.