Alright guys, what we're going to be
doing in this video is actually
beginning to record from our audio
source, and so if you're going to be
following along you need to have a
microphone set up to your computer. What
I would recommend is just a simple USB
one. If you have a USB headset with a
microphone on it that would be ideal, if
you don't you might have another kind of
mic, hopefully. Even one of the ones that
comes with an iPhone just that little
you know earpods or ipod ear pods,
whatever they call them, just get some of
those. So, what we need to do in order to
actually record audio and have it
recognized is import
speech_recognition as sr, and we're just
going to be calling sr just to make our
commands a bit quicker. Also, what we
need to do is we want to be able to
speak multiple times, and that's
something we'll cover after, actually.
It's just a matter of putting it into a
loop. So let's go ahead and create a
method called initSpeech, and this is
not going to take any parameters.
Actually, before we even get to that what
we need to do is set our speech
recognizer, and so we're going to say r
equals sr.Recognizer. There we go.
And basically what we need to do with
that r is we need to pass it
what we say into the microphone, and then
it's going to listen to it, and then we
can tell it to recognize what we're
saying. So, let's print out just let us
know that it's working listening, and
then here we're actually going to start
our recording. So gonna copy this because
we're going to be using that to tell us
that it's actually initiated so initiate,
and again if you guys watch the last
video you know you need to go ahead and
get some wave files. Even if you get mp3
files there are ways to convert mp3s to
wav, and I'm pretty sure miro audio
converter is a really good one. We could
also actually discuss converting audio
using Python, but that's not something we're
going to do right now. So you guys can
go ahead and download Miro if you need
to, otherwise just follow along. So as
soon as we call this it's going to say
listening and then it's going to play
the audio that tells us it's listening,
and then we're going to say with
sr.Microphone as source, we're going to say
print "Say Something," and then under here
we're just going to capture audio equals
r.listen, and it's going to listen to
the source. So again this is basically
just saying our recognizer is now
listening to whatever we're saying. So
it's coming through the microphone here
and we're calling it source so this
essentially is whatever we're saying, and
then the audio is going to listen to it.
And that's all we need to do to actually
record our audio. So what we're going to
do at this point is we're going to play
audio, and we're going to play the ending
sound. So audio/audio_end.wav and this is
going to tell us that we've finished
speaking, and now we're going to create a
variable called command which is going
to be an empty string right now, and then
we're going to
use a try except method here and this
is going to basically just be a fail
safe for if the recognizer could
not understand what we were saying. Let's
go ahead and try and we're going to set
command equal to r.recognize_google,
and this is going to use google to
determine what we're saying. There
are different things that you could use
here as you just saw. You can use bing,
houndify, ibm, sphinx, etc., and we will
actually get into sphinx as well and maybe
wit, but for right now we're just using
google, and we're going to pass in our
audio. So again the audio is captured
here as to what ever is listened to, and
then we send the audio over to google, it
puts it into this command variable,
and so then at that point we could print
out what we've said. So let's go ahead
and use the except methods here or not
methods but conditions, so print
"Couldn't understand you, bro." And then
under here what we're going to do is
we're going to just say, we're just going
to print back what we've said. So, print
"Your command:" and then command, and that
is it. So, let's go ahead and save this,
and now let's run it, and I'm going to speak
and what we should see is that whatever
I speak gets printed down here.
Right, we didn't call that method,
actually. So, initSpeech. There we go. My
name is Nick,
and it spelled Nik wrong, but it did catch
it. So let's go through something a
little more difficult and you didn't
hear it but it did use the beginning and
ending audio file exactly when it
showed up, so that's pretty neat. You guys
should have the exact same result so you
guys will hear when you're doing it. So
thank you guys for watching this video,
in the next video we're actually going
to be getting into actually
understanding what we're saying and be
able to launch certain actions from
what we're saying.