Hi guys, in this video we're going to
actually make our program talk back to
us and so the way we're going to be
doing that, and I have this audio
recorder up now which is recording
through sound flower which is an add-on
that allows me to actually record my
systems audio, so you guys will hear
audio in this video as well. So, what
we're going to do and there's really no
cross-platform way to do this on
Python 3 just yet, at least no easy way, I
actually run a project called pyttsx,
and it's a project that I've inherited.
Basically, it's installing right here and
it's been doing that for the last 10 or
20 minutes because it's installing from
source, and it's pretty big, and it has a
lot of dependencies. So what we're going
to be doing instead of using this right
now, and maybe we'll come back to this
later and I can provide you know a better
package for it, or actually set it up to
pypi or something like that, what we're
going to be doing is just discussing
some cross-platform methods to make your
terminal speak. So, on Linux you're going
to want to go ahead and install gnustep-
gui-runtime, and this is
instructions for debian based distros
using apt-get. If you don't have a
debian based distro you might want to
check for this program in whatever
package manager you're using, you should
be able to install it, and then you
simply run the command and say and then
whatever you're going to say. On Windows
you're going to download PTTS and you're
going to install that, and then you
should be able to print this command
here and it should speak for
you. And on Mac OS all you need to do, and
it actually installed this, awesome. So
we will come back to that probably in
the next video, but for right now all you
need to do is on a Mac run that
command. So every time you see me using
the say command in our program you're
going to be using this, if you're on
Windows.
So let's go ahead and jump into this and
all we want to do at this point is to
make the program speak back to us, and so
the way we're going to be doing that is
we're going to create a method called
say, and we're going to pass it in the
text of what we want to say, and then
we're going to be using the sub of process
in order to spin that
process on the computer as well. So what
you need to do is import subprocess.
Down here we're creating our third
command or method actually let's do this
up at the top here, and it's going to be
say and we're going to pass it in text,
and when you use subprocess you can actually
call binaries, anything that you can do in
terminal you can do in subprocess, so,
yeah. What we're going to do is we just
call subprocess.call, and then we call
whatever we want you know to do. So, in
this instance I'm going to say space
plus text, and i'm going to set shell to
true. Now, what I can do at this point is
down here when we're done speaking,
rather than printing out a command we're
going to print it, but we're also going
to say it. So I'm just going to call say,
you said, command. So if I save this now and
we're going to run it, I will bring up
Quicktime to make sure I can see the
audio recording, just to make sure it's
working, let's go ahead and run it.
"Mary had a little lamb" and as you guys
can see our program can now talk back to
us. So, we're going to connect it to an
artificial intelligence so we've just
created the input, we've created the
output, and we just need to bridge those
two gaps this point and this is going to
be the biggest part of our program. It's
going to be an artificial, artificial
intelligence. So if we say "hi" we're going
to make our program say, okay, well that
person said "hi" so we should say "hi" back,
and that's what we're going to be doing.