Alright guys, what we're going to be
doing is extending this and creating kind
of an artificial, artificial intelligence,
and we're going to be doing this which
is going to be very limited and
restricted, but we're going to be doing
this without an external python library.
And so basically this is going to be all
just straight-up Python 3 and we're
going to attempt to parse what's
recognized as what we're putting in to
this program. So, let's go ahead and
create a new file here and it's going to
be called commands, and now in here what
I'm going to do is I'm going to include
subprocess, OS, and I guess that's it. So,
import, it's doing this thing again
where I have no cursor, so awesome. I'm
going to close that, close that again,
jump in here and relaunch pycharm. Sorry
about that guys. Sometimes it does that,
I'm really not sure it only has ever
happened to me on Mac OS. Alright, so
let's go ahead and open up assist again,
and we're going to think about commands
that we want to be able to issue to the
program, and we want to kind of make it
like if we wanted to ask what's your
name. That's going to be the first
command we program here, so in commands.py
we're going to import
subprocess and os, and I think that's
fine for now. So what we're going to do
is we're going to create a class here
and the class is just going to be called
commander. So, skip
down a line, there we go, we're going to
define init and in here we're going to
create two lists, and they're going
to contain a few words that would
basically either confirm something, or
cancel something. So, let's go ahead and
create self.confirm
equals a list, and it's going to be "yes,"
"affirmative," "si," "sure," "do it," and these are
all like if our program says are you
sure you want to do this we should be
able to pass in any of it, we should be
able to say any of these things to
basically tell the program that yes, we
do want to do it, and i'll show you how this
is going to work in a moment. And
then self.cancel is going to be similar
say "no," "negative," "negative soldier,"
"don't," "wait," and "cancel." So those are our
two lists and then what we need to do is
let's create a function in here called
discover, and this function is going to
all it's going to do is determine what
we're saying, and what action this
commander object should give. So go ahead
and write def discover and here we're
going to pass in the text of of what we
say. So, if let's say "what" in text,
and "your name" in text. So here we can
kind of glue together different pieces
of the sentence that we're looking for.
In this instance what we're going to be
looking for are the words "what" and "your
name." Now that means I can say what is
your name, or I could say what your name,
or I could say what your name. I could
also say what does your name mean and it
will do this, and so this is why we're
going to be getting to a better parser
later, but for right now to introduce
you to the basic concepts of what's
happening at a base level we're just
going to do this, and there are libraries
out there that we're going to be using
that will basically be able to identify
if it's a verb, if it's a subject, and
we'll be able to get the subject of the
sentence so that would either be your,
my, he, something like that, right, and we'd
be able to better identify what you're
speaking about and then be able to react
to that. So, for right now we're just
going to say respond, I'm going to say
self.respond, and "My name is PYCOMMANDER"
and it's not actually going to say this,
so I want to make sure it's going to say
it so I'm going to spell out pie...let's
just say python commander. "How are you?" So,
what we need to do is now define the
self.respond method, and basically
what this is going to do is it's just
going to call that say command, or if
you're on Windows it's going to call
that PTTS, it's the library
that you can use to make your computer
speak, basically it connects to the text
to speech. At this point what we're doing
is we are, so the first step in this
program is turning speech to text, then
we can parse it,
and then we put in the text that we want
to respond with, and then we turn that to
speech. So it's kind of coming full
circle at that point. So let's drop down
here and define respond, and we're
going to pass in response there, and
we're just basically going to call
subprocess.call. I am on Mac so I'm going
to be using the say command, and then
response, and I'm going to set shell equal to
true. What we're going to do we're
actually going to create one more
variable in here. If "my" in text: we're
going to say self.respond "You haven't
told me your name yet" else: so we're
going to assume you're either asking
what your name is or what the computer's
name is, and so in that case that's
what's going to happen here. So what we
need to do now is go ahead we need to
import commands, we need to instantiate
commander, and then pass our text into
this, and so in our audio file here let's
import, rather from .commands import
Commander. Then init speech right here
this is where, let's turn this into
a while loop, actually. So, if while
running equals True: So up
here we're going to set running equal to
true, and then if
you say "quit" it will set
running to false so that we can quit out of
it. So if command equals "quit" running
equals false. There we go. So, what we need
to do is we need to either pass that in,
or we could basically tell it that it's global as well, and...yes, that's fine.
We're not we're not even going to worry
about that right now. So, while running
equals true just do this. So in here what
we need to do is when it has determined
what we've said we need to first
instantiate commander, so cmd equals
commander, and then down here we're going
to say cmd.discover and we're going
to pass in the command, and we're going
to comment that out. This should now
respond to us, so I'm going to go ahead
and I'm also going to in the respond
process here I'm also going to print out
the response. Let's save this and I'm
going to open up a new audio recording
because I didn't think about this before,
sound flower two channels, let me just
make sure this is on the correct output.
There we go, alright. Alright, so, let's get
recording so that you guys can actually hear
this now. So, back over here to audio and
run the program...parent module not loaded,
alright. Let's go ahead and add that
blank
init file here, there we go. Cannot perform relative
input, or import...okay. "What
is your name?" My name is Python commander,
how are you?" "I'm good." What is your name?"
"My name is Python commander, how are you?"
"What is my name?" "What is my name?"
Something's broken there. We will figure
that out. Alright, so I'm going to stop
this, alright that's fun. We're going
to be fixing that, I think there's
something wrong when if my in text...
yeah.
we're gonna have to fix that, but
basically that works as far as what we
wanted it to do so far. So, yeah, in the
next video we're going to be extending
this and I'm going to be showing you
guys the confirm and quit options.