Alright guys, so what we are going to do
in this video is I'm going to make this
little quick command work, and now I'm
going to do that is I'm going to
basically say if command in a list, and
here I'm going to put all terms that we
want to be able to to quit the app from.
Alright, so, what we need to do is as you
can see when I hover over this it says
shadows name running from outer scope,
and it says local variable local
variable is not used, and so you can tell
that what this is trying to do is create
a new variable within this method, but
what we want to do is actually capture
the global running variable. So in order
to access a global variable within a
function you just type global and then
the name of the variable, and then that
turns that variable here into the global
one and we're going to set it to false. So if
I save this and run it, "exit," "goodbye,"
"quit," there we go. So as you can see it
took a few times, for some reason it thought I said
said exact, and maybe that's my Canadian
accent, not too sure,. I'm not too sure how
Google works with accents actually
that's going to be very interesting if
it doesn't, but it's Google so I would
think it would. So in this video we're
basically just going to add some
functionality to the commands right here,
and basically we want it to be able to
launch an application. So if "open" in text
we want to be able to open up a
program, basically. We also want
to be able to launch a program, so if
launch or open in text, what we're going
to do is we're going to need to get the
apps name, and so we're going to split
text at the space, we're going to get one
response from it. And so the first word
it's going to strip off because now we're
going to target the last item. So, if I
say launch Mozilla Firefox what this is
going to do right here is it's going to say,
okay, let's take off the first word, or
let's split it at the first space, which
is right after the word launch, and then
you know it puts it into two parts. So
this list would have two list items and
the first one would be launch, and the
second one would be anything that I said
after that. So this becomes Mozilla
Firefox, two words. So what we can do with
Mac OS, and actually with Linux
there should be a way to do this as well,
with Windows I'm not sure if they have
a way from the command line to launch
programs, but with Mac OS you just issue
the command open. And so what I'm going
to do is type os.system and this
allows us to make system calls to the
operating system, and then we just pass
in the command. So I'm going to say open
-a for application, and then I'm
going to add whatever app I'm trying to
open, plus .app. So, with this I should
be able to launch Safari. So let me quit
out of it, there we go. Let's go ahead and
save and rerun the application, and
let's go ahead and make it respond first.
So, self.respond "Opening" app. So let's go
ahead and open Safari. "Open Safari"
"opening Safari" and as you can see this
opened safari for me. So let's try again,
"opening." "Open Chrome." "Opening Chrome." "Open
Google Chrome." "Opening Google Chrome." "Open
finder." "Opening finder." "Open itunes."
"Opening itune." "Open goofy." "Opening
Cuckoo." I'm not really sure what it's
trying to find there, but as you can see
it partially works. Maybe it's my mic, I'm
not really sure. I don't know maybe it's
where I'm recording multiple audio
sources at at once, but, yeah, basically
you can see that what we do is we're
able to issue commands and kind of parse
them out and with this we're going to be,
probably in the next video or soon after,
we're going to start using an actual
speech parser and these are the same
kind of speech parsers that are used by
big-name corporations and organizations
that have machine learning as a
priority. So, thank you guys for watching
this video. I hope you found this one fun
and informative, and I hope you'll join
me for the next one where we get way
more advanced with this.