Alright guys, what we are going to be
doing at this point is adding a little
bit of artificial intelligence here. It's
artificial in the truest sense of that
word. We're not actually going to create
a brain, and we're not going to give our
machine the capability of storing
memories, and then when new data is put
in like audio or you know if we were
really smart people we'd be creating an
AI that can see, but we're not going to
be doing that, that would be a real
challenge. Anyway, what we're going to be
doing we're not going to be creating
life, or consciousness, or awareness, we're
just going to give the illusion of
consciousness or awareness by when we
ask the program something it is going to
parse the internet, very specifically by
the way, I'm programming this very simply.
You could extend this so much further
and I'm going to provide a few examples
of how you would when we're done. What
I'm going to do is we're going to be
scraping the web to find our answer, so
we need to be able to ask a question, be
able to parse it correctly, and be able
to get the response or the correct
answer, and then we you know make our
computer or our program here speak back
to us and tell us the answer, so it will
be sort of like a dialogue. So we've
already got the audio sorted out here,
and I'm actually going to go ahead and
create a new audio recording so that you
can hear, alright. I have to actually
change my sound settings in here as well
to make the output device the
two-channel sound loud as well so that
it can actually record into here. So let's
go ahead and record, and I'll just
compile you know the audio track and
then this screen recording in the video
editor, and then you guys will see the
end result. So it's kind of irrelevant,
don't worry about what I was doing there.
So what we're going to do now though is
we're going to create a separate little
project and then we're going to connect
the two. So what this project is going to do
is it's going to be a class that we can
access in order to
basically scrape a certain question, so
let's go ahead and get started. I'm going
to create a new Python file here
called get_answer.py and then we're
going to need to make a lot of imports,
and this is stuff that we actually
covered back in I think section three.
It was a while ago where we did some web
scraping and we scraped Bing, I think,
for pictures. We set up a an interactive
picture getter. So we're going to be
using selenium and bs4, as well as
urllib parse. So let's go ahead and just
start our imports. This is a lot so I'm
going to go over each one. So first we're
going to import time. Now we're going to
start our selenium imports, so the most
important one, they're all important but the
most important one, from selenium import
webdriver. Then we need to import a
class called by and that allows us to
figure out if, well it allows us to
target elements to try and figure out if
an element is present. The next three are
related to detecting elements. So, from
selenium.webdriver.common.by
import By, and the actual thing I'm
importing has a capital letter. Classes
typically have capital letters. We're
going to import a class that allows us
to wait for certain things, so from
selenium.web driver.support.ui
import WebDriverWait, this is
camel case, again. And then we need to
import a class that will allow us
to determine expected conditions. So this
as well as going to help us wait for
certain elements to appear, and with
Google being a dynamic system that runs
a lot on JavaScript this is essential. So,
from selenium.webdriver.support
import expected_conditions as EC
capital letters. And then we need one
more from selenium and this is going to
tell us if something times out, so from
selenium.common.exceptions
import TimeoutException.
Again, in camelcase. Now we're going to
import beautiful soup 4, so from bs4
import BeautifulSoup. This is going to
allow us to parse the returned HTML data.
We need URL parse as well, we might not use
it, we might, from urllib import urlparse.
Sorry, from urllib.parse import
urlparse, and then the final one is going to
be sys. Alright, so, that took a while
to import all those. What we're going to
do now I'm going to be going over
basically what we were doing in the last
videos as well, and so I mean not the
last videos but the ones where we were
actually scraping the web. So, if you guys
didn't do that don't worry about it
we're going to be scraping the web now,
so you guys will have no problem with that. So, what
we need to do is we need to create a
class
called Fetcher and then define the init
function, and we're going to take in,
right off the bat, we're going to take in
url. So as soon as this initializes we're
going to initialize the driver, and then
we're going to call a method within this
class that will actually look up the
data for us and return it. So we're going
to say driver equals webdriver.
PhantomJS. So, a little note about
Phantom.js it's a JavaScript browser
that runs not in a graphical user
interface. So if you are on Mac you just
need to run brew install phantomjs.
Linux should be similar and I do know
that we have some of the students
here using Windows, if you have any
trouble with Windows it should be as
simple, and I say should be but Windows
can be really overly complicated
sometimes, it should be as simple as
downloading the Phantom.js binary file
that you can actually execute, putting it
somewhere, and then making sure that file
path is in your path environment
variable. If you need any help doing that
let me know. Also, I will see if I can find
links to download Phantom.js as well.
So right off the bat we're going to wait,
and we're going to make the driver wait
for 5 seconds. Then what we're
going to do is call a method that we
haven't yet defined called lookup, so just
write def lookup and we're going to
take in both the driver, actually we
don't need to because we're going to set
self, there we go, that's smart, self.
driver. So now that's an instance
variable and we don't have to pass it
into anything, and self.url. So, in look up
what we're going to be doing is we are
going to be getting the URL, so we're
going to say self.driver.get, and
we're going to pass in self.url. Now
what we need to do, and I will show you
guys why, basically,
when you open
up google.com and you do a search this
is the URL we're going to be using. So, if
you know anything about get variables
you know that here q is set to whatever
we type in. So we can remove this, right,
and it doesn't go anywhere, but if we add
it back and make equal to how to make
pie, we see that what we have here is
exactly what we're looking for. So this
should be the answer. If we ask
our program how can I make pie, our
program should say this, this, this, and then
maybe print out the link to where it found
it so we can look there. So that's what,
and I mean you could extend this by
actually following, this adding some
logic, and you know trying to find the
exact directions and your program could
return that, that would be ideal.
Now this div I have already taken the
effort on another machine to have
Phantom.js look at it and print out the
results, and the result is basically that
what we want to target here, this box
that has the instructions in it, has a
class of GSFI. So that's what we're
looking for. Sorry, actually, this
has a class of GSFI. So we're just going to
wait for this to appear I believe, and
then this right here, the actual content
that we have, has a class of underscore
SPG, and i will show you guys exactly
what all this means in just a moment. So what
we're going to do is we're going to try,
we're going to say ip equals, and this is
a variable we're never going to use, going to say
driver.wait.until, self.driver actually
sorry about that, this is an instance
variable. Self.driver.wait.until
expected conditions which we've said is
EC, presence_of_element_located then we
open up brackets here, and then we put in
brackets here it's tuple, By, this is the
other thing that we imported up there,
CLASS_NAME, and this is in all caps. And
where this is a tuple you need to add a
comma and then the class name of
whatever element we're looking for which
is gsfi. There we go.
except: print("Failed bro"), there we go. So
what we're going to do at this point if
we have the page and it
didn't fail right there, basically
we can just get, we can create our
beautiful soup from this, and then you
know continue, I guess. Alright, so, what
we got to do is actually I forgot to do
something...no, I did it. Alright, we need to get the
response here which is self.driver.get.
We should be able to access self.
driver.page_source, and now this is
going to be the web page that is
returned to us. So what I want to do is I
want to create my beautiful soup from
that, so I'm going to say soup equals Beautiful
Soup, the first parameter is self.driver.
page_source, and then the second one is
html.parser and this is a string. There
we go, we've created our soup. Now what
we're going to do is just print out our
soup. So I'm going to save this and then
what we have to do is call lookup here,
so lookup, sorry self.lookup,
there we go. So, what I'm going to do is
in my commands here, one sec...is it?
Yes, okay, in my commands script what I'm
going to do is I'm going to say from
get_answer import Fetcher. Now,
we're going to continue this in the next
video because I think this video is
already pretty long, but basically what
we've done is we've written a scraper
that just prints out the entire source,
and basically what's going to happen
right now is nothing if we were to run
it and that's because we haven't
connected it to our commander.