Alright, so, what we're going to be doing
here is connecting our answer class, the
fetcher here, it's going to fetch the web
page that we specify, we're going to
connect that to commands. So right now
what happens, and let's trace this back,
as soon as we start speaking it's going
to play a ding sound, and then we say
something, and then it plays the audio
end sound. Then it uses Google to recognize
what we're saying, and if it can it
instantiates the discoverer that we
created right up, where did we do that? Is it in
here? That's commander...cmd that's what we
called it. Here's where we
instantiated it, there we go. So we've
created our commander instance and then
down here we run the discover command,
then we pass through our text whatever
that might be. So now if our text has
what in your name we just tell it you
know what to say. Otherwise, we're going to
create our fetcher here. So we're going
to say f equals fetcher, and we're going
to pass in a URL. The URL is going to be,
let's collect this right
here, I'm going to paste this in there,
and then we're going to say plus text. So,
it's going to instantiate, this should all
work correctly, so I'm going to ask this
question now and let's see what happens.
"How can I make pie?"
...
Alright, so, it found how to make a pie
and that's because when you misspell
something on Google, let's say, that's
pretty neat, actually. Let's say I search
for how can I make my...that's odd that it
actually gave me a different set of
results, cool though. How can I make my...
and it "failed bro," and so it prints out.
Where did it fail? Let me see...
Alright, so it couldn't find that, but it did
generate our page correctly because it
waited. I wonder if that changed. I could
print out the, yeah, anyway, we're gonna
skip that. What we're looking for is that
block that actually tells us how to make
the pie and if you recall that block is
right here on this dynamic page which is
built for newer browsers, which is what
we see if we use Chrome and Safari, it's
going to have a different class, but if
we were to use a really, really old
browser, or it's just the type of browser
that Phantom.js uses, it's going to give us
a different set of results. Now I've
already parsed through it and I found
the class, that is this, and it is
_spg. So what we're going to do
is in here we're going to say answer
equals soup.find and we're going to
find_all actually, and we're going to
find everything with the class name
equal to _sPg, and the P there
is capital. Where this is a list, let's
set this to 0, and now this is our answer.
So let's print out answer.text, sorry
get_text, and then let's say self.driver.
quit. Let's rerun this and see what
happens. "How far is Pluto from Earth?"
Alright, interestingly, I think we forgot
to save something. Interestingly, this is
looking up for pie every single time. So,
we got to troubleshoot this a bit, so let
me go ahead and print out self.url and
let's see what we're looking for here,
and I think we made the problem in
commander. No, audio. Well, let's have a
look. "How far is Pluto from Earth?"
There's the problem, alright. The
problem is that the URL we passed in
right here is actually wrong. I'm not
sure why it would use two Q variables, or
if we did that. So, cancel this, there we go.
Save it and run it again, this should
work, I hope. "How far is Pluto from Earth?"
Alright, that is cool, we are done here,
let me cancel out of there. We got the
answer we want. As one final thing, we
want this to to tell us you know what it
is. So what we're going to do is, I think what
we can do is, this right here, let's
return answer.get_text, and then
let's change this from this looking it
up, we're going to change it to, remove
that print statement it's getting a bit
full there, going to jump over here and
here I'm going to say lookup. So we're
going to say answer equals f.lookup,
and then we're going to say respond with
answer, self.respond, actually. So this
should now tell us what basically
whatever we want to know. So let me just
take one final look through here, that
will never be reached, so up there, there
we go. Let's run this and see what
happens. "How far is the Sun from the moon?"
Alright,
so at this point we have a problem with
this string being printed out. Now let me
see why would that do that? It said it
couldn't, unexpected EOF while looking
for matching quote.
Let me jump back over
here and let's try to say that. You know
what I can actually just put that there, let's
try and wrap it manually in quotes maybe,
try it again. "How far is Earth from the Sun?"
Hmm...odd. Let me try that again. "How far is
the moon from Earth?"
I think something's happening with my
internet connection, actually. I might
have to do a bit of troubleshooting
around that and then update you guys
with the next video, and make any other
adjustments we need to make. So, this
should be working, I think it's something
outside of our code itself, hopefully it
works for you guys. I will be back. Join
me in the next video where we will wrap
this up.