Alright guys, so it wasn't actually a
problem with my internet connection or
anything, it's a problem with our program
and it's not really a problem so much as
ways that we can improve it. There are
certain websites that, or there are
certain Google searches that will return
the exact element we're looking for,
however this kind of thing this uses the
class underscore XWk. So what we can do
is we can copy this and add a
conditional in there, the get_answer. What
we're going to do...
Alright, we need to change that because
we're first going to look for this. If
not answer we're going to then look for
this, answer equals soup.find_all class
equals that one. So let's go ahead and
save, and let's ask who plays Kelso.
"How to make applesauce?"
"To make basic applesauce, peel, core
and coarsely chop 2 pounds..." Okay, it's working
so far. "Who plays Kelso?"
That one failed. We will have to look at
that more. And how to determine actually
what class that is I'm actually just
going to dump the entire file here, so
with open test, sorry gotta put that in a
string, "test.html", "w+" as f:, we're going to
say f.write, and we're going to write our
soup, and then f.close, so that we can see,
actually. Let's run that same question
again, then look at the page that we get
back, and determine what class we should
be using. "Who played Kelso?"
That looks tremendously wrong but we got
our file here, and it didn't write
anything. Alright, so, let's actually
look at why it didn't write anything, and
let's find out how we can make it right
stuff. So, let's convert this to a string,
sorry about that. Alright, let's try again and
this time let's say, "who won the Super
Bowl?" We're looking for that. "Who won the
Super Bowl?" And now we wait.
Alright, so we have a page here and this
is what we want at the beginning of line
three, so what we're going to do is at end of
line teo we're going to go right to the
end, and we're going to look at...
this line...sorry about
that. I will edit that out, actually.
Alright, so, this line wrap is what's
causing a problem at this point. What we
need to do is find where the top of the
page starts and actually has content...
we need to find the
beginning of the results here, and then
is that it? No, past 24 hours.
So, what I'm going to do is I'm going to
search this right here, that should be
able to find the string that we're
looking for, there we go. So this is m3b,
that's the class we need to look up. So
let's copy it, and this should be a lot
easier actually. So, let's drop in here
and put that there. Now let's run it and
ask the question again, and Google's only
going to give like four or five
different types of responses so that's
when this is going to be useful. We can
determine what kind of questions are
most commonly asked and then code it to
find whichever one. And, again, this isn't
true artificial intelligence, this is
just kind of a connection of
artificial intelligence. We're using a
source of data that we, you know I mean
we could actually create a database and
we could tell it to go learn about
certain things. So we could create an
empty database and then you know when we
input the command go learn about
football, we could we could send our
program to the most relevant Wikipedia
page and have it index all of that data,
and make sense of it by compiling facts,
and then we would be able to ask it
questions about it, and what it would do
we would have to create some sort of search
interface just like creating a search
page on the internet like Google is done,
and we would be able to search our own
database, but again that is a big, big job.
So we're not doing the memorization of
facts we're just doing how to retrieve
them, I guess. So, let's go ahead and ask
it this question. "Who won the Super Bowl?"
And we wait...New England Patriots. "Who is
Kurt Russell?"
Kurt Vogel Russell born March 17,
1951, and there we go. Let me
just stop this. So as
you can see we can ask our program very
simple questions, very direct questions,
and we'll be able to get a response if
Google has this. Otherwise, if at this
point it doesn't have an answer we're
going to set the answer to "I don't know."
There we go. So, we are good to go, I
just want to search right quick to see
another few examples. So, let's say when
was pizza invented? And as you can see
we've got a nice little blurb about that.
We could ask that question to our
program. We could say, who invented Python?
And we would get this guy's name right
here Guido van Rossum, and this is just
an example of what you can do you know
with Python and connecting
different dots. This again is not true
artificial intelligence but for the sake
of this series this can be enhanced, and
superseded, and can be expanded so far
that it can be artificial intelligence,
and you guys are prepared right now to
do that if you would want to. It's just a
very, very big task.