Hi guys, welcome back. I need to jump into PyCharm here for this video.
What we're doing in this subsection is
Webpy. We're going to learn how to use
web.py and use it effectively, and what
it is, and basically what it does. It's a
framework in Python which can serve up
web content using the HTTP protocols and
it runs its own server. You write code in
Python to define routes based on urls
and then you run the application, and you
can you know you do all your logic in
Python, it's really, really awesome. So, what we're going to do is jump into it and
install it, before we do that check out
this Adam Atlas quote, i'm not going to
read it to you it's longer than I care
to read, but check it out.
You're probably gonna come to webpy.org
any way and that quote is so
true.
Now to install you're going to have some
problems most likely. If you run
"pip3 install web.py" I've already got
it installed but it wasn't that easy to
install.
So, what you guys are going to have to do
you're going to get an error and this is
going to be something that happens once
in awhile in Python, so i'm going to show
you how to circumvent that. What you're
going to do is go to github com/webpy/webpy.git
and you're going to see that this
basically includes a setup.py file, and
this will allow you to install it.
One of the recent commits here was they
removed Python 2 and then added Python 3,
or something.
So basically what we're going to want to
do is go to python3.
Ok, this is the one that I installed. So
you can copy the URL to clone it, ok.
So, let's grab this, copy, you're going
to change directory into "cd Projects"
and then run "git clone" and
then that. Now it's going to create a
folder which is going to be equal to the
project's name, so webpy, now of course
I've already got that done because this
is how i installed it too. Once it's
cloned, if you don't have get installed
install it, go to github.com and you
should be able to find an installer
there. Now once it's created the
directory if you're go into and list it here
you're going to see exactly what you see
here and there is a setup.py file. So
what you need to do is you need to run
"python3 ./setup.py" Manually installing Python
packages is literally that simple.
Now I've already got it installed, it's
going to install it anyway though, and it
looks like it finished installing it
correctly and we've got it there.
Actually, it says it's already the active
version. So we've got that installed and
ready to go. Now we're going to set up a
project here for it, we're going to
basically write out this code right here.
So we're going to create a new project,
Python, and we're going to go out there
there we are going to call it
"webproject"
Ok, I do click that.
Alright, so if you're wondering how to
tell if you've got Webpy installed
correctly, let's
go ahead and create a Python file and call
it "main" "import web" going to save this,
this should not return an error. So if we
run main it didn't return an error,
this is good. Now, what we need to do is
set up a certain set of routes so what
we're going to do is we're going to
create a variable called "urls = ( )" and you
can really named this whatever you want
to. It's going to be a list that contains
two items per row, and it's going to be
the route, and then the name of the class
which that route needs to connect to. You
can use regex here, so if you want to
have like item, or let's say '/post/' if
you're making a blog, and then you can
just put in, you know, regular old
regex. Mine is gonna be forward
slash, it's going to be the root of the app,
I'm going to have it connect to an 'index'
class, and that's all you need to do. So what we're going to do is define that class
now.
So, "class index:" it's literally this
simple. All you do is define a class
called "def GET(self, ):" going to pass itself automatically, and then you can also pass
in other parameters with it if you want.
Now this URL isn't built for
accepting any other parameters so what
we're going to do is we're going to make
that happen. So, basically just following
the example
on the right hand side here, we're
going to add some regex to basically
recognize anything in there and it's
going to pass it in here as "name" Now,
what we're going to do is we're just
going to make it print out something, so
"print("Hello", name, '. How are you today')" and that's all our class actually needs
to have. So let's go ahead and "if__name__ == "__main__":
"if__name__ == "__main__":
and we're going to run the app so "app.run( )" but we haven't defined app. So, as you see
over here in the example this is where we
actually instantiate the web application
simply by running "app=web.application(urls, globals( ))" and
this is going to be the routes that we
define here, so again you can name this
anything you want to, you got to pass it into there though.
Let's go ahead and save and run this, and
it's running right now so what we're
going to do is go ahead and open
"localhost:8080" it says none.
So let's access "/nick" and I got confused
here for a second because I wasn't
expecting it to pop up here but we
didn't get to that yet, we're just
printing something, we're not returning. So that's why it did
that. So, Hello nick? How are you today?
Now, if you want to return something it's
really simple, just type return, and then
whatever you want to return. So let's run
this again,
and refresh again, and you see it returned
an object. Now more specifically what we
can do if we want to which we probably
do is just turn this into a string for
now. So remove the commas and
concatenated it all as a string, save it, run
it, refresh, and you'll see that we've got
text. So what you can do here is you can
actually add HTML in here, and that's
basically where that comes from, this is
where it all ties together right here,
the fact that you returned HTML. And we're going to be learning about at templates
as well, and that's where the majority of
the reusable code comes into play as
well, and basically this is going to be
all your logic, we're going to be storing
templates in a separate directory, and
loading them in and putting the
content into those templates.