Hey guys, welcome back. In the last video
we actually built a login script but it
didn't actually do anything, it kind of
just it kind of just tested you know if
the password's correct but we didn't
actually do anything with the password,
we didn't do anything account-based, so
what we're going to get into in this
video is what's known in computer
science as a session. So what a session
is it's a way of keeping persistent data
synced up between a client, or an
individual user, and the server. So, for
instance when you go to Facebook and you
login with your email address and
password, what happens is facebook checks
that the information is correct and if
it is correct and you've logged in,
what it does is it sends information to
your internet browser telling the
browser who you're logged in as, and
then your browser sends that information
with each request that the server can
check if there's a session, what's
the session username, and do stuff based
on that and generate pages. So, basically when
you're on Facebook and on the top
bar there you click profile, or your name,
not sure which it is now, it used to be just
the word profile, what happens is it
takes you to a template page that
contains all your data, and it generates
that based on session data. So what we're going to do is we're going to rig up
our login form to a session management
bit of code. So let's go ahead and open PyCharm
here, let's open up the controller,
and we're going to create the session.
Now in order to do that what we first
need to do is disable the debug mode in
Webpy because the debug mode interferes with the ability to run sessions, and I'm going
to get that out of the way right now, and
so what we need to do is basically
disable the debug mode. So in the error
messages that I've got before it provided
a lot of information about the error
themselves and where the error was
beginning and happening in the code, and
so that's debug mode, so we're going to
turn that off. So, in the top your script
run "web.config.debug = False"
and that's all we need to do
there. Now what we're going to have to do
is actually change the order of render
and app. The reason why we need to
do that is because we're going to do
some code between app and render, and we need app to do that code, and then in
the render method we need whatever we
write here, so we just need to change the
order of that. So what we need to do here
is, and actually before we get into that
we're going to create a way to logout.
And so the reason we're doing that is
because when we start logging in we
might have problems, we want to log out
and log back in, we need a way to do
that. So let's go ahead down here create
a "class Logout:" let's "def "GET(self):"
and
we're just going to run "session.kill( )"
and kill is a method so add those
parentheses there, and then we're just
going to return "success" So
basically what's going to happen is when
we go to /logout it's going to
kill the session and then return success,
and so we're going to handle this with
ajax, and so in JavaScript if we get this
return we know that we're logged out so
we can redirect maybe to the login page,.so let's go ahead and create a log out
route. Name it '/logout',  and we're going to connect it to the 'Logout', class, and now
down here you'll notice that session is
underlined red and this because it's an
undefined variable as of right now, so we
actually need to go ahead and create it.
So this is going to be the most
important thing, well it's all important
in this video, but this is going to be
the thing that actually instantiates the
session. So go ahead and create a session variable "session
= web.session.Session( )" and the second
session there has capital "S," and it's a
method so go ahead and open up
parentheses.
Now the first argument we're going to
pass this method is the actual "app,"
instance.
The second one we're going to pass it is
how we're going to store this persistent
data, so in this case it's going to be
just stored on the disk.
Let's go ahead and write "web.session.DiscStore( )" and
we're going to give our storage unit a
name so I'm just going to call it
"sessions" and i'm also going to pass in
another argument
we're going to have to identify it by
keyword here, so go ahead and type
", initializer=" and then we're going
to open up some "" here and
type 'user': 'none' And so this is we've
always got something here so we can
check if the user is logged in. Now that
doesn't actually initialize it, we
actually have to initialize the
initializer. So, go ahead and create a
"session_data = session._
initializer" So here we've actually
initialized our session. Go ahead and
drop another line and we're going to
chain, well actually let me
separate it like that. What we're going to
do is in our render method call here
we're going to pass a "globals=" variable, and this is going to create global
variables. So we're going to go ahead and
create 'session':
"session_data,"  and let's say a user
we're going, well let's say 'current_user':
It's going to be equal to let's just
say session data user, so
"session_data["user"]" and
that's what all we need to do. Now,
basically what that means is each one of
these routes we don't have to change
that, we don't have to pass anything into
this, but where we're creating them is in the global's and the render method, the session
variable is always going to exist to any of
these routes in the HTML templates. So
what we're going to do here, if I
just save this and run it we shouldn't
get any errors. We should be able to go
to "localhost:8080" and we're
getting an internal server error. So
let's go ahead and see why that is, and
so we're missing one required positional
argument and that's because in home, yeah
okay, so I actually defined it at some
point with logged in user. Let's just go
ahead and change that, re-run the script,
refresh, and you'll see that our page is
still right here. If we go to login we
actually haven't created the current
user the session data that we want to
create. So, when a user logs in we need to
actually instantiate that session. So
let's go ahead and login, no, check
log in right here.
So what we're going to do is if so is
correct is either going to be equal to
false in which case is just going to
return this, or it's going to be equal to
the user object. So if this is true that
means it's the user object. So what we're
going to go ahead and do is we're going
to create session user, session data user
there, so "session_data["user"] = isCorrect"  so we're
basically setting session user to the
user object here. Go ahead and save this
and refresh, we shouldn't get any errors,
and we don't.
So what we need to do is we need to add
one thing into our javascript file and
that's just to redirect. So when we
start a session we're going to have to
refresh the page so we're just going to
redirect it to the home page, because I mean
that makes sense, you don't stay on the
login form
you're already logged in, so let's go
ahead and type "window.location.href
= "/"; and this is basically just going to
redirect back into our home page.
Alright, so we need to do one last thing
and here we're creating a global
variable called session, so we're going
to just print that out here. We're going
to say Hello $session" Now we should not
get an error message, we should be able
to refresh, we don't have an error, so
let's go ahead and login. I believe the
user I created in the last video was nick1 and the password was avocado1,
awesome. So I did login successfully. So
what I'm going to do at this point is
we've got a user and basically if I
refresh the page you'll see that the
information stays persistent and that's
until you restart the server, so if I
restart the server here, and refresh,
we're going to see Hello  and
that's because there's no user. So what
we're going to do is we're going to
create an if statement here, so "$if $session['user'] == 'none':"
"&lt;h1&gt;Hello
CodeWizard&lt;/h1&gt;" then go "$else:" say hello
user. Still getting invalid syntax...
oh...
I accidently put a dollar sign there that
didn't, that didn't need to, so yeah, there
we go.
So as you can see it says Hello CodeWizard, let me just check the logic here
to make sure we're doing it correctly, we
are setting user, I believe, yes, we are
setting user to the actual user object.
So, once we get into the user object we
should be able to type "['name']" to access
that, so let's go ahead and restart this,
let's login as nick1, and avocado1, and
you'll see it says Hello nick.