Hey guys, in the last video we learned
about user management and session
management, and we created our login
script which is fully functional to log
a user in, however now we're going to
talk about logging a user out. It
includes making some changes to our
program, including the logout function
right here the class. So basically what
we need to do is we need to change, in
our code we've been using this right
here to determine if a user is logged in
or not, if user is logged in user becomes
the user object as defined down here.
However, what we need to do, and we again we've been using this in all of our
checks in our templates, what we need to
do is we need a way to reset this to
a null value, and in python that null value
is just "None"
it's a boolean operator. So, we're going
to set the initializer object to user is
None, and then basically what we need to
do is down here, well first let's go
through here, we need to manually check
now all of these instances "None" and change
them "none", accordingly.
Now, what I've added here in the main
layout is basically it's a very simple
if statement that says, if session user
equals none
meaning if the user is not logged in, we
want to provide them a login and
register link,
otherwise we need to provide them with a
logout link, and I've given this the ID
of a logout link and you'll see why in
just a moment.
Now this is not going to kill the
session automatically, what we need to do
is we need to first clear out the user
object manually, and so we're going to go
"session['user'] = None" and "session_data['user' = None]" and we're going to
going to save this.
We are also going to save our home
template and our main layout template,
and now we're going to create the ajax
logout, and how we're going to do that is
just add an "a" element here with an id of logout link, and we're going to be using this,
this is going to be the event target. So
copy the ID and come over to scripty here,
and what we're going to do is we're
going to just open up another event
trigger. So "$(document)on('click', '#logout-link')" and that's going
to result in the "function(e)" which we're
going to find next. We are going to pass
the event to the function so that we can
do this "e.preventDefault( );" We don't want the default action
of clicking on a link to have any impact
right now on this event. So what we need
to do is we need to create an ajax
request to this url right here, so the
log out page. Let's go ahead and "$.ajax({" "url: '/logout', type: 'GET',
and when we use GET as a type for
an ajax request we actually don't even
have to send any data, so what we're
going to do is move right on to the
"success: function(res)" i'm going to be
capturing the response, and basically in
the controller we've said to return
the word success, so that's what we're
going to check now. So "if(res == 'success')" we're just going to redirect
them to the login page "window.location.href = '/login';"
"else{" "alert("Something went wrong.");" there we go. Now we should all,
we should have all the makings here for
a working login and logout system, so
what we're going to do is I'm going to
save this, we're going to run the
controller file, no socket could be created
and that's because I've already got it
running, I guess. So let's close this tab, let's connect, re-run this, we're going to
refresh here, as you can see we're not
logged in because we are presented with
the generic Hello CodeWizard, so
let's go ahead and login. I believe the
user was nick1 and avocado1.
Now once we get logged in you'll notice
that it is personalized and this does
demonstrate the fact that we are logged
in,
in addition that if statement in the
main layout has presented now a logout
link. So we can do whatever we're going
to do here, refresh pages, the session
is going to remain persistent. However,
when we want to log out
we just click that log out link and you
can see now the system is registering
that we are logged out, we get the same
generic CodeWizard here, and we get the
login links.