Hey guys, welcome back. Now that we have a working user management system and we
can login and logout, what we need to do
is make this a little more functional.
And how we're gonna do that is we're
going to focus on the home feed for a
moment, and as you can see I've added a
bit of style here, I've added a sidebar
to the left, and i've added this post box,
and this is a preview of what each post
will look like. And it has buttons down here which we're going to maybe make
functional event later, maybe that's
going to be somewhat obvious after we
get done with everything else so we're not
going to have to do that. You guys can go
ahead if you want to turn, if you want to
turn this project into something really
awesome, then go for it,
however I don't think that's going to be in
the scope. Now as you can see i'm going
to show you guys the code that I wrote
right here in the home file. Literally
all this form is right here is a text
area and a button, and the text area you
can see I've personalized that by adding
the session user and then the name of
the user in there. Now, something else
have done is I've also added a bit of code
right here at the beginning of the
homepage, and we see two black lines, found
one, alright. Let's go ahead and fix that
to make it PEP happy.
Alright, what I've done is I've
automatically logged in a user manually and
statically by username and password so
we don't have to keep logging in every
time we restart this, and so the way you
do that is we're going to set a data
variable here, and it's going to be equal
to a method called type. Now in this
method the first argument is going to be
the string obj, the second argument is
going to be wrapped in parentheses it's going to be the word object, and then the
third argument is the dictionary that
includes username and password. So that's
how we create that object here and then
we load up the login model and we
basically just copy the same data as we
did down to the check login here, except
instead of getting input with the
username and password we're just setting that
statically, and so this way every time we
restart it we don't have to relog in and
that would be a little annoying. So I
want you guys to go ahead and pause
this video and do the same if you
haven't yet,
and that's going to make it a lot easier.
Now what we have to do in order to get
posts happening we first got to get them
in to a collection, so we're going to go
ahead and create a new model and we're
going to name this model "Posts" and i'm
feeling lazy so i'm going to go over to
my login model right here and i'm going
to copy the beginning here, and i'm going
to paste it right here just so we don't have
to keep doing it. I'm going to rename the
class "Posts" same as the file there, and this
basically just sets up the database
at the beginning of the class
instantiation. So i'm also going to set "self.Posts = self.db.posts" Now,
we're going to need a method to put a
post into the database and so we're going
to start with the javascript
stuff. So let's jump over into the Home
we need to do one thing and that's when
we submit that, so i'm going to copy that ID,
when we submit that we're going to get
everything from it which right now just
has a text area, but we're also going to
be putting it into the database with the
the user name of the logged in user. So let's jump over into our JavaScript here and
let's create an ajax method, "$(document).on('submit',
'#post-activity' and when you
define an ID here you need to use the
hashtag and the resulting event is going
to be a ", function(e){" we're going to pass
event in so that we can go "e.prevent( );"
With ECMAScript 6, or 2015,
you actually don't need to end
everything with a semicolon, but i'm
used to it so if you guys see that
you know you don't have to,
for the most part, I mean unless you're
putting multiple statements online like
this, you know, you will need to separate
them,
otherwise you vsn just leave it like that. So we're going to create an ajax method
here first we're going to build the form
variable so, "form = $
(this).serialize( )" and then "$.ajax({" we're going to set the "url: '/post-activity'," we're
going to create that route in a moment,
the "type: 'POST', "
"data: form," for now it's just going to contain the content,
and then on "success: finction(res){" "console.log(res);" whatever we get as
a response from the server, and if I come
up here it's probably going to complain
unterminated statement, that shouldn't
matter though.
Let's go ahead and run this, refresh the
page, when we post if I open this up it
should say failed to load because we
don't have that route creating. So let's
let's jump into our controller
here and let's get that route created. Up
here I've got API post i'm going to
change that to "post-activity" and that's where
we're going to post to. Do I have that?
Okay, yeah, I already got that written and i'm
going to delete that, i'm going to write
it again, that was from a test because what
we need to do, i'll explain it. So let's go
ahead and create a "class PostActivity:"
and we're going to "def POST(self):" and we're going to get
the "data = web.input( )" and now what we need to do is we need to set data username equal to
the login user, and so let's go ahead and
do this. So, "data.
username = session_data['user']['username']" Now we need to
instantiate the posts model and how we
do that we're going to have to import it
here ", Posts" We're going to come back down to the post activity method and we're going
to instantiate it using, "post_model = Posts.Posts( )" and then
we're going to need to create a method
to insert that data. So right now we're
just going to say "post_model.insert_post(data)" then we're
going to "return "success" "
Go ahead and save it. Now what we need to do here is create that method, so let's
go to Posts, "def_insert_post(self, data):" Now this is going to be really
really easy, all we need to do is in
input that into Posts, so let's go
ahead and set "inserted = self.Posts.insert( )" and then we're going to
pass data. Actually, we're just going to
capture the username and the content. So
""
and i'm going to "return True" in case we want to do some fact-checking
after, and add that new line to make pep
happy, and remove the indent to make pep
happy. Alright, let's jump into this. So i'm
going to refresh this page, I am logged
in, so i'm going to go ahead and I'm
going to just write a simple post. I'm
not actually going to write it,
well
yes, i'll it.
"This is a simple post and it should make
it into mongo" Go ahead and post that we
get a success here. So what i'm going to do is in Mongo i'm going to refresh and we do see a
post database, and we do see that the
user name was set correctly and the
content was set correctly. Now this is
awesome, I can continue inserting posts,
but we don't have a way to pull them out
yet. "Hello world. This is Nick." Alright,
so now we've got three posts in here, and
we're going to learn about getting them
out of the database in the next video.