Hey guys, so now we've got our posts in
the database and they're entirely
useless to us because we can't see them
on the front end, so what we're going to
do is we're going to turn this little
static code right here into a dynamic
repeating content based on all posts
that we bring out of the database. So how
we're going to do that we're going to
jump into the Posts model again, and
we're going to "def get_all_posts:" and this
is going to be simple,
this is going to be "all_posts = self.Post.find( )" and
then what we're going to have to do is,
and this is where it's going to get a
little tricky, when we pull out the
posts from the database we can navigate
them in Python but we won't be able to
navigate them in the template files. So
what we've got to do is we've got to
manually kind of recreate a list of
posts using Python dictionaries rather
than pymongo cursors, and i'll show you
guys why right now. So, we're going to get
all posts,
we're just going, we need to actually get
the user of the post as well, so "for post in
all_posts:"
Let's set posts.user = self.Users.find_one( )" and here we're going
to look for ""  because we are storing that, and then
we're going to just "return all_posts" Now
in our controller what we've got to do,
and we've got to make a few changes here and in the home file, let's jump up here
to the home file. We've got the
post model so let's jump down instantiate
it, whoa what just happened there?
So let's go ahead and instantiate the
"post_model = Posts.Posts( )" "posts = post_model.get_all_posts( )"
and then what we're going to do is we're
going to pass "posts" into the home
method, and then we're going to jump over into the Home file and we're going to
"$def with (posts)" and then up here at the top, actually right here before the posts
begin, i'm just going to print out "$posts"
and you guys are going to see what
happens. We're getting the server error and that's because...ok, one sec.
It's that all right, let's change this to
this, start again. We're still getting an
error because we need to do that in both
places here, we can't access them as an
object if they're a dictionary. There we
go. Now you see we get a map object. What
I'm going to do in the Home file is I'm
going to go "$for post in posts:" "$post" I'm going to try
and print out each post. You guys are going to see this didn't work very well at all,
and this is because it is a map object,
and so the stuff in here the template
doesn't really know what to do with it.
So what we have to do as I told you guys
before we're going to come over the
Posts model here, we're going to create a
new variable called "new_posts = [ ]"
and then for, actually let's do this but that, because we can make
things a lot easier, i'll show you guys
why. So just before the for statement
here we're going to add a new variable
called posts, and for each post in all posts
we're going to go "new_posts.append(post)" and then
instead of returning all posts we're
going to return "new" posts. We are going to
save this, restart the server, and now refresh, and as you can see now I can access the
content in here, and you'll also see that
the user is the entire user object that
posted it.
Maybe we'll want to strip out the
password at some point, but for right now
that's, that's ok. So, what we're going to
do is we're going to iterate over these
and put the dynamic content in each
post instead of printing it out, so let's
jump into the Home file,
there. So, we're going to access "$post['user']['name']" and then "$post['content']" I'm going to
refresh, and you'll see that each one of
my posts that I posted Mongo is now
there, and if I "Even having a new one." and post that it's going to be there as well.
Now, we could insert it with the date, and
most likely going to do that at some
point and so we can flip this around so
most recent is at the top, for right now this
is really all we need to understand is
how to get PyMongo map objects into
lists that we can actually iterate over
in the template file.