Alright guys, welcome back. I've done
a bit of work behind the scenes here
between the last video and this video, and
the work is basically designed and
setting up some templates because that's
not exactly relevant to what we're doing,
and I assume we're all going to be
designing something slightly different,
so we're going to be focusing more on
the back and functionality. So, what I've
done was I just included masonry isotope
here for the layout so it makes it a
nice inconsistent column, and what I mean
by that is this one doesn't have to
appear at the same beginning point as the
left-hand column. So it's kinda, you know,
each one is consistent in how much
border is between each one. So that's
isotope, go to "isotope.metafizzy.co"
this is the package that I used, they
have great documentation, so check that
out if you're interested in that.
Now the other thing I did was I have
created a profile page here that
basically it's only going to show the
users post that you're viewing the
profile of. So in this case i've mapped
this link right here to the logged-in
user, so profile/whatever the user is.
And I've also got an info section that
contains an About, Hobbies, Birthday, and then some professional information here. Now
I've also, I haven't done this or these you guys can do if you
want, I just put them there because
that's kind of the scope of what we're
doing, so regarding the code what I was
going to do is using ace editor which if
you guys don't know what it is it's a
javascript library where you can create
a code editor directly within a web page,
and you can customize it with different
syntax highlighting so you can make it
work for Python. You can actually maybe
even a drop down for the user to select
the syntax kinda like pastebin. That's
beyond the scope of what we're doing though. What we're going to be doing right
now is we're going to be learning about
how to modify this information and
then print it out. If I go into my PyCharm
file here for settings
you'll see that it's just a form and
it's all static information as set in the
value, so we're not actually doing
anything dynamic with this page yet,
and that's what we're going to be doing.
We're first going to be focusing on the
settings page here, which again it's
just a copy of this page except each one
of these is an input, and with the same
names as you can see here, so name, about,
hobbies, and birthday. So we're going to be
submitting that form through ajax so i'm
going to go ahead and copy the ID of
this form, and i'm going to write out a new
eventhandler right here. So let's go
ahead and write "$(document).on('submit',
'#settings-form', function(e));"
We are going to pass event into it "e.preventDefault( );" so that we
can prevent the default behavior of form
submit, then we're going to serialize
formed by setting "var form = $(this).serialize( );" and this should look familiar to
you guys because this is how we've been
doing it all along.
Now we're going to begin writing our
"$.ajax()"
the "url: 'update-settings'," The "type: 'POST'," "data: form,"
and then on "success: function(res)" I'm going to say "if(res ==
"success")" "window.location.href = window.location.href;" "else" For
simplicity you guys can make that dynamic, you can actually put the new content into
the the page itself. Otherwise, we're
going to "alert(res);" itself.
So, now we need to go into the Controller,
and what I've done also if you guys
haven't figured it out, which you should, I
have created some new routes. It's
nothing special, it's the same things
we've done up here. This is profile/
anything/info and that's going to
redirect to the info page. The next one is
settings and this doesn't require any
additional parameters, and then the next
one is profile/anything. So just to
note, if you were to put this above this,
then if you tried to go to this link
right here the info link it would always
go to the activity link, because this is
kind of a catch-all. So any longer,
similar URLs you need to put before the
catch all one level less, I guess. So, yeah.
So what we're going to do is you see
that I've created settings equals UserSettings
well now what I'm going to do
is I'm going to create the route for
ajax request which is '/update settings', and it's going to route to a class called
"UpdateSettings", Now we're going to go
ahead and define that class and also
what I've done for the user profile is
the user profile is the main activity
page here, so it's what shows my posts. So
what I've done is I've added the
automatic login script because we don't
want to always have to log in every time
we restart server, and then in the posts
model i've created a new method called
get_user_posts and we're passing at the user name of the login, well actually, of
whatever username is right here, so it's
only gonna get posts from them. So, if I
look at the Posts file here it's
basically the same as get all posts, the
only differences were passing a
parameter of username equals user in
the find method, and then we're also sorting it in descending order by date. So,
everything else should be same. So what
we're going to do is down here we're
going to end, similar thing for user
settings except we're not passing anything
in there, yet. So what we're going to do is
we're going to define "class UpdateSettings"
and it's going to be a "def POST(self):" So,
we're going to get the input here, so
"data = web.input( )" and then we're
going to set username equal to our
sessions username. So, "data.username = session_data["user"]["username"]"
Now what we're going to do I'm, I should
have named the login model accounts
model, and you know integrated the register model into it so that we only have one
model. So this should be accounts model,
i'm going to be working in that to create a
new method, so we're going to be calling
that new method here. What we're going to
do is instantiate the model, so "settings_model = LoginModel.LoginModel( )"
and then let's go ahead and write "if
settings_model.update(data):"
So if this returns true then we're going to "return
"success" "else:" we're going to "return "A fatal error has occurred." So let's go ahead and
save this since we are done in the Controller file. Let's go into the Login model and
build out this update info method. So go ahead and "def update_info" we're going to
pass in "(self, data):" Now what we're going to do is we're just going to create a method,
so let's go ahead "updated =" and
here's how to update information in
PyMongo. Go ahead and target the collection, so this case it's self.Users.update_one( )"
it's this simple. Now the parameters
that we're going to be passing in are two
dictionary objects. So the first one is
going to define which exact item or
document in the collection we want to
update, so here we're going to target by
"," And then the second is going to be, you need to begin
it like this, with the keyword "" and
then there's a dictionary inside there,
or in our case what we're setting as
data in here should already be a
dictionary. So we're just gonna push all
the information from "data" into this set
method. So let's go ahead and "return True"
We're going to save this, and refresh it, we're going to jump over this file and refresh
this. We're going to go to the settings
page here and i'm going to update my
about section too. "This is my about section." and I'm going to save it, and it didn't save
it correctly. So let's go ahead and find
out why. Oh, sorry,
yes it did. It's just we haven't
dynamically generated this.
So what we're going to be doing now is
just working on that, so I'm going to
come into the settings here, and i'm
going to set it to "$session['user']
['name']" I'm going to copy
this value because i'm going to just
paste here to save time. This value for
hobbies and then the value for birthday,
so we're going to rename these accordingly. This is going to be "['about']" this is going
to be "['hobbies']" and this is going to be
"['birthday']" and normally for a birthday field
you would use it a date or
timepicker, we're not gonna be doing that
right now. So as you can see this is my
about section, i'm gonna update my name
here to Nick Wally, save it, and you will
see that this does update. Now what we
need to do on the main profile pages
implement that here.
So what I'm going to do is up at the top
here we're just going to enter
the "$session" information because we're
storing the entire "['user']" object in
this file. So session, user, and "['name']" and
additionally we put a headline value
here, and that's basically the same as
all this so we're not doing that. Now
what we're going to do is we're going to
close the settings file and we're going
to do something similar with
the info file.
So if we go to info here, as you can
see it's all static and we don't want to
use the session information for this
because we're actually targeting a user
in the URL here, so we need to get that
out. So if i go over into the Controller
and look at UserInfo the username right
here is this,
so what we're going to do is we're going
to instantiate, well actually the login
model's already instantiated, what we're
gonna do is we're going to "user_info =
login.get_profile(user)"
What we're going to do at that point is we are going to send the "(user_info)"
into the profile. We actually need
to go to find this method here get
profile, so let's go ahead and jump into
the LoginModel as well
again and we're going to, whoops don't know why that copied, I think I named it "def
get_profile(self, user):" So what we're
going to do is we're just basically
going to do the same things up here,
except we're going to be passing it into
in a different format. So let's go ahead
and "user_info = self.Users.find_one( )" and we're going
to find based on "" which is going to be the user that we're passing
in, and then we're going to just "return
user_info" We're going to come back over to our Controller and we're passing it into the Info file,
so what we need to do in the Info file
is we need to "$def with (user_info)" Go
ahead and save this. Now what we're going
to do is I'm going to print out "$user_info
["name"]" We're going to refresh, going to,
there you go.
Now this is going to be different if I
login as someone else. So i'm gonna go
ahead and log out, i'm going to create a
new user and this is going to be
"nickwally1" "Wally Germaine" "wally@pb.net"
and my password is going to be the same
"avocado1" Login...and to do this what we
actually need to do is go into the
controller here, I need to remove this
login method for each page because I
don't want to be automatically logged in
at this point.
So here's a profile here as well, so i'm
using the model there. And then post
activity we don't need to do anything,
check login post registration and all, so
we need to remove it from the home page
as well. Let's go ahead and save, and
refresh, going login as, I don't remember my username, so
let's go ahead and type "nickwally1"
Alright, i'm going to set it to "avocado1" going to login. As you can see
Nick Wally posted these posts, and if I
go to my profile
it's going to be static again. What
we're going to do is go to "nick1"
Alright it was the info that we stored
that in. So activity, let me have a look here
on the activity page which is profile,
we're going to be passing the same thing.
So we need to go to our Controller here,
and under UserProfile we need to do the
same thing that we did in UserInfo. I'm going to copy
and paste this there, and we're going to
pass in "user_info" and then in our
Profile here we're going to define with
posts and "user_info" Here at the top
we're going to change this to "$user_info["name']"
and we're also going to change all these
to "$user_info['username']" and i'm going to replace
copy this, change nick1 in there, and there we go.
So if I refresh, and refresh this, I get
an internal server error. The type is not
because we need to login, alright. So let's go ahead
and login "nickwally1" We could build some protection around that but i'm not going
to focus on that right now. Going to login, go to my profile, and we see that my info is
this,
however if I go to settings, so
here's where we would need to do some
error checking. So if we go into settings
here, in here about, what we need to do is
check if it exists. So, you would need
to do some error checking perhaps, maybe
set some default data here in the
controller if user info doesn't include
any fields, so you can actually create a
little function to go generate any empty
field, and maybe even just put a space in
there just so that the key exists within that
database. So that's all for this video.
In the next video, I'm not sure if we'll be
continuing WebPy or moving on, but
either way we're going to have some fun.