Hey guys, welcome back. Before we continue with anything and I think we're getting
close to the end of the Web.py module,
but before we even finish it we need to
talk about relative datetimes because
they're so important in today's day and
age. People don't like to see full date
times printed out, like in Unix time or
anything, they want to see pretty
relative dates. So like instead of seeing
September 15, 2016 at 11:18 am, what they would like to see is like a minute ago,
you know.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to install a package, so go ahead and
write "pip3 install" and then the package
we're going to install is called "humanize"
Now i've already installed this, you
guys will need to, it's pretty simple it
shouldn't get stuck or anything and you should now have this installed. So what we're
going to do with this let's launch a Python
shell "python3" and i'm going to show you guys how
to use this. So, first we're going to
"import humanize" and then we're going
to "import datetime" Now as you can see up here
the current time is 11:18 AM, so what I'm going to do is
I'm going to set a variable called
"posted_date" and this is going to be
"= datetime.datetime( )" and here
we're going to enter the "2016, 9,
15, 11, 14"  so
in this case let's say 14. So this is
going to be equal to September 15, 2016
11:14 AM. So let's hit enter. Now what we
need to do is we need to essentially
humanize this and how we're going to do
that is by typing out the following. So
you first you need to access "humanize" and
then inside in that class there is a
method called ".naturaltime" which does
not adhere to pep guidelines because
there should be an underscore between
natural and time, but there's not, and
then this is a method so open up your
"( )" and then what you're going
to do is pass it two arguments.
The first one is going to be the current
date time so we're just going to go
"datetime.datetime.now( )" minus whatever date you want to print out relative time.
So in this case I've stored in a
variable called "- posted_date" and you'll
see that prints out '6 minutes ago' and
so when we're working with dates in
our application with Webpy, this is how
we're going to do it. So let's get into
that.