Alright, so what we're going to be doing
is adding a relative timestamp to each
one of our posts and so we actually need
to change the posts model here, because
when we're getting posts we're setting,
where is it right there, setting the name
in the content of the post, and so what
we actually need to do as well, actually
we're not doing that there were doing it
right here,
so what we're doing here is we need to
be able to access it.
So, in this instance what we're going to,
go ahead and open the controller
here,
well maybe this will work right away.
What we're going to do is we're going to
set under here let's open up &lt;span class="timestamp"&gt; and then
"$ humanize.naturaltime(datetime.datetime.now)" Actually, rather than
putting this in our templates let's do
this at the model level. So what we're
going to do here is just print out "$post['timestamp']" and then we're going to create
the timestamp in the posts model. So what we're going to do is we're going to
"import humanize" and then right here
when we're getting all posts we're going
to set "post["timestamp"] = to humanize.naturaltime( )" going to pass
in "datetime.datetime.now( ) - post["date_
added"])" and this should work.
So let's go ahead and check this out.
Going to go ahead and open up a browser.
Then you'll see that it does in fact
work exactly how it's supposed to.
Now, the only thing i'm going to do is
I'm going to style this up a little bit
to make it look a little pretty, and
there we go.
So if I post a new one here
you'll see that I posted now. If I wait a
few seconds and refresh it's going to say
posted x seconds ago.
If we were to wait even longer it would
say posted a few minutes ago, you know,
etc. So that's how we're, that's how we've
improved this, now we're also going to
build out a comments section for each
one of these posts and then I think
that's the last thing that we're doing,
and I'm doing that show you guys how you
can chain different
collections kinda a one object like we
did for the user object here.