Alright guys, welcome back. This is going
to be probably a longer video than our
other ones, but we're going to be doing it a bit quicker because all of the key
concepts involved in what we're about to
do
we've already learned and we've already
used those concepts. So, this shouldn't be
anything new
it's just going to extend our application here a little bit further,
and that's where we're going to leave
this application and move on from
Webpy on to some other things. So what we're going to do is basically add comments to
our application. We're not going to make
them dynamic, we're not going to make them
like first maybe just show one comment
and then you can toggle it and it'll
drop down, we're not going to do all that
fancy stuff, we're just going to build a
bit of basic functionality for comments.
So, we have a form here and this is
static right now it's just going to print
out the actual posts content name and
what not, and so what we're going to do
is I've already built this form for you guys
are going to want to go ahead and do
this, so you might want to pause the
video now and make sure you have an
input with the name post ID, and you're
going to actually print out the post ID
in that input as a value, and you're going to
have a text area named comment-text and that's where we're actually going to
submit that comment. Now once you guys have this form built you need to make sure
it's in a form with a class name that
you can target,
I've named mine comment form. I'm going to jump over to scripty here and we're
going to do the exact same thing we've
done to this entire section. Just going
to say "$(document).on('submit'), ".comment-form", function(e)" We're going to "e.prevent
Default( );" action on form submit here, we don't want it refreshing the page, going to
create a "var form = S(this).serialize( );" and we're actually
going to build out our "$.ajax(" request. The "url: "/submit-comment"," the "type:
"POST"," "data: form," and then on "success:
function(res)" and just "console.log(res);" Something else
we can return a JSON object here and
set "dataType "json"," and
this will allow us to parse the response
as JSON. I'm not sure if we're going to do
that, so i'm going to go ahead and save this. Now we need to jump over to the Controller and
build a route called SubmitComment, same route that you're ajax'ing the request
to, and name a class
SubmitComment like this. Let's go down here, and I've already built this out but i'm
going to remove it, and we're going to
write it again. So we're going to "def
POST(self):" and we're going to get the
"data = web.input( )"
and we're going to set "data.username = session_data["user"]['username']"
Then what we're going to do is we're
going to have to write a bit of code in
the Posts model, so right now we're going
to "post_model = Posts.Posts( ): and then
we're going to store inserted, let's name it "added_comment =" to
make a little more straightforward i
guess. We're going to target the
"post_model.add_comment(data)" I'm going to
say "if added_comment:" "return added_comment" "else:"
"return  which is a forbidden
error.
Alright, so let's jump over to the post
model and actually build out this method.
So we need to "def add_comment(self, comment):" here. What we're going to do is we're
simply going to we need a new collection,
so go ahead and add this code
"self.Comments = self.db.comments" here actually instantiating the
collection itself.
We're also going to "import ObjectId" and
this is necessary,
actually I don't think it is necessary.
Alright, so let's go ahead and jump down
here. We're going to insert the comment
here so "inserted = self.Comments.insert()" So let's say "post_id":
comment.post_id comment.post, "comment-text":  comment
["comment-text"],
"date_added":  datetime.datetime.now( )" and as
you guys can see this has already become non PEPPY, so let's go ahead and do this,
and then we're going to add "username": comment
["username"] Going to turn that just to make things consistent with the same type of
dictionary access. Then let's "return inserted" let's refresh, let's refresh this, and
confirm that we're able to add a comment. Click add comment we get no response.
Let's go ahead and check in here, I should have two comments now and I do, awesome. As you
can see what we've done is we've stored
comment text, post ID, date added, username
and then the ID of itself.
Now, this post ID if i go ahead and look
at posts, this one's in 0330, so this is the
post that this comment is on and that's
how we tie it would make it a bit
relational even though it's NoSQL. And
that's how to insert comments. Now we're
going to talk about getting the comments
out. So what we need to do is in the
get_all_posts here, for posts, and all posts
this is going to target the post itself.
We're going to set "post["old_comments"] = self.
Comments.find()" and here we need to covert the
post ID into a string and "str(post["_id])" Now
i'm going to create a new variable
called comments, actually,
"post["comments"]" we want this to be part of the post itself. It's going to be a "= [ ]"
You do something similar here so we can
get the user timestamp of the the post
added. So what we're going to do is "for
comment in post["old_comments]:"
Let's just make sure we can "print(comment)" and i'm going to remove this,
we don't want anything else printing out
just so we can verify the comments are
being found and they are. As you see
here, the post ID and this one also has a
post ID, so these are the actual comments for one particular post. So what we're
going to do is for comment we actually
need to get this, "comment["user"] =
self.Users.find_one({"username":
comment
["username"]})" "Post timestamp, actually "comment["timestamp"]"
= to humanize.naturaltime(datetime.datetime.
now- comments( ) - comment["date_added"])" Then what
we're going to do is "post["comments"].
append(comment)" Save this, refresh, we
should not get any errors at all, if we
do it means we've done something
terribly wrong, and we didn't. So, I'm
pretty sure at this point that we can
now access post comments in the Home
file. Let's just go ahead and confirm
that, "$post["comments"]
and as you can see indeed we did. So what we're going to do is "$for comment in post
["comments"]:"
we're going to basically use our
iterative template here, and now perhaps
"$comment" timestamp, "$comment" users name, and "$comment" content, and also you know
link to the user's profile who wrote the
comment. Then we're going to rerun, and
we're going to refresh, getting a server
error so let's go find out why. KeyError:
'content' and that's right we named it
'comment-text' right...there we go. KeyError
'comment-text' let's rename that to 'content'
What i'm going to do, is I'm just going to
manually modify these comments here to
change comment text to "content" save it,
and then this one the same thing, that's
already changed. Both of them were
stored as content, alright, good stuff. Then
we need to change the post method here
to make this store that is "content" that
was the problem in one of the
objects the comment text didn't exist,
it had a comment or content used, and the other one was different so of course it
wouldn't work. Now, I believe I have
another user here, i'm going to go log in
and comment on one these posts as that
user. So let's go ahead and find that
user, nickwally1.
Alright, let's go ahead and logout "nickwally1" and "avocado1" and you guys are
going to see, oh wait, of course this won't
work because once it hits this page it logs
in. We gotta go to the controller and then
remove that auto login bit of code, save, refresh,
and now let's login again. So "nickwally1"
and "avocado1"
Alright, let's write a comment "I'm writing a comment TOO!" submit, we have to refresh this, as you can see this
is going to redirect to my profile and
this is actually working. Now we could
upload images for the avatars, well
I think we're actually going to do that
just because I think that's like the
last basic thing that this needs in
order for it to be complete,
managing the profiles information like
the image and
the this right here. And if I go back and go
to this profile I should also see, yeah,
awesome. But I'm not seeing the newest
template for each post because we haven't
implemented that.