Alright, welcome back guys. This is the
last video in the Webpy section, we're
going to be learning how to upload files,
store them onto a database, store the
file path in the database, and then use
those images as the avatar and background
images for a user. So, if I go ahead and open the page here we've actually made a huge
issue, and so I've actually dropped the
entire database. If you guys don't know
how to do that right click, click drop
database, and it will get recreated in
our code here.
So what we're going to do is, it's
on the settings page but we need to do
is modify how the user accounts get
created, and so i'm going to, well
I'm going to open up the register model
here, and i'm going to say "avatar":
black, just a blank string "", and then also
"background": "" so
that even though these don't exist when
we're registering the account, we still
have the keys in Mongo so it's not gonna
bring any issues with it, and actually
i'll do the same for name, actually
already set name, , "about": "" , "hobbies": and
"", "birthday": "" was the other one.
And so now every time we create a user
is going to set all these empty fields
which we are going to need later on. So
i'm going to go ahead and save that, going to
refresh the application, and i'm going to
refresh this page, go to register, "nick" "Nick Germaine"
then my password, as always, is going to be "avocado1" Now again we still don't
redirect here so i'm going to go ahead
and login, and then i'm going to go to
settings here, and this little bit of
code is what we want to focus on right
now. What we're going to do is we need to
import OS into our controller, for the
sake of this video we're actually going
to be doing all the code in the
controller. So what we need to do is on
the settings page, the avatar form where
is that, Avatar right here, so this is the
avatar upload. I've added these
attributes or properties to the forum,
we're not going to send this request
through ajax we're actually going to be
doing it the old school way just because
waiting for file upload progress data is
kind of unreliable and I don't want to
focus on how to make that work right now,
so we're going to just do it the old
school way. The input is named avatar and
then we have a submit button. Now, you
need to set input type to multipart/form-data when you're sending images, the
method is going to be post obviously, and
then the action is the route that we
want to send the file to, so in this case
it's /upload-image/avatar and
you guys will see why avatar is listed
there. We're going to do the same thing
for the background upload except it's
going to reference a different URL, and I'm
going to
actually do that now. So i'm going to
copy this, put that down there, and just
replace the the word avatar with
"background" and we can use that to check
what type it is and then do something based on what type is. So we are done with this
file, we've got everything we need,
let's go back over to the Controller and
actually build out that route.
So, what we need is '/upload-image/(.*)'. "" and then we're
going to create a class called "UploadImage" Let's scroll down here and do that
right under the last class that's
defined here, let's create a "class
UploadImage:" there we go.
We're going to "def POST(self, type):" so this is
either going to be avatar or background.
So, what we're going to do at this point
is we need to first get the input, so
we're going to store that in let's just
say "file = web.input( )" and here we're going to set "avatar=,
background=" by default.
And now what we're going to do is we
need to get the directory what we want
to work with, and so for instance each
user is going to have their own
directory here with information in it, so i'm
actually going to move that to trash right now. It's
going to be /static/uploads and then
the users directory. So what we need to
do we're going to store that in a
variable called "file_dir
= os.getcwd( )"
it's going to get the current working
directory, so the CodeWizard directory
right here.
"+ "/static/uploads/" + session_data["user"]["username"]"
Now what we need to do is check if that
exists and if it doesn't exist then we
actually need to create it. So "if not os.path.exists(file_dir):" we're going to
create it so "os.mkdir(fil_dir)" Now we can move on to the to the fun stuff.
So this is going to check if we actually
have a, this is gonna be based on the
type, I guess. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to, yeah let's do things like this.
file path going to be equal to, actually let me put this in an if statement just to make
sure. "if "avatar" or
"background" in file:" So if
one of these is in file then we're
actually going to do stuff with it, so
"filepath = file[ ]"
then we're going to open up square
brackets here and we're actually gonna
put "type" the variable that's coming in here, and then ".filename.replace( )"
and so basically what we're doing is if
you're running this on Windows we're
going to get rid of the backslashes
here and replace them with '\\',
'/' So that's going to be the filepath.
The "filename = filepath.split
("/")[-1] and
this is going to get the last item in
that array, and then we're actually going
to create our file. So file is going to
be equal to "f =" and we're going to just
basically use the same, the same open
method that we've used before, so let's
"open(file_dir) + "/" +
filename" and then let's go ahead and we
need to we need to open it in binary
mode and so it needs to be' and
binary mode so we're going to use 'wb'
there, alright. Now we're actually
going to write the file, so go ahead and type
"f.write( )" and here what we're going to
write is basically the same type thing
we used up here, so filename and then
we're actually going to
read the file so it's not gonna be file
name. We're gonna read (file[type].file.read( ))]"
So we're going to write whatever we can
read out of that file, this going to be binary
data that's why we need to use the b
argument there, then we can safely close
that. So "f.close( )" We're done with that
now what we're going to do is we're
going to, we're going to actually update
this in Mongo, so let's go ahead and
create the URL based on what
kinda you know if I want to show it in here
we need to use the path beginning in
/static/uploads, we wouldn't get
the current working directory. So what we
have to do this is just to be able to
make filesystem path if it doesn't exist.
So we're going to create an object here, a
dictionary rather "update = ", and we're going to set update avatar,
actually it's going to be type, actually
it's going to be,
yeah, "update["type"]" = type" "update[type] =" and then whatever the type
is, so this could be either a key avatar or
background in there. So update type
that's going to be equal to the URL, so
we're going to go ahead and '/static/
uploads' + session_data["user"]["username"] + "/" + filename so there we go.
So that's going to be the URL and then we need the username as well so "update["username"]" and
let's just go ahead and set this to
"= session_data["user"]["username"]" Now we're
going to instantiate the login model
which should be the account model, but
it's not,
let's go ahead and do that. I'm going to
name it "account_model =
LoginModel.LoginModel( ) there we go.
And then we're going to do create a
variable called "update_avatar =
account_model.update_image(update)" and we're going to pass it
the update variable in here. That should
happen successfully now outside of that
second if condition i'm going to
"raise web.seeother( )" this is basically
we're going to redirect to "/settings" page
once the file is uploaded. So that is all
we have to do, I hope this makes sense to
you guys at least in this file. We're not
done yet but we're done with this file.
This should not look very difficult it's,
it's very standard stuff, and we've done all
this actually before. So, the the only
difference is we are now doing in Webpy
and it's to upload and image. So, what we need
to do is actually go create that update
image method, so let's copy this, go into
login model here,
and let's "def update_image(self, update):" Set "updated = self.
users.update_one({"username":
update("username"]})" and then we're going to set, here's the fun part, we're going to "" and I
think I'm gonna be able to do this. We've
set type in there, so let me type
"" what did I name that...
should just name this "img" that would
make more sense, so "img" so this should be
equal to either avatar equals the image
path, or background equals image path.
Let's go ahead and see if this works. "return updated"
I'm going to login...I am not sure if I missed
anything...we'll see.
I'm going to go ahead and upload an image here, going to savem we get an internal server error. So
let's see what's up with that.
Ok, so, basically we can't do that.
So, what we're going to do is we're going
to say if update["type"] ==, oh wait,
that could be the issue, it actually
might work. Go back to the home page, let's login "nick"
password. I'm going to go to settings
here, going to go to upload an image, and it worked.
It doesn't look like it worked, but it
worked. If I now actually refresh the
entire Mongo collection here and go into
to CodeWizard, collections/users, we will
see that my avatar is actually set to an
image. Now this is awesome. This means
what we can do is we can actually,
we actually already have that in
the users you know avatar.
Well, actually, user info will be got if
you go to profile. So what we're going to
do while the settings themselves the
avatar should be the avatar, so what
we're going to do is we're going to set
that here by going "$session['user']['avatar']"
So let's rerun this, go home,
login, and as you can see that is very much
the case. If I change the image, there we
go,
it's an old one, and that one didn't work.
Oh, yes i did, but why isn't it
refreshing here? Go home, settings,
that's interesting....
did my session information get updated? If I logout, that would be another issue altogether.
You know what, that's what it was, yeah.
Okay and then the background image
should update as well, but what we're
going to do is we are going to add that
in first. So, the background right here
the URL is going to be equal to '$session["user"] I have to escape that I guess,
this might be tricky.
Yeah, it's gonna be tricky. Okay, I think
in CSS you don't have to add anything
around these, so we're going to try like
this it might get a little messy here, let's
go ahead and try. So "$session['user']
['background']" Save this, this should work.
Let's go home because
we need to login again, click settings, and
as you can see the fact that I don't
have a background image doesn't impact
whether this page crashes or not. So another
interesting thing is if I go to profile/Nick it's still going to show this because
the profile that we've created doesn't
do the same thing. So if I go into
profile here and set this where, there's
name,
here's avatar right here. "$session['user']['avaar']"
copy this,
'background'
There, save that there,
refresh this, this should be the same for
everything else too. So i'm going to copy
the background image here, go to info,
and i'm going to paste the background
image over that.
Actually, it's not session, was it
profile, I was accessing this is in some way.
Where is no profile page, right here.
user_info that's what is. So let me do this
right quick, change those, jump back over
to info, change those here as well.
Alright, let's refresh, go over here,
login...
go to settings, i'm going to upload a
background image,
save, and when we refresh it doesn't do
anything but if I go to profile it
should, and it definitely does. if I go to info
as well, it does as well. Then we go back
and nick1 doesn't exist so actually I
had hard-coded those in here on this
page only, so i'm going to replace that.
There, now all that should work correctly.
We're basically done, now you also
could go into the, into the posts and in
the user object there should be the
avatar and everything in there.
So, on the homepage which is right here
what we could do is every time it says
avatar here, what we would do is "style="background:url($post['user']['avatar']"
Let's save that...and so if we refresh i'm not sure if that even has
the proper style,
we're actually going to go login, and on
the homepage
"Here's a new post" hit post, and we see
it with my avatar which doesn't have the
correct style. So, basically you'd set
"background-size: cover !impotant"
background position, and you do
that basically you can see that we do
have a correct working avatar
and background system. So thank you guys
for watching this video in this section,
I'm not too sure which module
we're going to be exploring next, but
it's also going to be very fun. So, I
can't wait to get started on that.