Hey guys, welcome back. So, now that we've learned how to actually build an
application, it's still pretty bare,
and so what we're going to be learning
about is templates and how to use them
effectively. And so what we're going to
do is create a template here, and it's
just going to be inside of a directory
so let's go ahead and create a directory
called "resources" Now we're also going to be storing bootstrap here later on and
so we're just going to create a new HTML
file in here and we're going to call it
"main" and in here let's just type, I'm
going to type some HTML so that you guys
can see basically what this is going to
look like.
So let's create "&lt;h1&gt;Name: $name&lt;/h1&gt;"
and the way that you access the
variables that you pass into this is
through the "$" there and so
what we're going to do is we need to
actually import that into this HTML file
and you do that as "$def with (name)" and then the variables that you're going to be
capturing into this file.
Let's go ahead and remove actually all this, just write it for right now just with
HTML, and we're also going to be passing
along an age. So, your "&lt;p&gt;Your age is $age&lt;/p&gt;"
What we need to do here is import ", age"
variable as well. So let's go ahead and save
this. Now if we jump back over to our
main Python file we're going to actually
have to tell Python where to find all
our templates, so let's go ahead and type
"render = web.template.render"
and tell it to look in the "("resources/")" Now, when we create
the, when we create the function down
here, what we actually need to do is we
need to "return render.main" and our files
called main so we're going to put the name
of the file, and then we're going to
capture the variables "(name, age)" in
here. Now we need to extend this a little
further to also pass name/age into here.
So what we're going to do put another "/" and that right there  "(.*)"
We're going to go ahead and save that, so
what we should be able to do now is
access nick/ and then my age, it's to come here it's going to run this method right
here within the index class because
again we're telling it to look for the
index class if this URL is accessed. It's
going to render the main HTML file,
and let's just run it and see,
stop that there, run it again, we're
say that as you can see this is
Name: Nick, Your age is 27. So just a little
note if you're wondering how can we get
them in these names if we're not
specifying the name of each variable,
this is going to be the first argument
here, and this is going to become the
second argument here.
So, again, if we wanted a third one we'd
have to pass them in the same order into
this function in order to name them and
then use them elsewhere. Now, again we're
going to define this with these two
variables, so you need to name the
variables that you're pushing into this
render method, you need to push those
down to the HTML file, and then use them
by using dollar side proceeding that
variable name. And that is how to
get a basic template setup and we're
going to be following this a little
further as well, actually what we're
going to be doing we're going to be
setting up
Mongo to this web application that we're creating.