Hey guys, welcome back. So far in this
subsection we've learned what Webpy is
and how to set up a basic example
using Webpy and how to serve up web
pages, but I mean there's a lot more to
it then we're going to learn eventually
but we're not going to need to learn all
these right now and I don't think it's
going to make sense to go through each
one without a full example of a
practical use of this, and so what we're
going to be learning from here on out
during the subsection is how to make a
website that has dynamic data, and we're
going to be setting up our project as a
model view controller or MVC. And what
that is basically is the first entry to
our app that defines the routes is going
to be the controller, and the controller
is going to go and access other files
called the model, and it's going to
collect the data that's going to be
generated onto the page, and then once
it has all the data it's going to that
to send all that data to the view or the
HTML template. Now we've already learned
about the templating of Webpy and how
to use that we're going to be taking
that a bit further, but first what you're
going to have to do is go to
"getbootstrap.com" and download. So, when you first get to this page you're going to
come right here, click download bootstrap, and download the compiled and minified
version right here. We're not just going
to use bootstrap, we want it to be a
little bit pretty, so go ahead and go to
this URL add that into the discussion on
the right-hand side, and just download
the zip file. Now once you've got both
of those and you unzip them it's going
to look something like this. So i'm going
to go ahead and create a new project
here, it's going to be python, going to
get rid of that, and we're going to be
creating a sort of social network mini
blog posting website, and we're also
going to be using PyMongo as the
database drive force, so that's going to be
fun. This is going to be, you are going
to be learning how to combine a bunch of
different knowledge to create something
awesome. So the name of the network i'm
just going to call it
"CodeWizard" and it's going to be a
social network for coders. So now I've
already got this here, however i'm going to
open a new finder window and i'm going
to go into PyCharmProjects, and CodeWizard is right here. So this is going to
be the directory that i'm working in so
obviously first I need a main.py
that's going to be the controller. So
let's go ahead and create a Python file, and
I'm actually just going to name it
"Controller" and it'll do the
extension on it's own. So there's
Controller.py. Now what I need to do
is create a couple directories, so the first
directory is going to be called "Models"
and then the next directory
it's going to be called "Views" and this
is where we're going to put all our
models, this is where we're going to put all our views, and each one of these is going
to be able to be imported.
This is going to be essentially its own
file that contains all the top level
code. So let's I don't think actually
that the bootstrap material comes with
bootstrap itself, but I could be wrong.
I believe this is just...yeah, okay.
So what we're going to do is go ahead
and go into bootstrap, going to copy
these files, so copies over and we're
going to go into the CodeWizard project
here, go into actually we need another
directory, actually in Views create
a new directory and call it "Resources"
and i'm going to rename that so it's
actually spelled correctly. Then in here
we're just going to paste these items, so
you should have something that looks
like this,
the main controller file, we're going to
have models here which is empty as of
now, and the views container for right
now is going to hold resources, and
that's going to have these three
directories right here. Let's jump back out of
here and go to the bootstrap material, go into the dist this means this is
the distribution, and we're just going to
copy these two files here, and we're
going to merge them in here. So basically
if we're go into css we shouldn't only
have bootstrap, we should also have the
bootstrap material design. So once we've
got that set up we're good to go.
That's the only css stuff we're going to
be using here, and you'll see it right
there. Now in Views i'm also going to
create a directory called templates. So
we've got that set up. Now let's go ahead
and set up our controller. So i'm already in
here, so "import web" we're going to create our "urls = ( )", again it's a list so the
first one is going to be '/' and it's
going to go to the 'home' page class. So,
here we need to start the
application so "app = web.application"
gotta pass the "(urls, and globals( ))"
Now we're going to define our class so
i'm going to add a comment here, it's going to say
"# Classes/Routes" so essentially these
are each going to be the
controllers, so each class is going to be a
controller for a different route. So here
we need to create a class called home. So
drop down a line "class home:" and i'm
going to "def GET(self): and for right now
we're just going to load up,
we're just going to return a string for
now, so "return "home" "if __name__==" __main__":"
"app.run( )" Let's go ahead and run this file, didn't mean to debug that, it's alright.
"localhost:8080" and we see that our
home is returning that template. So
now let's go ahead, in the next video
we're going to be creating the homes
template, i'm going to do a bit of work
behind the scenes too because, I mean it's
going to be static so I'm just going to
go ahead and create a file here, call it
"home" and now this class right here
is what you're going to be generating
the static homepage, so i'm going to do
that separately.
There's going to be a sign up function
which we're going to be doing in the
next video as well.