Hey guys, welcome back. So between the
last video and this video I've added a
bit of style to make it look a bit
better, hopefully you guys have added at
least a navbar as well. I'm going to go
ahead and show you guys what I've done,
and if you want to pause the video and
do something similar,
go for it.
I just don't want to take up too much
time like doing things that you might
not want to do, so most of the styling
and additional stuff i'm probably going
to do between videos and then we will review it in the next video. So, in each video at
the end I'm going to tell you guys what
you should have ready for the next video,
and you can do that stuff on your own. So
I've created a nav bar &lt;div class="navbar
navbar.info navbar-fixed-top"&gt; "&lt;a class="navbar-brand"&gt;CodeWizard,/a." and then I've
created navigation here, and I've got
"Home Feed" "discover "profile" and "settings"
these are all pages that we are going to
create here, i've also got a button over
here this says "register" Now, the bootstrap material if you haven't used it yet it
comes with his awesome waves affect, and how we use that is just add the
class="waves-effect" to buttons and links and stuff, and it will do that ripple thing
that you see.
However, before we do that we've actually
got to get jquery going and we need to
initialize the JavaScript here for
material, and so what I'm going to do is
go to "jquery.com" and i'm going to
download jquery3.1.0, here it is right
there. I'm going to go back in to static, css going to drag that right over here,
oh, into the javascript file actually,
there we go.
So if i go into the JavaScript we'll see
which javascript files i'm going to have
to include. It's going to be a jquery, and
then bootstrap,
and then material, and also the ripples.
So, we're going to do that similar to the
css files, so "$var static/js/jquery-3.1.0.min.js
static/js/
bootstrap.min.js static/js/material.min.js
static/js/ripples.min.js" Alright, there.
we go. These are the four javascript
files that we we are going to need to
include. It's common practice with jquery
to include it just before the closing
body tag here, so let's go ahead and do
something similar to what we did up here
with the css. So, "$if.js:" we're
going to go "$for
scripts in self.js.split( )" we're
going to split it here, and then we're going
to print out "&lt;script src="$script&lt;&gt;/script&gt;" and we're going
to save it. And then outside of here
we're going to create our own script to
initialize I material. So,
"$.material.init( );" I might have to put that
into a document, i'm not sure. Let's go
ahead and restart this, and we've got an
issue on line 45.
Alright, I think it's because we're using
a dollar sign here and it doesn't know
what that is because we're using jquery,
so we're going to do is we're actually
going to just create our own external
javascript file for use in here, it's going to
make it a lot easier.
So, what I'm going to do is go ahead and
create a new javascript file, and i'm going
to name it "scripty" and I'll
paste this in here. So in MainLayout i'm
going to add that "static/js/
scripty.js so that will get it loaded
into the page on its own. So what we're
going to do now is we've got our
JavaScript included we're going to
create a form, so what we need to do is
in the controller here let's create another
route, and
let's call it '/register', and it's going to
connect to the 'register' class here. So
let's go ahead and define that "class register:" "def GET(self): "return render.Register( )"
Now let's go ahead and create the
"Register" page, and in here i'm just going to
create a form. So, I believe the container
is in the page of the pages themselves.
What I'm going to do is get this out of
here because I don't want to add that to
every page, and i'm just going to paste
it right here, and this basically makes
it where the navbar is floating, it
doesn't, the content doesn't go
underneath it. So, what I'm going to do
is "&lt;div class"container"&gt;" and i'm going to
add a "&lt;h2&gt;Register Account&lt;/h2&gt;" and on this page we are going to need a
few fields of information. So what we're
going to do is we're going to create
some material drop inputs, and as you can see I want this one right here, so
I'm just going to look at this, and it's
just a regular input with the label
static, yeah. It also has a hint there, I
don't know if I like the hint or not, we
could use that though, so. Let's go ahead
and create a username input "&lt;div class=
'form-group label-static"&gt;"
and it's going to be empty by default so
"is-empty" as well "&lt;label for="username"
class="control-label"&gt;Username&lt;/label&gt;"
&lt;input id="username"
class="form-control" type="text" placeholder="Choose a username" /&gt;"
Let's go ahead and save this,
going to rerun the application here,
refresh this, and go to the register page. So as you can see I've got the register
account and it's now starting to ask for
information. So I'm actually going to
drop down a little bit between the title
and that field, going to create another
input for email address
we're going to want that, and then down
here we need a button. So "&lt;button class=
"btn btn-info waves-effect ripple"&gt;Submit &lt;div class=
"ripple-container"&lt;/button&gt;" Go ahead and save this and reload, something
happened there that I don't like, oh "from
group" right there, that's what it was.
Alright, reload here and we'll see it looks
a little better, and a submit button right
there.
Still those ripples are not working. I
will troubleshoot that between now and
the next video and yeah we'll figure
that out. So i'm going to make this into an
actual form just by adding the word "&lt;form&gt;" around it, and I'm going to have to
indent the entire form itself, i'm going
to move over to the JavaScript and
basically the ID for this is going to be
"register-form" and this button is going
to be a "submit" button, there we go.
So that's our HTML. What we're going to
do is come over to scripty here and we're
going to type in "$(document).on("submit", "#register-form",
function( )" and we are going to be sending a ajax request to another route that we
set up, it can accept posted data. So,
let's go ahead and just "console.log("form
submitted")" that's as far as we're going
to take this video here, and I got to
prevent default "e.preventDefault( )", that's right. Refresh and as you can see form submitted and it
prevented the default submit type. So in the next video we're gonna be basically
taking these fields, we're going to be
building a separate route for handling
the data, and we're going to be putting
this into PyManga. So we're also going
to have to build out a PyMongo class
to import.