Welcome back guys. So in the last video I
had some problems being able to tell if
the JavaScript was working or not
because the ripples weren't happening.
Some good news, I've got them to work if
you look at this when I click on stuff
and hold it will it will now ripple,
there's no route there. And so I tried a
few different things, I used this hosted
library of jQuery 1.12 I figured
maybe the 3-series was too new, however that did not end up resolving the issue.
What did end up resolving the issue is
that i did not include the ripples.min.css
and the ripples.min.js. So in the main layout just go ahead and
add the style sheets for the ripples and
the ripples will work if you add the
waves effect right here.
So, with that said, we are going to get
into form submitting in Webpy and
how to do it, so this is really, really
simple but also really, really powerful.
So what we're going to need to do is
build an ajax event here. So i'm going to
create a "var form = $('#register-form').
serialize( );" and then "$.ajax()" and this is basically, again, if you guys haven't done
this that's no worries. I will explain it
briefly as I go.
Ajax is a way to capture the form and
send it over to the server using
javascript so that you don't get a page
refresh and that's exactly what we're
going to be doing here. So, we need to set
the "url:' '" so this is going to be the URL
that we're going to post data too, so
let's name it '/postregistration', the type
is going to be "type: 'POST'," we're going to post data, the data is going to "data: form,"
that we're sending, and then on success
we're just going to "success: function(response)"
in the success function, and we're going
to "console.log(response)" So that's
literally all we need to do for that. I'm
going to remove that console.log up
there, going to save this, still not
going to work because we haven't
actually created this route. So, this is
the Webpy stuff right here. Let's go
over to controller, let's create the route, so
'/postregistration', 'PostRegistration'
and yeah these
classes should be using capitals as per
PEP guidelines, so I'm just going to go
through and fix those really quickly as
well, and then we're going to define a
new class here called "class PostRegistration:" and now when we define the main function
it's not going to be get, it's going to be
"POST(self):" So, there's a few ways to capture
the data that we get, the one that we're
going to be looking at is called an
input method and it's going to get all
the posted data. Now alternatively if
you put it into a get function it's going to
get all the get data and get data is in
the URL, but post data does not go in the
URL it gets submitted behind the scenes
sort of. So in order to get the data I'm going to create a variable here called "data
= web.input( )" it's
really that simple, and then i'm going to
return the username from this so, "return data.username"
it's really that simple. So basically
when I run this script now, let's go
through it,
stop the script from running, start it again,
we're going to refresh. The username i'm
going to choose is "nick" and full name is
just "Nick" for now. I'm actually not going
to fill anything else but i'm going to
hit submit, and what you see is that it
accesses the back end, and what
happens is we get the form
data, we send an ajax request over to
this route. So it's coming here at that
point, it's going into that class, and it's
setting the data within web input
method, and then we can access this like
any other object and get each field by
the name of the input. So, that's awesome,
and that's how we're going to be getting
the data to then put it into PyMongo,
and so in the next video we're setting up
our first model.