Hey guys, welcome back. In this video
we're going to start with our models and
so we need to create a register model in
order to register, and also grab data from
the database. So in Models here I've
created an __init__.py to make any file
that we create in here callable and able
to import, and i'm going to go ahead and
create a Python file and we're going to
name it
"RegisterModel" and then in this file i'm
going to create a "class RegisterModel""
same as the filename. And then for
now I'm just going to define a function
called "def insert_user, data):" and we're going to "print("data is",  data)"
So we're going to use this,
actually let's "import pymongo" here
right now "from pymongo import MongoClient" Alright, now in our controller
we're now going to import our register
model, so "from Models import RegisterModel.RegisterModel"
and the reason we're in actually we can't do
that there, okay, you'll see why I tried
to that there. So, we need to, this is
going to include the file but not
necessarily the class from this file
when we instantiate it. so what we need
to do is create our registration model,
so "reg_model =RegisterModel( )" and
we can't just call that directly, it's not
going to work.
It's not callable because this is the
name of the file this isn't the class
within the file, so we need to add the
file name "RegisterModel." and then the the name of the
class we're going to import which is
right here. So that's how we're going to
call it, and then what we're going to do
we're just going to pass
the data directly into that function and
this function is going to print out that
data. So, "reg_model.insert_user(data)"
So let's save
this, let's stop this, and then restart it.
Go ahead and refresh, and now i'm going
to enter username "nick" "Nick Germaine" and then my
email and password right there. Going to hit submit and we see that it has accessed
that because that function has finished,
and now you'll see that the register
model is getting that data. So what we're
going to do in the register model right
there we're going to, we're going to
initialize the class so "def __init__(self):"
and what we're going to do we're going
to set "self.client = MongoClient( )"
"selfdb" = self.client." let me check what I
need the database here. You can up open
up Robomongo, right click on the
connection, and click create database
that's what i've done so i've already
created codewizard here, and then "self.Users =
self.db.users" So, as soon as the
register model is instantiated it's
going to have these variables
associated with the top level, and then I
can use it in insert user here.
So what we're going to do we're going to
go ahead and insert the data. Now, I'm
able to access each one of these by
basically just accessing the
the keyword in there for it, so what
we're going to do is we're going to go
ahead and say "id = self.Users.insert()" and here's where we're going to
pass in the data. So, "username: data.username, "name":
data.name, "password": data.password, "email": data.email
and then what we're going to print down
here is "print("uid
is", id)"
Let's go ahead and save this, we're going
to restart the server here, going to
refresh this, choose a username, and a
password.
Going to go ahead and hit submit, and we'll see that we do have a username. So it's just
like using regular PyMongo at the
at that point we can open the
collections and we can see our user
right here. So, that's how we just
connected the registration model to a
back end PyMongo client, and what we're
going to be doing in the next video is
we're going to be talking about sessions
and how we can allow a user to log in by
username and password.