Alright guys, welcome back. In the last
video we learned about how to register our
user, but we didn't register our user
properly and that's because we are
storing it in Mongo using an unhashed
password. So basically it's stored as plain
text in the database and that's just bad.
So what we're going to do, we're going to
rework our script a little bit and we're
going to encrypt our password, and then
put the password in in the encrypted
form, and then what we're going to do is
learn how to match passwords and check
if they match. So to do this,
new window, we need to install something so go ahead
and type pip3 install...alright, let me try that again. Type "pip3 install bcrypt"
I already got it installed. It's going to
install a few other packages, once you
get it installed just close the terminal. Now we're going to "import bcrypt" here. Going
to create a variable called "hashed = bcrypt.hashpw
(data.password.encode( ), )"
and then we're going to generate
some salt. So salt is what encrypts,
it's the algorithm that it encrypts
with. So "bcrypt.gensalt" and that's
really all we need to do. So now this
creates a hashed version of the password
and that's the password that we're going
to store in the password field. So what
we're going to do is we're going to
immediately after this we're going to
then also check the password, check
if the password matches a specific
password. We're just going to check it,
and i'll explain things in a moment,
so "if
bcrypt .checkpw( )" and this function is
going to take the first item of
plaintext so we're going to set "avocado1"
and of course we need to ".encode( )" that
first, and then the second parameter is
going to be the existing hashed password.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
get the user here, so "myuser =
self.Users.find_one( )" and it's going to
be based on the the ID. So find one where
the ID is equal to...actually let's just
search by username. "{"username":
data.username}" and what
we're going to do is we're going to use
that second password through "myuser["password]" So, if bcrypt the check
password method, and we're passing in two items here, the first one is the password
we want to see if it matches the
existing one, and the second one is going
to be the existing password which we are
pulling out of the database. So, if it's
correct we want to "print("this matches")" So let's go ahead and run the controller
here, no socket could be created, address
is already in use.
Oh, I'm already running it here, let me end
that one, there we go. Start this, refresh
this, do I have anything in Mongo? No, I do not.
Alright, we're going to create a user
and my password is going to be the same
one that I used over here,
avocado1. So i'm going to copy and
paste it just to make sure I put it in
correctly and we get the desired output.
So hit submit, it's going to say nick1 here, but
if we come back over here you're going
to see that it matches, and this
basically means that this is the
type of a check we're going to do when a
user logs in.
We're going to get the username objects
or the users object based on the
username they put in or email, and we're
going to hash the password they put in
and check it against the existing hashed
password. And if we open up Mongo and
refresh you're going to see this time
we've got a binary password in here, and
if we go ahead and edit the document,
this if someone ever did get into your
database and they saw this they
wouldn't know what it means, and so
that's why
it's a lot more secure than storing plain text in the database.
So in the next video we're actually
going to create that login script, and
use a similar function to this right
here.