Hey guys, welcome back. We're not going to get to sessions right away, the first
thing we're going to do is just build
out the outworking login system, and so
this is probably gonna be a really quick
video. What we need to do in templates
create a new file called "Login" and then
in here
&lt;div class="container" and then we're going to create a "&lt;form id="login-form"&gt;" "&lt;/form&gt;"
and above that form we're going to use
an "&lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;" and we're just going to
say "Login" and in the Register form I did
put a couple line breaks here after the
h2 element, so I'm going to do the same
thing here in this file. Now we're going
to be using the same things we have here,
so what I'm going to do is I'm just
going to copy one of these to make
things a bit faster for us, and I'm just
going to go like this and then that. So
the first one is going to be "username"
and the second one is going to be
"password"
and this actually has made things a lot
faster here, and then down
at the very bottom we're just going to
create a "&lt;button class=
"btn btn-raised btn-info waves-effect"&gt;Login&lt;/button&gt;" Go ahead and save this, and
then in the controller file we actually
need to add a route here that it's going
to be a get route, and it's going to say,
and actually I need to add two lines
between classes which I haven't done so
far. So, "class Login:" "def GET(self):" and we're just going
to "return render.Login( )" The path to
the login page is simply going to be
'/login', 'Login', and there we go.
So if we save this we now need to edit
the MainLayout to have a link right
beside here which is going to be similar
but it's going to be a login, and that ones
actually going to be in front of the
register. So, this is going to be a regular
link, but I do want the button and "btn-link" It's going to be called Login and
it's going to route to the "login" route.
Let's go ahead and save that, run our script again, let's go ahead and refresh the
page here, now you can see we've also got a login link. We've got the register
button and a login link. When we
go to this route we get presented with
our username and password,
and then we're going to have to do
essentially the same thing that we did
with a register form. So we need to go
into the javascript file here which is
called scripty, and essentially we're
going to do the same thing but with the
login form. So, "$(document).on('submit', '#login-form',
function(e))" I cannot type
today,
that's unusual. Going to "e.preventDefault( );" and then we're going to capture
the form "var form = $(this).serialize"  we can actually use this variable here, and the reason we can use
that is because we are targeting the
form element itself, so when that submits
inside of this that is equal to that. So,
then we're going to create our "$.ajax("
"url: '/check-login',"  the "type: 'POST', " "data:
form," and then "success: function(res){" we are going to do something if they successfully login, but
if they don't we're also going to do
something. So, what we're going to do is
create an if statement and the only
thing we're going to return is error. So,
"if(res == "error"){" now we're just going
to "alert("Could not log in.");}" "else{" and then
here we would handle a redirect and
whatnot so "console.log("Logged in as", res ");"
So basically what we need to do
here is we need to make the response
from the check login either just the
word error, or the object of maybe the
login user and we will redirect to
another page based on that. So now we
need to create the check
login model. So let's go ahead and create
a "LoginModel" 'check-login',  is going to
connect to 'CheckLogin' class, and then
we just need to create the check log in
class. So "class CheckLogin:" "def POST(self):" and what
we're going to do is essentially the
same thing we're doing up here and then
we're going to do some stuff in the
model. So, "data = web.input( )" login
model equals, actually "login =
LoginModel.LoginModel( )" same as with the registration model, and then "login.
check_user(data)" and then we're going to for now
we're going to just "return "error" and
we're going to be building out the login
model and then we'll get to that in a
moment.
So in Models here create a new Python
file called LoginModel, and then create
a "class LoginModel:" Now, we need
to import PyMongo, so "import pymongo,
bcrypt" and "from pymongo import
MongoClient" and actually maybe as we go
on I will put that into a script
on its own so maybe we don't always have to connect to the Mongo database. So,
here
similar to the registration here we're
going to copy this actually because it's
going to be the exact same, and then for
insert user and you know we're just
going to replace that with "def check_login(self, data):" and I believe that's what
we called it over here in the controller,
"check_user" it was. So let's go ahead and
get the user account from Mongo, so in
order to do that we're just going to
type "user = Users.find_one()"
Now, "if user:" we're going to check the
password, so what we need to do is get
the users password, as well as the
password that they had...the password that
they have stored into the database.
So, let's go ahead and just do the check,
I guess. So, "if bcrypt.checkpw(data.password.
encode( ), user["password"])" So if the check password
is correct we're going to return the entire
user object. So, "return user" "else:" "return "error"
there we go. So how we're going to
check that in, actually let's make that
"False" So if a user and if it's correct
we're going to return user, "else:" we're
going to "return False" here as well. Back
in our controller we can check that now.
So, "isCorrect" is going to be either the
object or false.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to say "if isCorrect:" "return isCorrect"
Let's go ahead and save this, end this,
and start it again. Now I need to check if I
need to add a user and I don't, so I
should just be able to login with the
username nick1. So let's go ahead and
refresh this, going to login with "nick1"
and "avocado1" and you'll see that
this is it logged in as and then the
user that I've logged in as. Now if I
were to type in the wrong password, it
would say could not login, so we've
actually got a working script here that
will login. We will be able to set sessions
is in the next video, essentially we're
going to learn about cookies and
sessions and stuff, and then we are going
to basically just enable it right there.
If is correct we're going to start a
session and pass that data back to here.
So thank you guys for watching and I
will see you guys soon.