Hey guys, so the last section of videos
we learned about how to get data and
HTML from the internet using Python, but
we haven't really learned how to do
anything fun with it yet, and so that's
what we're going to be getting to now by
discovering a package called beautiful
soup. So, I believe it's bs4 that we
need to install, so go ahead and open up
terminal and type "pip3 install ps4" and once
it installs we should be able to just
use it right away just like any other
package.
Let's go ahead and close terminal, open
up PyCharm here, let's just go ahead
and start a new project it's going to be
pure Python, let's get rid of that, and we're going to
name it web scraperery. So basically
when you get data from the internet it's
called web scraping, so this module is
going to really help you guys do web
scraping tasks. So, the way we do that is
using beautiful soup so let's go ahead
and create a new file, just name it
"main" let's write "from bs4
import BeautifulSoup" that's all you
need to do. Now we're gonna have to also
use requests in order to get the data,
and then once we get the data we're
going to convert it into a beautiful
soup, and then we're going to parse that
beautiful soup and do different stuff
with the content that would get. So let's
also go ahead "import requests" So let's
build a request here, and what we're
going to do is we're going to go to
Bing because Bing is a search engine
that we can search quite easily, and
let's search for
pizza. What we need from here is just
the URL right here.
So what we're going to do is we are
going to send a get parameter, so let's
build up params object "params = "
we haven't built that yet, but just one sec, so we're going to set the
URL to this "(http://www.bing.com/search", params=params)" Then the search variable is going to
actually, we need to ask what we want to search for, so this is
going to be kind of an interactive program.So let's go ahead and "print("Enter Search Term:")"
actually let's just make this input,
so let's go ahead and create a search
variable "search = input("Enter search term:")"
So what's going to happen is the first thing it's going to ask is what we want search
for, we're going to get that, we're going
to send it along as the q get
variable in parameters to this URL, and
we'll get the results from the page of
what we searched for. So now that we have that we are then going to turn it a
beautiful soup. so let's go ahead and
create a variable called "soup =
BeautifulSoup" and what we're going to
pass into this class beautiful soup is
going to be the actual text of the document. So, it should just be
"(r.text)" and then we can "print(soup.prettify( ))"
Let's go ahead and save, let's run this. So we want to search for "pizza." So it did get
it, it let me scroll up, Bing has a lot
of code in their pages. So, there. No parser
was explicitly specified, so using the
best HTML parser for the system which is
HTML parser. Now we could manually pass that into the beautiful soup if we, it says
right here if we in the the beautiful
soup call what we can do is just pass
that in as well "html.parser" We won't get that error but then happened was we got the results,
and we printed out a prettified version
of the soup that we just made. So, what we
can do with this is we can actually find
certain contents from within the soup
and use that, and that's what we're going to do in the next video.