So in the last video we learned about
how to make some soup, and in this video
we're going to be learning about how to
get into that soup and get stuff out of
it. So let's go ahead and type "from bs4
import  BeautifulSoup" and "import requests"
So, as in the previous video we're going
to create a search variable which is
going to be "search = input("Search for:")"
let the user search for something. Going
to build the params object which is going to be "params = " and the search results
so again this is going to send the get
variable of q equal to whatever we
search for along with URL. Then we're
going to create a request, so "r = requests
.get("http://www.bing.com/search, params=params)"
So there we've got our requests sent now let's build the
soup,
so to do this you create a variable and
call the "soup = BeautifulSoup class" we're
going to pass it in the "(r.text, )" that we get
back we're going to be the actual HTML
content, and we're going to use the "html.parser" Now this should default to the
html.parser but
we don't want to see that little warning
message there so we're going to specify that anyway.
Now, what we need to do is get the
results of this page, so i've loaded up an
example search on the bing.com website to see kind of what we're going to need to
parse through. So as you can see here as
I highlight over each thing it's going
to highlight what we're looking at, so
what we're going to need to do is first
we need to get the list of results, so
we're going to need to get an ordered
list with an ID of the results. How to
do that is using the find property or
method from the soup. So we're going to
create a variable called
"results = soup.find" and here the first
thing that we're going to pass into this
function is going to be the element
we're looking for ("ol", ) then we're also going
to pass a dictionary object of any
attributes that we're going to look for.
So for this instance we're going to be
looking for an ""
then we can get the results loaded up
into a variable. What we can do there is
we are going to look for each list item
with a class of b_algo and the reason we're
doing that is because some list items
have the list or the class of b_ad, and
basically those structures are different and we don't really want the ads, we don't want
any of this information on the side
either like they've got wikipedia
information, and a map &amp; stuff, we just
want search results here. Let's go ahead
and we're going to use a different
method here. So we're going to create a links variable what is
going to be equal to the results to
find all list items with a class equal
to that "links = results.findAll("li", )" So notice the capital A right here, essentially the parameters
we're passing into the method is exactly the same as the parameters we're passing into
this one, so they work the same way.
You could also if you're looking for a
very specific href attribute you can
change that to href, then whatever
you're looking for.
So once we've got the links built what
we're going to do is we're gonna put it
in a for statement. So "for item in links:"
and we're gonna have to get two things out of this,
we're gonna have to get the text of the
a element, and then also the href property.
So how we do that is first for the text
of any element it's really simple type
"item_text = item.find("a").text"
So we get the text of that a element,
and then "item_href = item.find("a").attrs" and here we're
going to use a variable property called
attrs for attributes, and this is a list
so we put square brackets there and then
find whatever attribute of this specific
element we're looking for going to be "["href"]" So what we're going to do here we
need to make sure there's both text and
a href for this to work, so let's put it
in an if statement. "if item_text and item_href:" we're basically going to
print about. So "print(item_text)" underneath "print(item_href)"
Let's go ahead and save this, we'll run it once, then we will look back over it. I'll try to
explain more in depth. So its first going
to ask what we want to search for of
course we're going to search for pizza,
and we search that we see the first
page of results which has the links here
as well. So I could click on that and it will load up
Dominos Pizza's website. So, basically,
let's go over this again. We need to import
requests in beautifulsoup, we allow the user to input whatever text that they're
looking for, and then we're going to put that to a search variable that we're going to
stuff into the params object which is
going to make the get variable q equal
to the search, and this basically means that it's going to tell the URL that it needs
to append this part onto it. Then we're
going to create the request,
here's the URL, this is the parameters
that were passing in. Once we get the
request object we're able to access the
content of the HTML from r.text, so
we need to build soup so that we can
actually parse through it. So we set a
soup variable equal to the beautiful
soup class, and what we're passing into
that is both the content and the parser
that we want to use. Now the default
parser is going to be the HTML parser,
but if you just leave it up to the
default it's going to print out a
warning and it's not going to look as
nice, so we specify it here.
Once we've got the soup equal to the
entire webpage, essentially, we're going
to create another variable called
results and we're going to search
through the soup for the first instance
of an ordered list with an ID of
b_results. So again this is going to be the
element you're looking for and this list
is going to contain any attributes
you're looking for, and then from within
the results we can use the find all
method, and we're going to pass it the
elements were looking for within the results, and then the class attribute that we're
looking for. So this is going to find all
list items with the class of b_algo
and store them in a list called links.
Then what we do it's basic stuff,
we create a for statement for items and
links, we're going to create the text, and
href, and how you get the text of
any element is just by targeting the
element and then putting the text
property there, and then if you want a
specific attribute from an element you
use the attrs and then in this list
item you need to type what you want, what attribute you're looking for, and
then we just print it out. So as you can
see this is very powerful stuff and we
can actually we could target the bottom
links right here, and we could also grab
the results from the second page as well
if we wanted to. We would most likely
want to create a recursive function for
that which we might do in the next video,
but we are going to be doing some more
stuff and parsing with beautiful soup. So
thank you guys for watching.