Alright guys, so in the last video we
learned about navigating downwards
through the domain of an HTML webpage in order to parse it using beautiful soup, and we're
going to continue with beautiful soup
for a while because there's a lot of
little things that you should know in
order to properly navigate web pages.
So what we're going to talk about first
is parent parsing, you can actually
find the parent of an element, as well as
children. So let's go ahead and if we
have a look here each list item we're
targeting and then we're finding the "a"
element in it, so it's going to go look
at the "li" or the the list item and
then it's going to come down here and
find the "a" element, but the parent of the "a"
element is an h2, so what we should be
able to do here is print out the item's
h2 element as well. Let's go ahead and
"print("Parent:". item.find("a").parent)"
"print("Parent:". item.find("a").parent)"t I'm going to go ahead
and save that and then run it.
We're going to search for "pizza" string
object has no attribute item,
oops, need a comma there not a period. So, there we go.After each entry it has the parents
which contains all this, we could parse
through that if we wanted to.
Now, additionally, each item should have a description, i'm just going to check on
this right here, if
I inspect the element here it looks like
the "&lt;p&gt;" we should just be able to
target each, well the "b_caption" and then
the "&lt;p&gt;" of it. So let's go ahead and do
that.
So this is to get, this is just a little
more parsing on the children, so let's print
out "summary" We're going to need to go
back one more ".parent"
and then we're going to ".find("p").text)" from it so let's go ahead
and save this and run it.
We're going to search for "pizza" again,
we're just using this example as we go.
So as you can see we actually now are
printing out the summary for each for,
each item as well, and that's through
targeting the "a" element which is right
here, and we're targeting the parent and the parents so we're actually going back up to
that list item, and then we're finding
the "p" element and printing that out.
So that's how to use parent to navigate
as well. You can also find children of
each item. So, let's just "children = item.children" and this is going
to compile a list of all children
elements of that list item, and to give
you an example we should see two. So
there's going to be an h2 element and
then a div element. Same for here,
there's going to be a h2 and then div.
So it's not gonna add a list with and h2
then an "a" element, a div, and another
div, etc., it's just going to add two items
because those are the two direct
children of this item. So, "for child in
children:"
let's just print out the child, so "print("Child:", child)" and this here so we can see
exactly what children are going to be
printed. So let's save that and run it again,
and we search for "pizza" and as you can
see this one actually has four children
it looks like, but most of them have two,
just the h2 and the div, and then we
could also parse through each one of
those as well, however what we can do is we
can find the next sibling of an item. And
so what we're going to do here we're
going to target the first child, so
the first child in that list "[0]" and then
what we're going to do is print out,
should be the div element, print("Next Sibling of the h2:", children.next_sibling)"
And if I run this now again, we're going to put in our search term, list_iterator
object is not subscriptable. Ok, so what we actually have to do is let's just find
the h2 "item.find("h2")"
Alright, let's run this again, and here we
can see the next child, or the next
sibling and you can also use previous
sibling as well. So if we wanted to
target that and do previous sibling it would find the sibling just before the div, and
the sibling just before the div is the
h2 element. So that's how you compare
sideways through documents as well.