Hey guys, welcome back. In the last video
we learned about some directional
navigation through some soup, and in this
video we're going to be combining a few
of the things we've learned already to
do something really neat. So, i'm going to
go ahead and create a new Python file
called "images" and we're going to
import beautifulsoup, requests, pillow, and
we're going to import the bytesIO.
So let's go ahead and from, why can I
not type in here?
Well, something happened to my keyboard, still working,
it's messed up. Let me close this and try
and open it again,
there we go. Don't know what that was but anyway let's jump into images.py. From
"from bs4 import Beautifulsoup, going to "import requests" "from PIL import Image"
and then "from io import BytesIO"
So let's go ahead and get, let's get
a variable created called "search" so
this is going to be another
interactive one. So "= input("search for:")"
and then we need to build the "params = " so
whatever we type in, then we're going to
create a request.
So "r = requests.get
("https://www.bing.com/images/search"), params=params)"
So if you guys didn't notice yet what we're
going to do is we're going to be saving
images from Bing based on our search,
yeah, so let's go ahead and do that.
So what we need to do is turn our page
that we've just searched for into some
soup.
So, "soup = BeautifulSoup(r.text, "html.parser")"
Now what we need to do is grab each
image. So I've looked through here
already and I found that each image is
stored in an "a" element, where is that it,
and it has a class of thumb.
I'm not sure if it's going to show that
here because it shows all this
stuff, but this is all generated by
JavaScript after. So, basically the
properties you see here won't be what
you get back. What you get back is an "a"
element with a class of thumb, and then
the URL, the href of the element is
equal to the actual location of the file.
So, I've already got that
information now this looks a bit
different. So how we will do that is we will
create a variable called "links = soup.findAll" going
find all a attributes or elements with the class of thumb ("a", )" Then basically we're
going to go "for item in links:" What we
need to do is we need to actually get, we
need to create a new request for each
item's URL, so we're going to go ahead
and print img_url, this is going to be our
variable, or let's just type
"img_obj = requests.get"
and then in here we're going to pass
in the "(item.attrs["href"])" So this is
going to get the file in a format
that we can read, now we couldn't just
pass it the href element into an image.open call, it just wouldn't work. So
we're also going to get the title of the
image. How we're going to do this,
let's just type "title" that's going to be
our variable. We're gonna get the "= item"
we're gonna get the ".attrs["href"]" and then what we're going to do
because I guess with the image library
there's not an easy way to get a title
of a file name, what we're going to do is
we're just going to split at the last "/"
so anything after the last "/" is going to
be the filename. So as you can see here
"/" would be the the actual
file name. So let's go ahead and split this,
".split("/")" and then to
get the last element in a list in Python
you go "[-1]" in the index box there.
So that's going to be the title that
we're going to be using to save the
image, so let's go ahead and create our
image. So, img "Image.open(BytesIO)" and then we're
going to pass it in "(img_obj.content))" So there's our image we have it open,
we're now going to save the image to an
images directory. So i'm going to go
ahead and create a new directory, and i'm
going to call it,
let's call it "scraped_images" so we're going to use that here. So we're going to
go ahead and save the image here, so I "img.save" and then we're going to save to the
current directory "("./scraped_images/" + title, )"
to save it, so it's going to
saved in that directory with its
original title or filename, and then
we're just going to type "img.format)"
and that's it.
So let's go ahead and start this up, see
if it all works as it should. So here
we're going to search for "pizza"
and I forgot to put some print statements
into their to see what it's doing, but
let's just jump in here and as you can
see images are being generated and
saved to the computer with their
original file names. Now this will go
forever because i'm pretty sure Bing has,
well it'll go that far,
so past the first load it won't pick up
anything because we're not actually
scrolling down the page which Bing you
know checks for if you scroll a certain
amount but we're not going to be
scrolling certain amount because we just
pulled the dom from the internet, so I
think this is all it's going to save,
actually, but it didn't stop yet so I
think so it's going to save a few more.
Can't identify image, awesome. So,
that's how to save images and we could
do that for, let's put a print
statement in here, i'm just going to
print out the URL's. So print("Getting", item .attrs["href"])"
print("Getting", item .attrs["href"])"
So for each item that it has saved it's
going to then print that. So let's go ahead
and start this again and I'm going to
search for "Skyrim wallpaper"
Let's just say I want to scrape a bunch
of wallpapers off of the internet, it's
going to do that. So if we come back over
here we're going to see that i'm going
to start getting a folder full of Skyrim
wallpapers, and what we could do actually is
you could extend this further to for
each time you search for something,
instead of storing everything in the
scraped images, you could actually get the
search term create a directory called
whatever search term was, and then save all
images by filename into the appropriate
directory. But, that's as far as we're
going to take this one.
Thank you guys for watching, and I'll see
you guys in the next video.