Alright guys, so we actually are going to
take this specific example a little bit
further, we're going to make a few
improvements to it. So one of the
improvements is going to be we're going
to be able to loop through this, so once
it's done saving all the images from our
first search, it will prompt us for
another search. So, that's improvement
number one and then improvement number
two is going to be to get a directory
made for each search term, and then it
will save it into the appropriate
directory here. So, let's start with
making this loopable, what we're going to
do is we're going to run
"def StartSearch( ):" and then we're just going to indent all of this. And then down here at
the end of the function we're going to
call it again "StartSearch( )" And then initially when we
start the program we're going to need
to call it one more time "StartSearch( )" So this in and
of itself should make this loopable, so
let's go ahead and run it.
We're going to search for "Epic
Wallpapers" and we're going to see that
it's going to run through a bunch of
these and it's going to save them still
into the scraped_images
directory, and actually one of the images
that I scraped last time I've never
seen it before and I was looking through
them, and I'm like okay well I'm going to
use this as a wallpaper. So that's pretty
neat you could easily fill up a wallpaper
folder with anything that you're
interested in.
So let's go back over to the program here
and see how it's doing.
I'm not sure how many images it's going
to get but it is going to get quite a few, and
then once it's all done it's going to
loop through and ask us if we want to
search for anything else.
This probably was a bad example to use as a looping example because it's going to
take a little while to get all those
images. I think when you do an image
search,
ok, so it actually got stuck on one of
the images. We could do a try,
where is this error coming from? Line 24 and line 19 so it's coming at this so we can
split it right there and let's try
except. So "try:" "except:" "print("Could not save
image.")" That would have looped if it
didn't get that error and if we waited
long enough. Now that we've got that
taken care of the what we're going to do
is we're going to get the search term,
we're going to create a directory if it
doesn't exist,
so what we need to do is "import os" the
OS package. What we're going to do is
we're going to create a "dir_name = search.replace"
all spaces with underscores "(" ", "_")" and we're also going to make it all lowercase ", lower( )"
and right up here we're going to say "if not
os.path.isdir" going to pass
the function "(dir_name):"  as an argument there,
so basically what that means is if this
directory name is not a directory then
we're going to do this. So we're going to
"os.makedirs( )"
wow I cannot take today, and then we're
going to make it "(dir_name)" right there,
and then down here what we're going to do is we're going to
delete this, concatenate it with the
directory name "+ dir_name" So, let's go ahead and
start this again and we should be able
to i'm just going to search for "small
images" because they should be smaller,
there we go. Seems to be going quite a
bit faster here. If we go back here we
should see that all the images are now
going to this directory, and then we
started another search it's going to,
it's going to save in to the next search
terms directory. Let's see, I think there's
there's actually quite a few images on
the first go without getting to
the bottom there, there might be like 50
or so. Let's go back and see if we can get
that all right, what's this? Too many
redirects. So this is happening at the
request, so we're going to have to put
that into a try as well. "try:" that
"except" going to print out "print("Could not request
Image")" Let's try and get an example of
this happening one more time. So, "kitten"
I could print out the number of, we would be able to run the len command
on the links here we could be able to
tell how many links are in this list
that it creates. So as you can see now let's drop down to the bottom and is now
asking us to search again, so that's an
example of it looping, and for this
instance I'm going to just end it here.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you
guys in the next video.