Alright guys, welcome back. So we are done with the Webpy subsection of section 5,
and that was pretty big, was bigger than
I initially expected. And so with that
being as big as it was, I think right at
this point we're at about almost seven hours
into the course, something like that. So,
judging by how big that
module was itself, and I think that was
about an hour and a half or two hours
just on webpy, I think the entire course
is going to be pretty big, so I hope you
guys are happy with that.
Also, we are taking suggestions if you
guys want any other modules, or Python
packages, or maybe even concepts if I
don't explain something that you want to
learn
let me know and we can see about doing that. I'm completely open to adding as much as you
guys want into this course. So right now
we're going to be covering the Django
module in Python, and what we need to do is actually go ahead and install
Django. So to do this type "pip3
install Django" with a capital "D." I've
already got this installed so you're
going to see this message here telling
me that i've already got it installed.
It should install pretty quickly for you
guys, just wait until it's done, and
then what you're going to do is if you
do have PyCharm installed, and I hope you
guys do just because it's going to make
things a lot easier when i'm doing stuff
that you guys can do exactly what I'm
doing, going to change into the
"cd PycharmProjects" directory, and here we are actually going to use Django admin. So,
you guys should have access to this command now that you've got Django
installed, so run "django-admin startproject" and then we're going to name the
project so i'm going to name it "mysite"
Now if you run the "ls" command you'll see
that it's created a new directory here
called mysite, so let's change into my
site "cd mysite" and let's list.
I'm going to go ahead and open PyCharm actually, and i'm going to open that directory an
we're gonna have a look here at what
we've got.
So by the default
Django has created some applications, well some files, for us. We will get into the manage.py
in a moment, first we're
going to go over these files here and go
over what they are.
This is a blank file. You guys know why
there's a blank file titled __init__, you
should if you don't recall basically
that lets us load any files in this
directory into other Python packages as
a package. The settings file is going to
contain specific configurations for the
Django project. It includes installed apps
and what and app is, the difference between a project and app in Django, is let's say we're
about to build Facebook. The project
would be Facebook, but then there would be
multiple apps existing inside the
project as well. So an app might be the
messages, or you know status updates,
comments, maybe groups, etc., so each
kind of component is its own app and it
keeps it separate, keeps it clean, so
that's why we do that. The urls is regex
based so if you guys don't feel you're
that strong regex, and I know i'm not,
i'm doing my best to get better at it
but it just, I mean it's simple, I
just never use it. So, yeah, I
don't generally create web applications
with Python, so that's why you know in
Python regex is really useful for
that kind of stuff and I've used it a
little bit before in
javascript when I need it, but the use
doesn't really come up that often with a
need for it. So, and the wsgi file its
going to allow you to run let's say
Apache, the Apache server, and then run
this application or this project on that
server, so that's what those files are for.
Now the manage.py file, let's open this, you
guys don't need to do anything in here,
we're actually going to leave this
entirely alone, but this is what it looks
like. This lets us run specific commands
to manage your project as you can guess
it's called manage.
So what we're gonna do I'm gonna go
ahead open terminal here, and what we're
going to do, I am in this directory, so
run "python3 ./manage.py" and then it's
going to take an argument and the
argument is going to define what we're
going to do. So, for instance, you can sync up the database again, you can create the
database, and what we're going to do
right now is just type "runserver" and
that's all one word, and this is going to
run the web server. You'll see this
message, we're not going to worry about
that right now, we're just going to copy
this right here, we're going to go into
our browser and paste that in, and you
should see this page. We haven't done
anything yet and so you see this message
and in the next video we're going to
start doing stuff with Django.
If you already have something running on
port 8000, thats cool, because what we
can do, cancel that, when you run the
server you can specify the IP address
and port that you want to run on.
So for instance i'm going to run "python3 ./manage.py runserver 4500" Now if
I wanted to run it on port 4500 I would
do that, and as you can see it's running
on port 4500 and I would access it on that port in my browser. So, thank you guys for
watching this video. You should be set up
with Django and we should be able to
move on and actually do stuff in Django,
and remember this is based on top of the
Python language, it's built on Python,
however a lot of the stuff here is not
just standard you know custom a Python
that you're going to be writing. It's
going to be Django specific code and so
that's why we need to do this, so let's
get started.