Welcome back guys. Now this isn't
entirely efficient in terms of our
structure because if we use exactly what
we've got here and we wanted a nav bar
on every single page, we would have to copy and
paste it on every single page, and so
in this video we're going to talk about
template inheritance and what that means.
And so basically what we want is a main
layout that includes a navbar and maybe
a footer, you know things that are going
to be on every page, and then we want to
be able to load child templates in there.
So, each page, each individual page
that has different content, would be a
different child template. And so in our
templates right here we need to create a
HTML file and we're going to call it
base.HTML.
This is going to be the base template of
our entire site. So let's go ahead and
give it a title. What I've called
this project is my site and I'm going to follow suit
and call it my site in there. Now here's an
interesting thing we're actually just
going to add a nav bar right here, so div
class nav bar, default nav bar, static,
top. We're going to go ahead and, actually
I'm just going to copy a default
bootstrap navbar. So, getbootstrap.com,
go to getting started, and I
actually want to copy the entire head,
actually just these three meta tags
right here, it's going to be important to
copy these right there,
and then the nav bar itself I'm just
going to go to components, click navbar,
and I'm going to copy just a simple navbar.
Well, I'm going to copy this I guess
then I will strip some things out that we
don't need. So, copy that, stuff that right
here, and now we don't...let me indent this
a little better.
Oh, so, bootstrap indents two spaces in
their examples and my code generally
indents four so that's going to be fun. Up
here I'm going to type my site.
This is the regular navbar so what I'm
going to do is I'm just going to remove
the search here at the top and the
right navbar links, and I'm just going
to make this say home,
random post, and it's going to link to
the homepage. This is going to link
nowhere for now, we're going to create
that. This is going to be my profile, and
then settings.
It's that indentation already getting to me.
Alright, so, let me save this. This is
going to be our base HTML but we haven't
actually used it all yet, so what
we need to do is we need to add in the
main part of the body where we want the
content to be dynamic we need to add a
basically a block and we're going to go
over this more in depth. First, what we need
to do is add a div with an id of content,
and once we've got that added we're
going to go ahead and open tag and
the tag is going to be block, and it's
going to be called content. And then
we're going to end block right there. Now
we're not going to define anything in here
just yet,
what we're going to do this is going to
be, this is going to allow us to define
block content in a child template and it
will replace everything that we put in
here, and if the block content is not
defined whatever we put right here is
going to be shown. So what I want to do
actually I want to show you that. This is a
fallback text. Let's go ahead and save
this. Now what we need to do is we need
to, we need to create a template that
inherits from this, and in here actually
I've got to add the bootstrap stuff and
our static stuff so let me go ahead and
copy this and delete it, and in base
right here we're going to be putting
that stuff.
Let's go ahead and indent properly and now
in our index file here what we're going
to do is at the very top here we're
going to add a tag and it's going to say
extends, and then whatever HTML file we
want to extend from. So in this case its
base.HTML.
Now if I save this,
and reload this, we go to our page and
refresh, you'll see that now I've got
that nav bar, but my content from the
index page isn't shown there. The
reason for that is very simple it's
because it doesn't know what to do with
any of this it loads the template and then
it's like okay well I don't know what to
do with all this so I'm just going to
show the template, and that's where this
block content comes in. If we define this
in in here in the child template that
that section, that block, is going to
become whatever the child template is
defined as. So let's go ahead and define
block content right here, and then we're
going to close it right here with an end
block, I'm going to indent that. Now when I
save it and hit refresh you'll see that
our content from the index HTML page has
overwritten the block content that's
defined here, and so I guess think of it
like if you define a block of code in
here in the base layout and then you
also define the same thing in a child
template the child template will have a
higher priority in essence. So what we're
going to do is I'm going to go into the
single post page and I'm going to do the
same thing. So I'm going to type extends
base.HTML. So if I refresh this and
go to that page you'll see that I have
the same navbar, and that's the point of
using a base layout. Now you also see
that the fallback text is back and
that's because in here we haven't
defined the block content. So, block
content we need to end the block right
there, then I'm going to indent this
properly.
Let's save it, rerun the application,
refresh, and now you'll see that the
entire site so far has a uniform ,
and that's exactly what we wanted.
So, you can also can also do this neat
thing where you can set the title in the
same way. So I'm going to define here
block title, and it's just going to be
the title. So in this case it's going to
be the posts title, so post title. And
then in base HTML that's not going to
work yet because we haven't defined that
as an over writable block of code, it's
set statically here.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to open up the same block called title
and we're going to end that here, and
when we refresh now you'll see I need to
restart that, oh I'm on the index page. When
i go here you'll see that now the posts
title is the name of that, and what we
can do is on the post page we can print
out my site and then the post title, so
if we refresh you will now see it says my site,
awesome post number four, and my first
post. And so that's a basic introduction
to blocks of code and what you can
do with it. Now we're going to be going
on more with this in the future,
most likely, so this should give you guys
enough capability right now to style
this up, make it look like your own, I'm
just going to do a bit of basic styling,
and then in the next video we're going
to get to user authentication.