Hey guys, welcome back. So in styling our
application here I've actually extended
the functionality a little bit and I'm going
to explain what I've done and give you
guys some examples. So here's what I've
got so far. I'm gonna be running a gaming
blog, I guess, I'm not going to be going
over the style so much as the changes I've
made to the actual structure of the
application. So, what we've got to do
is as you notice my posts here changed a
bit,
regardless of the style we're more
talking about the fact that you can
upload images now. So if you go to the
back end here you can load up a post and you
can choose a file, you can upload that
file, that one are used I think let's use
that one, and then save it, and then if
you go back to the web page and refresh
you'll see that that has an image now.
And so the way that I have done that,
let's jump into our PyCharm project here
and go into first our settings. So in
settings the same way that we set the
static URL here you also need to make
sure to set media URL equal to the same
format just /media/, and then create
MEDIA_ROOT = os.path.join(BASE_DIR,
'media/') type it out just
like that. That's going to allow you to
use media files in the creation of posts.
So, what you're going to do is open up
the models here, and you'll see that I
added an image property here to each
post and it's equal to models.ImageField,
which is camel case, and the
default upload location is image. So,
basically when you upload an image it's
going to go into media/image and then
it's
gonna post it there, and it's going to
build an image object inside of the
database for that column. Now when you do
this and you try to run the application
you're going to get problems because some of
the fields don't already have the image
column, and so this is different from
PyMongo. With mongodb you don't have
to worry about that right, but in every
other SQL database, this is SQLite
here, has to lite
whatever it's called there,
not sure how they pronounce it.
So what you're going to do is, what
you need to do first, before you do
anything is you need to make migrations
for the blog before you do anything you
migrate and fake the blog. Then you're going
to go in here and you're going to add
this, you're going to rerun the make
migrations on your blog app, and then
you're going to actually migrate it. So,
this is going to give all other columns,
basically when you,
one sec I ran it up here.
Alright, so when you run the make
migrations the second time
what's going to happen is it is going to
recognize that you're trying to add a
field, so it's gonna allow you to select
a fix and we're going to provide a
default value for all previous posts and
also all posts the future that don't
have an image uploaded to it, and so
you're going to hit the one on your
keyboard and you're just going to type
the name of the placeholder,
essentially. So this is going to be
located in
placeholder.png in the media
directory right above image there. So if
I were to jump over here and take this
image right here, I'm going to copy it
over to PyCharm projects, my site, media,
and paste it right here. I'm going to
rename it to placeholder and this isn't going
to work because that's a JPEG image. So let's
go ahead and find another image that is
a png, do I have any? How about this right
here, let's use that.
Rename this to placeholder.png and now
if we refresh the one post that didn't
have an image you'll see it now has a
placeholder image, and any new post is going
to use whatever we defined as the
placeholder image unless we override
that. So make sure you do that, so again set
an image property of your post, set it to
models.ImageField with the default
argument upload to equal to image, this
is going to store that in the media
image directory. Now in our templates
here open up the index page and the way
that you're going to display that is right
here. You're going to open up a variable
input here and you're going to type
post.image.URL, or if you were to name
this like img like that what you would
do in here is use that same property, so
if you are accessing the image property
whatever we called it and then the URL
property of the image.
So that's one big change that I made the
ability to add images there,
the other big change that I've made is
in the post.
So, when we go to a single post you'll
notice that we have the post itself and
then we've also got some recent posts on
the side we're going to be making a
sidebar, and the way to do this is
basically we first so there's the base
layout right here, and then we're going
to create a single template file which
extends the base and this is going to
contain the sidebar and then you create
another block here which is going to be
overwritten by the post page itself so
in this case I'm calling entry, and then
the post file here we just extend single
template instead of base HTML and what
that does is it puts this right here
into this right here, and then this right
here goes into that. So, we're extending
and extending this is a three-level deep
extension of a template I guess you call
it. Something else I want to mention just
very quick, how do you turn
line breaks into HTML line breaks
because that's something that we haven't
done yet. So, in your post template you're
going to print out post content, put a
pipeline after that, and then
line breaks keyword right there, that's
all you have to do. So I guess another
thing to mention is that in the post
view I've got all posts instead of just
the the one post based on the slug, and
these posts are used to populate the sidebar,
and then I pass in posts to the
post.HTML page as a separate variable to post.
So this is the single post right there
this is all posts, and what you can do is
it's going to go ahead and load the
single template and then it's going to
extend it from, or it's going to load the
post HTML then it's going to extend it
from this, so any variables that you have
accessible in post.HTML is going to
be accessible to higher levels as well,
so here I just put a loop similar to how
the index page used to be. So that's
really the only improvements I've made,
so we're going to, in the next video I
mean, this kind of video is kinda catch
up because a few changes were made and I
didn't want to get you guys lost and I
actually didn't intend to make all these
changes.
When I said I was just going to style
it like well you know what we need
images, you know, so I decided to do that,
and I hope you guys understand how. I'm
going to provide a written demonstration
and put it in this discussion for this
video just make sure. I think I've
explained it well but you guys you might
want to look at the some more example
code and have access to it.