Hey guys, welcome back. In this video
we're going to be starting up our app
for blog, and we're going to put the app
inside of the project. So, inside my
project directory here, am I in my project
directory? Yes, I am. Alright, good stuff.
What we're going to do is we're going to,
going to run
"django-admin startapp blog"
and this should create an application
within our project called blog, and if we
come over into PyCharm here you're going
to see that it shows here. Now, something
I want to see if we can resolve right
now is one of the requests we've
got from students was to increase the
font size in PyCharm, and I get this i'm
filming at 1080p so if you're viewing on
a smaller screen it can be hard to see.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
see if I can do that right now, going to go into
preferences, if I could actually scale
the entire UI up, that would
probably be good too, because these files
on the left you might not be able to see
that well either.
Let's have a look here.
Alright, so we're going to create "New
Fontsize"
I've never done this, ok, and then it will
allow us to increase the font size 16,
one step further 18.
Alright, this looks good, it's a good size
for me, I hope it's a good size for you guys.
If not, let me know, and the font Courier
New, we're going to leave that Menlo and
apply this, alright. So,
Django has created these files for us
here in a blog subdirectory here, and so
we're going to be using some of these
but first what we need to do is we need
to go to our main settings.py and we
need to tell it that we want to include
this app in our installed apps. So how to
do this is right here in installed apps
let's go ahead and just write 'blog' it's that
simple. I'm going to save this. Now what we
need to do is we need to start writing
models and basic code, so what we're
going to do is go into the models file
in the blog here, and we need to also
import some other stuff. So let's go
ahead we're going to import a URL
resolvers, so let's go ahead and write "from django.core.urlresolvers
import reverse" Now we're actually going
to create our model so it's kind of like
when we, when we were writing Webpy.
We're going to be creating classes
except these classes inherit from the
model, I guess root class we'll call
it. Let's go ahead and write "class Post" this is
going to be the class of each blog post so
we're going to add fields here that it
is going to contain. So write "(models.Model):" So when you inherit a class, I believe we
went over this,
we should have, I will check over this
after and if we haven't i'll explain
this more in-depth. Now, anyway,
this is the class that we're going to
inherit from so now this class that we're
creating right now has access to all of
the code that's in this class and it
becomes a part of this class, I hope that
made sense. So now we're going to create certain fields that every post is going
to have, so for example every post is
going to have a post title, and the post
"title = models.CharField( )" and the
character field we need to pass in a
keyword argument called "max_length
=" and then this is going to be the
number of characters that can be a title,
so we're going to say "255" Every post is
also going to need a URI or a slug so let's
go ahead and write "slug = models.SlugField( )" Now these are going to have
to have a few more parameters, we're going to make a "max length=255,"
and then it also needs to be unique. So
basically the slug needs to be unique
for each post in the database,
otherwise we won't be able to access the
correct posts, you know, because they won't
be unique. So pass the keyword
argument "unique= True" it's a boolean
operator. Each is going to have a summary, so this is going to appear on the home
page when it shows all your blog posts,
it's going to instead of showing the
entire content it's going to just show a
summary of the article. So "summary = model.CharField(
max_length=300)" Now is the content. Now this "content = models.TextField( )"
we don't want to limit any characters, so
we're going to use text field and this
makes it a text area. So basically these
are going to be inputs input fields and
this is equal to a text area, and this is
all going to build the admin,
we're going to get to that moment
actually, basically there's an admin site
that you're going to access so it's
going to be whatever/admin and you can
login, you can post things, so this is
going to build out what structure that
needs to be. So we're going to say
published because we're going to be able
to publish it and you know unpublished
articles, so it's going to be "published = models.
BooleanField(default=True) so when we save an
article it's automatically going to be
inserted as published so that
people will be able to view it because
we're going to use that when we pull
them out as well. And then here we are
going to create the created field which
is going to be a datetime, and it's
going to be, it's going to default to now
when the post is posted. So go ahead and write
"created = models.DateTimeField( )" we're
going to pass in one argument it's going
to be "auto_now_add=True" So these
are all going to be properties of each
post, basically. So now we're going to
go ahead and define the subclass
called "class Meta:"
and "ordering = [ ]" we're going to sort this based on
the date, so put '-created' and then inside this
class we're going to define a few other
things, we need to set the unicode in
order for the posts to work, so "def __unicode__(self):" and we're going to say "return u" and
here's where we're going to put the
title. So we're going to convert the title
itself into title '%s'% self.title and then we're going to "def get_absolute_url(self):"
We're going to "return reverse" and we're going to define a view
that we haven't yet created, so "('blog.views.post',
args=
[self.slug])" and this is going to
connect to this, so that's going to be the
arguments passed in to this view that we
have yet to create.