Hey guys, before we move on i actually
found a problem in my code. I actually
put this under the metaclass and it
should be just under the the post class
itself because it's going to be post.get
absolute URL that we're going to be
accessing, so go ahead and save this file.
Now once we're done writing the model
for the post what we need to do is we
need to sync the database. Now there was
a change so there's going to be, i'm sure
when the change happened, I know the
first time I ever used Django there was
a sink db command and you'll still find
information out there that refers
to this command, but that has actually
become a migrate command now.
So what I need you guys to do is go ahead
and run "python3 ./manage.py migrate"
it's this simple. It's going to, the first
time you do it should be correct because
you guys didn't have this in the wrong
class when you did it.
What we need to do is run make
migrations now. So, "python3 ./manage.py
makemigrations" this is going to
create the migrations to run, and then
run "python3 ./manage.py migrate"
Right, the default Python on my system is
Python 2, we're using Python 3 so we
need to begin every every python3
command with the the actual name of the
interpreter that we're using. So, there we
go.
What we're going to be focusing on in
this video is getting the administration
of the running, and it's pretty simple.
All we have to do is in terminal here
we're going to run "python3 ./manage.py"
and then we're just going to pass it the
argument create superuser, all one word, so "createsuperuser" This is going to
create a superuser and we're going to be
able to, it's going to use my username by
default, so my email is going to go in
here, and then my password is going to be
"avocado1"
alright. So now we're going to run the
server again, so "runserver" Now if you go to your
address here /admin it's going to take you
to this login page, so i'm going to go
ahead and login, and you should see this
and that's exactly what we want to see.
What we need to do in order to get our
posts working in the administration, we're
going to jump into PyCharm here, and
we're going to go into admin right here, and we're going to just register our model
that we've written, the post model. So
let's go ahead and write "from .models
import Post" and then we're going to
register the model and how you register
a model that you write, obviously first
you have to import it, and then you need
to run this command "admin.site .register(Post)" then what ever model you want
to register, so in this instance
it's post. Going to go ahead and save
this, we're going to rerun the server, I
can probably run this in here. I can
configure this I bet, let me see if we
can configure manage here to run with
run server, let me see. Up here run, edit
configurations, i'm going to add run server
in here, and we're going to run, it should
run.
No, let's try again. Oh, right here,
Script parameters, "runserver" There, alright. So now when we run it, it should run the
server so we don't have to go into
terminal each, time. So I can open up
terminal here
cancel out here, and I can actually just
close that now and we should be able to
run from right within here and we can. So,
this is gonna make things a lot easier.
We just re-ran and so let's go ahead and
open up the Django admin again, let's
refresh, and now you'll see in our blog
here we have posts and we can come here and
we can get a list and edit posts, but we
don't have any posts so we can go ahead
and add one. So, i'm going to name this "My first post" the slug is going to be
"my-first-post" The summary here
we can actually turn that into a text
area as well, but for right now i'm going
to write, "The first post that I've
created from within the django project."
and we need some lipsum. I think it's
.com,
yeah there we go.
Let's copy this, and I mean we still don't have any views so we're not going to be able
to see this right now, we're going to be
creating views I believe in the next
video, so let's save this. Now we see post
object right here, so we can see our our
posts.