Hey there guys, welcome back. We've learned
how to insert posts into the database
and now we need to learn how to bring
them out on to the front end, and how to
view them in the web browser. So what
we're going to do in this video we're
going to be working in three files, so in
the main directory, in the root directory,
go ahead and open up urls.py. In the
blog subdirectory go ahead and open up
views.py and these are really the
only two files were working with at this
point, the third one we are going to be
creating it in a little bit, probably
actually the next video.
So, what we're going to do here we
actually need to create some views in
order to to show them by url, so what
we're going to do well actually we're
going to start out with URLs. So what we're
going to do we're going to import this
views file so the path is blog views, so
what we're going to do is "from blog"
which is the director name "import views"
and now we might have views from a bunch
of different apps, so what we're going to
be doing is remaining these as we import
them. So, "as blog_views" then what
we're going to do is we're going to
create a few routes here, so let's go
ahead and create a single post route. So,
"url" and we're going to open up
regex here we're going to say "(r'post/%')"
"(r'post/%')"
We're going to say that's going to route
to the method in the blog views called
", blog_views.post" and then we're going to go ahead
and create an index page route. So,
"url(r'^')"
make sure and put the pointy thing, and I didn't do that up
here, you need to do that and this is
just going to be / so this is really it.
Just put the $ right there and
then go ahead and from this route we're
going to be loading up "blog_views.index"
then put a comma there. Now we're only going
to be defining two routes at this point and
this probably says we don't have those
views. So what we're going to do is we're
going to go ahead and open
up the views file right here and
we're going to create them. So in order
to do this we need to actually import
something first, so "from django.http" we
need to import a class called "HttpResponse"
And right here we're going to start
writing our views so the first one we're
going to write is the index, so go ahead
and write "def index( )" and for every view
that you create with django you need to
pass a parameter named "request" into
the function, so there we go.
And now what we're going to do is we're
going to get all the posts, actually for
right now we're just going to return a
simple page, so "return HttpResponse( )"
and in here create and string call it or
let's make it say "Hey there." and then
we're going to create the post view as
well and I believe I named that post,
right. Let's go ahead and "def post(request):"
"return HttpResponse("I'm a single post page.")"
We're going to save this. We should
be good right now to go ahead and load
up our application I believe, and refresh, and
as you can see our main page already
shows
hey there and if we go to /post we see
I'm a single post page.