Hey guys, welcome back. I understand that
for the most part we are not going to be
dealing with strings in HTTP responses,
so in this video we're going to learn
about templates a little bit and we're
going to be following that into the next
video as well. So what we need to do is
in our blog application here we need to
create a directory, we're going to call that
templates, and then in here we could
create just regular old HTML files and I'm
going to name this one
index and I'm going to select all
here, "&lt;h1&gt;I'm an index page.&lt;h1&gt;"
Alright, we're going to save that. Now
in our views we actually need
to basically just change from using HTTP
response to using render, and the render
call is a bit different. So what I'm going
to do is I'm going to delete this, i'm
going to type "render" and this is also
a method so what we need to do basically
is pass in the request first "(request)" and then
the name of the template file so in this
case it's 'index.html' and then
parameters as well which for right now
is just going to be that the object  So
go ahead and save, and then we can load
up this page and we're still in the
single post page so let me go ahead and
get over to main page, and as you can see
this is an h1 element and so we're actually
loading up HTML templates and here you
can do a lot more than you'd be able to
do right here. Now in the next video
we're actually going to learn about
getting our posts out and showing an
index page of all of our posts.