Alright, welcome back guys. So before we
actually go any further what we need to
do is actually create some more posts in
our application here. So I really don't
recall the username and password that I
set,
oh awesome I got it right.
So in post we only have one post but
we're working on an index page right now
and so Index Test is going to be the
name of this, slug is going to be index-test,
summary is going to be This is to show
more than one post. I'm going to go get
some lipsum,
paste that in there, and then i'm going
to save it. Is there a way that I can
duplicate posts, actually. That'd be neat.
No, I can't. Alright, unless published view
on site,
nope. Let's go ahead and create one more.
Title is going to be Awesome post number
three or 4, sure. I'm going to post the
same lipsum actually in there, going to
save, now we've got three posts so that's
awesome. What we're going to do now is in
our...here we go. In our views file
right here we need to import the post
for models. So if we go ahead and open up
models we will see this is the object, this
for each one of these posts it adheres
to this structure, and so we will have
access to the title of the slug, the
summary, etc. So what we're gonna do is
we're going to import this file into the
views file. So let's go ahead "from
.models" it means from the current
directory models "import Post" and then
the index page here we're just going to
get all of the posts. So let's go ahead
and create a variable called
"posts = Post.objects.all( )" it's
really that simple.
Now, we won't have access in the HTML
right now just by creating the variable,
what we need to do is that passed as a
parameter and it's going to pass the
variable into the HTML file here. So
we're going to create this just like any
regular dictionary object so i'm gonna
create a value for key {'posts': and it's going to
be equal to the "posts" variable. So i'm
going to go ahead and save this. It's not
going to do anything right now. I'm going
to view the site here and it still says
I'm an index page and that's because we
haven't done anything in the HTML page.
So, here's the fun bit. What we're going
to do there's two different types of syntax's that
we need to use here, and i'm going to explain
each one. So, you're going to see this and
that's going to be used for beginning or
ending blocks of code. So let's go ahead
and type  and then
we're going to end that right there
And now this is just a typical for
statement. So what we're going to do in
here is we're going to create a &lt;div&gt; &lt;div&gt; for
each post, and then an &lt;h3&gt; &lt;h3&gt; element and
this is going to have the title. So you
don't open it like this
that's not going to work right here, what
we need to do to print out variables is
open it with two curly braces on each
side, and then we're going to print out
} and underneath it here we're
going to let's go ahead and just print
out the summary for now &lt;p&gt;}&lt;/p&gt;
and let's save it. Now when this refreshes,
did it just refresh, I guess it did, ok. So it's
showing the title from each post, it's not showing
the summary. Did i do that wrong? I did
something wrong, I think, hold on. Let's inspect this.
The first one doesn't have a title,
none of them have titles, I accessed that
wrong? Posts, oh, posts title. There's the
problem.
Alright, let's refresh, there we go.
So as you can see we got the title of
each and the the text of each post
as you can see right here. So what we're going
to do is we're going to turn this into a
link, a hyperlink, and we're going to send
that through to another page. So let's go
ahead and open up an a element here, let me put
a space here, &lt;a href=
"/post/}"
and we're going to end that link right
there. So let's go ahead and refresh, and
refresh this and now you'll see that each
one of these turned into a link and if I
click on it, it goes to post/awesome-post-number-4
for that one, post/index-test
etc. And so this is going to we're
going to build out this route in the next
video.