Hey guys, welcome back. So, what we've got
so far is a basic single page that
doesn't actually show our posts, so what we
need to do is we need to make this
dynamic and actually show the requested
post in the page. So what we need to do we
need to import two more classes from
Django shortcuts, so it's going to be
"render to response" and then "get_object_
or_404" So in the post method right here
we actually need to change this, so in
the URLs what we need to do is we need
to add a little bit here of regex so I'm
going to put (.*)
and this is going to put a request in
here.
So, what we're going to do in the views
file is we're going to pass that in right
there "slug" and to see if this is working
we're going to print(slug). So let's go
ahead and save this, and run our program.
I'm going to go ahead and open up my
browser here and go to local host at
port 8000, I'm going to click on a post here, and
look in PyCharm and we do see that it
requests the actual slug. So we're capturing
that into this variable right here. So we
need to actually change all of this at
this point, so I'm going to delete that, we're
actually going to return render_to_
response. Now the first argument is going
to be the title or name of the HTML
template that we want to load, so in this case
it's ('post.html') the second argument is
going to be an object  so we need to open
it up like that, and we're going to pass
along the individual post in a variable
called 'post': and this is where we're
going to use get_object_or_404 and we're
going to pass it the class that we want
to look in, and the matching parameter
that we want to to grab the post by. So
in this case we're going to be looking
in
the (Post,) class, and we're going to be
looking for slug=slug. So it's
going to match the slug find the post
and return it to the template in this
variable. So go ahead and save this, and
now we need to go create this page. So in
templates here i'm going to create a new
HTML file called post, and I'm going to remove
this, and i'm just going to print out
&lt;h2&gt;}&lt;/h2&gt; and
then &lt;div&gt; &lt;/div&gt; right here we're going to
print out }
Save this, refresh the application,
we're going to rerun it, we're going to
refresh this page, and as you can see our
posts now are full and we might actually
want to add a link here at the top that
goes back a page. So...
let's jump down a few lines and it
should refresh, not sure if it's going to, now we
see we have now a working link that's back
to index on every single post page. And
one other thing we're going to do in
this video and this is going to wrap up
the Django section a bit, I mean we've
learned all the basics of Django, if you
guys want to take this further it's a
great package you can make great
websites and it's really easy to use, and
what we're going to do here is we're
going to add one more route.
It's going to be ur(r'^about/$'), and it's going to
be about. That's going to connect to
blog_views.about and we're just gonna make a
static page. def about(request):
So we're just going to use the render
method return render(request, 'about.html',  ) and
I mean we've done this before this isn't
going to be new, but used to drill this
in there make sure that you guys
understand the different concepts. We've
done this, we've done this specific
thing incidently, but we haven't done it
intentionally and so that's what we're
going to do now. Go ahead and create an
HTML file call it up about.html and this
is just gonna be literally a static page &lt;h1&gt;Static Page&lt;/h1&gt;
You could add all the content you
want to this page, you should refresh, refresh
this, and go to about and you'll see that
we do get a static page. We go back and browse
the site like that.