Hey guys, welcome back. So if we run our
django project here, and we open up
Safari and go to localhost port 8000, this
is a terrible looking site. So what we're
going to be doing is integrating django
with bootstrap. So, what we need to do
is go ahead and open a terminal here and
type "pip3 install django-bootstrap3"
and it should install
bootstrap in there. So what we need to do
now is we need to go into our project
into settings, and we need to find the
installed apps section, which is way up
here, and what we need to add is
'bootstrap3' So
in order for bootstrap to work we
actually need to include it into the
template files, so in this case I'm
looking at the index page so what I'm going
to do at the very top of the index page
here
you just need to load bootstrap 3. So
we're going to put this in the command
type, remember there's different kinds of
curly braces to use this is used for
blocks of codes or commands, and this is
used to print out variables and
whatnot. So we're using this type here
the kind with the with the percent
symbol, and we're just going to type
"" So let's go ahead and open up
another tag and we need to type
"" and then ""
and so basically what load bootstrap 3
does is it loads these tags that you can
use within your template. So what we're
going to do is let's save this, let's refresh
the app, and now you'll see that we do
have a working bootstrap. So that's how
to make our site a little prettier.
I'm gonna be styling this before the
next video so you guys feel free to do
the same if you want, I just don't want
to work with such a terribly simple site.