Hey guys, welcome back. I'm going to style
the app up a little bit to make it look
less basic and simple for the rest of
this section of videos, but before I do that
I want to allow you guys to do the same,
so I'm own going to explain the concept of
static files in Django. So with Django as you
can see most of the files we've created
so far have been loaded through Python
and served through Python and we
actually can't link to any of these
files just by putting a link into the
template files. What we need to do if we
want to load say a custom style sheet is
we need to use the static files directive,
and so how we do that is basically just
in the settings file here make sure that
at the bottom of your file you have a
static URL constant set to this '/static/'
and then what we're going to do is that
relates to our...to each app. So what we're
going to do is in the blog here we're
going to create a new directory called
static, and then in that static directory
i'm going to create a new directory
called css, and then in the css directory
i'm going to create a new style sheet
and i'm going to call it style.css. Now
in here just to make sure it works i'm
going to change the background of the
body to an ungodly color of bright red "body "
and to make sure that bootstrap doesn't
override this going to add the "!important"
flag here and this is going to make this
always no matter how much specificity is
involved in another CSS style
this is not going to be overridden by
any of those. Now what we're going to
have to do is in the index file here, and
drop down a few lines here, and i'm going
to open up some ah so curly brackets and
percent symbols here i'm going to
call this tag from now on, that's what this is.
So this allows us to enter Python code in
Django code, so what I'm going to do is
""
and then underneath that i'm going
to add &lt;link rel="stylesheet"
type="text/css and the
href=""
and then in
single quotes in here write 'css/style.css'
and then save it, rerun the
application, and if we refresh the page
you'll see that this actually did work.
Now, it looks like this has caused the
bootstrap link to not work, so let me have a
look there. We forgot to close it,
there we go. So let's close that, refresh
our application, and you'll see that now
bootstrap and our custom CSS is working
and it looks really terrible, so I'm
going to end that here. In the next video
you'll see this a little more styled and
structured, and it will look more like a
website. If you guys want to do that feel
free, it's going to make things easier to
navigate in the future doing this
specific section of the course.