Hey guys, welcome back. We have a few more things to do before we get into GUI
programming, but that is what we're going
to do next.
I was going to do pygtk built-in GUI
library, and then also pycute, but I'm
not going to do pygtk because it looks
like since the last time I used it
it's actually been obsoleted and
discontinued. So we're just going to go
through I think just pycute for now, I
mean that seems pretty full,
so we'll do that. But, first we need to
discuss is a few more concepts before we
actually get into that and so the first
one that we're going to be talking about
is a form of data persistence, and what I
mean by that is we want the ability to
open and read and write files in Python,
and that's something that we have native
support in the Python language without
even importing anything. So we're going
to look at a few examples, the first one
we're going to do is just a basic
writing a txt file, and so let's go ahead
and start that. So basically what we need
to do is we need to create a variable
that stores the file in the buffer and
then we write to that file. So what we're
going to do is we're going to create a
variable called, oops I just took a
screenshot, "newfile = open" and then
this is gonna take two parameters. So the
first parameter is going to be the name
of the file that we want to create, now
you can add an absolute path in here
by using the I believe it's OS join and
you can join file paths and stuff, but
we're going to do we're just going to
create a final in the current directory,
and we're going to call it "("newfile.txt")" and then you put a comma and
then the second parameter it takes is
what type of operations it's going to be
doing on the file. So if we just want it
to read a file we would add the r flag,
but what we're going to do is we're
going to write to the file so let's add
"w+" So then
that's going to create a file
in the system's memory, and then we can
manipulate that file and save it. So what
we're going to do is we're going to create
another variable which is going to just
be a string of texts, so label this a
"string = "This is the content that will be
written to the text file." and then how we
write it is we're going to use the
new file as a sort of object, so we're
gonna type "newfile.write" and then
we're just going to pass it what we want
to write to the file. So in this case
it's just going to be the "(string)" Now if
we save this, and we go to run it, we have
no output, but you'll see that it did
create the new text file and if i open
it,
it has the content that we wanted to
be into it. So that's basically how you
can write to a file, now let's say we
want to read from a file. We're going to
do that in the next video and we're
going to also be going over some JSON
stuff as well.