Alright guys, so in the last video we
learned about some form of data
persistence in terms of writing files, in
this video we're going to be learning
about reading and writing files, and also
manipulating existing file contents. So,
the use case of this would be lets say
i'm building a video game or something,
and I create a save function, i'm going
to need to save the data like what
level I am, how much experience points,
maybe what items and spells I have
access to, i'm going to need to store that
information into a file so that
each time I load up the game I
can check does this file exist, and if
it does start with these stats, and items,
and whatnot. So this is another form of
data persistence and that's the use case
for it,
what we're going to be doing is learning
about JSON format. So that's a format
of data storage and a file format
that Python can actually use quite well.
We can convert JSON objects to Python
objects, and vice versa, and that's what
we're going to be doing in this video. So
the first thing we need to do is install
a package, a Python package called simpleJSON, so just type "pip3 install simplejson"
I've already got it installed so
it's going to tell me I've already got
it installed, it doesn't come with Python
though, it doesn't come pre-installed
with Python, so if you haven't installed
it manually you will need to install it.
Now once you've got it installed,
obviously, we need to import it into the
script that we're writing, so go ahead
and type "import simplejson" Now we
would be able to access the simplejson
class simply by typing that "simplejson." and then we can access all the methods and
functions in there, but we just want to
refer to it as simply json and not simplejson,
just json. So what we can do
actually with Python is rename imported
classes on the fly for use within a
specific file, and what I mean by that is
in this file we can actually refer to it
as json instead of simplejson by
renaming it, and how you
rename imports is you type import
whatever package as and then what you
want to refer to it as "import simplejson as json" Now we also need to import the OS class and this is
because we're going to be writing and
reading files, and we need to be able to get
some information about the files. For
instance, if file exists, and if the file
is not empty.
So, what we need to do first we need to
create the if statements, so we're going
to essentially do if there is a file we
need to read the data from the file
manipulate it, if there is not a file we
need to create data, and at the very end
we're going to save whatever data we
have.
So, how we do that, we're going to first
check if the file exists, so we're going to
be working with file called ages.json
stored in the current directory. So
to check if the file exists or not we
can use the OS class, so "if os.path.isfile"
and what this will do is it will check
if there's a file with whatever name we
give it. So we're going to check the
current directory and it's going to be "("./ages.json")" So this will return true if the
file does exist, that's not enough though,
what if we accidentally have an empty
file and we load it and and try and do stuff with it? So now we're going to check if the file
size is not 0. So, if the file exists "and os.stat("./ages.json").st_size != 0:"
"and os.stat("./ages.json").st_size != 0:"
the size of the file we just want to make sure it's not 0, because if it is
zero then we've got a blank file and we
want to create the default data. So what
we're going to do we're going to open
the file here if it exists and stuff, so
let's go ahead and type "old_file = open("./ages.json", "r+")"
and this is going to allow us to redo it and whatnot. So go ahead
and type "data =" and we can just load
the content by typing oldfile.read,
and that's method so you need the
the brackets after it, but we need to do
is we also need to convert it into a
Python object as we load it.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to access this jason class here and
we're going to type "data = json.loads" and what this means is it's going to load the string
from the file, and then we just type "old_file.read" So again what this is going to
do is this is going to be the content
we're going to read from the old file,
and this is going to load it into a
Python usable object. So once we've got
the data variable created we can type
"print("Current age is", data["age"], "adding-- adding a year.")"
then we're going to manipulate the age
part of this object, so we're going to
say "data["age"] = data["age"] + 1" So we are increasing the
age by one, and then we're going to print
out the new age. So, print("New age is", data["age"])"
Now this block of code is going to
run if there is a file and if there's
content in the file, now if there's not a
file what we need to do is we need to
create, we need to create the file with
the data. So let's go ahead and type "else"
"old_file" just so that we have
essentially we're going to open a file
in that variable if it exists, but if not
then we need to create it as the same
name so "= open(./ages.json", "w+")" we're going to open this in write mode, and then
we're going to set the data. So, this is
going to say "data = " and we're just building
a regular Python object here, we're going
to convert it into a json
object, and you'll see why we're doing
this because up here we are loading it
into a Python object, but we're not
dumping it back into a json object
yet, we're going to do that outside of
the if condition. So we're also going to
set the "age": 27}" here and it's going to be
equal to my age. Then we need to print
out basically the files wasn't found, so "print("No
file found, setting default age to", data["age"])" Then, outside of the if statement
we've basically what we've done is we've
got a data object either way, so we're
going to use that, and we've also got an old file variable either way and it's equal to
an existing file or no file. So, what we're
going to do we're going to drop down
here, we're going to say "old_file.seek(0)"
this is going to set it to position 0, so
essentially if there is a file existing
that we're going to write to we need to
seek to the zero position, otherwise it's
just going to append data in the file. So
this means we can read and write, so if
there is a file we're using this
instance of that variable, so it's an
existing file and we need to seek that,
to essentially the start of the file.
Then what we do here simple we type "old
_file.write( )" and here we need to write our data variable to the file, but first we
need to convert it back into a json
object. So how we do that is "(json.dumps(data))"
and then the data object. So let's go
over this file again really quick. If
there is an existing file we are going open that file in read/write mode,
we're going to load the data from the
file, and then we're just going to
increase the age by one. If there is not
a file we're going to create a file into
the old file object, this is going to
create in-memory first once we write to
it is going to create it.
The data object is set to a Python
object and we're going to just print out
that the default page, and then we're
going to dump the data in to the file. So let's
save this and go ahead and run it, and on
the first run obviously no file is found
so it's setting the default page 27. Now
if we run it again it should say the
current age
is 27 and then increase it 28, and then
if we actually open this we can see the
changes happening in real time. Let's run
it again, it's going to change 29, and so
on and so forth. Now I could just leave
this as is turn off my computer and
stuff and come back tomorrow, and I could run again it and it would continue from the
same spot and that's because we're storing data in a persistent file in the file
system, and that's why reading and
writing from files is useful. So thank
you guys for watching and I'll see you
guys in the next video.