Hey guys, this is a quick video. What
we're gonna be doing is say we want to
install some packages and set up one
environment that has a certain set of
packages, but not have to install them
globally. So what we've been doing so far
using pip is we've been globally
installing packages, so any project that
I use I can now import simplejson as a
package, but let's say I want to set up a
very specific environment for just one
project that I want to install a bunch
of packages into, and we're going to be
doing that very soon, so that's why we
need to learn about this and it's called
virtualenv. So how you get that is
type "pip3 install virtualenv" and
I've already got it installed but if you
guys don't, if you haven't manually
installed it, it will install it. Once it's
installed,
what you can do is I'm going to change
into my projects directory, and i'm going
to create a new virtual environment. So,
what you do is just type "virtualenv"
and then the name of the virtual
environment you want to create. So, i'm
going to type test projects, or "testnv"
Now that we've got it
installed, you actually need to activate
it, and you'll be able to tell if you're
working in a virtual environment because
right here next to the prompt it would
say the name of the virtual environment
if you're in it. So what we're going to
do to activate it basically if I list
here you'll see testnv right here,
so what we need to do is we need to
source a file from there "source testnv/bin/activate"
and now as you'll see
i'm currently working in this virtual
environment. So any package that I
install now is going to install just
this environment, and then once I you
know if I close the terminal and open it
again I'll be back into the global
Python environment, so if i install
packages there,
you know, they would be globally
accessible to this one as well.