Hey guys, so I wanted to discuss more
about Python packages and where you
could find some if you're looking for
some packages. So let's go ahead and open
up a browser here, and there's actually a
Python package index which is called PyPI,
and if we come here there's the
ability to browse packages here, you can
also see packages here as well.
Now, if we go to browse packages,
I mean you can also submit packages if
you build modules and you want to submit
them to the Python package index which
allows them to be installed using pip. So,
let's go ahead and narrow down some into, there we go we've got webgobbler
here, let's go ahead and take a look at
this. If you click on a package, and I
mean you can search packages too, but if
you get to a packages page it's going to
give you a description here, gives you
some meta information about it, and
basically all we have to do is grab this,
open up terminal here and "pip3 install
webgobbler" Couldn't find a version so, no matching distribution.
Alright, well, you can also go to the
download URL.
Let's look for django because this is
something we're going to be getting into
very soon as well. So if i just search
django on the python package
index you'll see a bunch of modules here
as well, however we're just going to look
for this one right here which is Django.
You can download directly from here if
you'd like to,
however we're not going to. It says it
requires bcrypt,
argon2, and extra so let's go ahead and
jump into terminal here, and "pip3
install django" see if that installs it, awesome.
So we are installing django here, it should
pull in any additional packages that it
requires, and then once we get it
installed we can just begin using
it just like any other python package. So,
we're going to get into that in the next
section, for right now that's all I
wanted to talk about regarding getting
packages, and of course you know how to
use them.
You can go to the homepage of the Python package as well if you want to get more
information, and they usually have pretty
good documentation. So, for django we're
just going to drop into the
documentation here and you can see
tutorials, reference, guides, etc., and most
packages have a pretty good
documentation, even if it's a github page
instead of the website, it it's usually
pretty straightforward.