Hey guys, let's jump into data
visualization. So what we're going to be
using for this is a library for
Python called matplotlib, and it allows
you to create visualizations of data
like line charts, bar charts, etc. And so
let's go ahead and install it. I am going
to bring up terminal here, you do the
same. If you're on Windows you will need
to run pip3, and I hope it's in your
path. A little note on Python and Windows
is when you install it using the
installer there's an option that you
need to make sure it's checked
that says add to path. And then once you
do that and install it, if you open up a
command prompt and the Python command
isn't found, then just try restarting. You
can also check your path and stuff like
that. If you guys need more help
definitely just let me know, but if you
got to this point then I think you're
fine. So, Linux and Mac OS run terminal, on
Windows open up command prompt, and
you're going to type pip3 install
matplotlib. And it's going to pull in I
think numpy and scipy as well.
Yeah, there's numpy,
it's going to bring in a bunch of
dependencies here. So, there we've
installed it, and it also tells me that
pip has a new version. So let's go ahead
and update pip here.
There we go, and this should update it. No,
I ran pip instead of pip3, right. So
it's trying to update Python 2's
pip. There we go. No? Not pip3 either.
i will have to check out what's going on
with that. It's a permission denied problem...
sudo pip3 install --upgrade pip. If you guys ever
get a permission denied error with
Python, chances are you just need to run
it as sudo, but if you don't want to run
sudo commands just anywhere you know you
should, you might want to dig into
further why the permission was denied. But
for this instance root has access to
this file. So, I'm going to close this, and
we've just installed matplotlib. Now in
the next video we're going to get to
some basic usage, and we're going to ramp
up our usage of matplotlib to what I
hope will be intense levels.