Alright, so, what I'm going to do now is
I'm going to start adding our multiple
data sets to this bar chart, and we're very
quickly going to see one problem
that we're going to need to account for.
So let's go ahead and create c1 which is
going to be Canada's data, and we're going to
say plt.bar and here we're going to pass
in our data. So the x-axis is going to be
the index variable there, which essentially
it's a list that says 0, 1, 2, and we're
going to add Canada scores, and then
we're going to set the bar width also
to .5. Now when I run this you're going to
see that the bars themselves are
occupying the same space, except
vertically because the vertical values
are different, but essentially when
setting the index here to 0, 1, and 2
we're setting the x axis or the
horizontal position to the same values,
and so they're going to occupy the same
space. So what we could do we definitely
could modify this maybe to make that
chart or to make those bars with it
thinner, and that way we could compare
the data. Actually, we do it the opposite
way there. Let's make Canada's, because Canada's
are on top so we could compare it like
that, but that just doesn't look right,
and we're going to be adding two more to
it. So what we need to do I'm going to
create a bar width here, and we're just
going to set it to .1 actually so
they're actually going to be a lot
smaller, and then we're going to use the
bar width variable here because we're
also going to be using this variable for
another calculation. So, if I go ahead and
restart the application you're going to
see they're thinner, but they're
occupying the same space, so what I can
do is this right here is from 0 to 0.1
or 0.5 because each bar width is
.1, so I can set the next bar or
Canada's bar instead of having a
starting point of 0, 1, and 2 I can
set that to 0.1, 1.1, and 2.1. So
how I'm going to do that is just in the
index which actually plots out the
x-axis I'm going to do a bit of math
here, and I'm going to basically just
index plus bar_width, and this should place
it in the orange one just to the right of
the blue ones, and as you can see that's
the exact desired result. So what I'm
going to do now is I'm going to add
China and France's score, and I'm also
going to apply this same method except
it's going to be bar_width x 2, and
bar_width x 3, for example. Or, we could also
simplify that into a different math
equation, but for right now let's go
ahead and create ch1, it's going to be
plt.bar, it's going to be index plus 0.2, it's
going to be china_scores, and we're going
to be using the same bar_width. And then
f1 is going to be the France bars, so
plt.bar index plus 0.3, and it's going to be
france_scores, and bar_width. So I'm going
to change one thing here instead of
using bar with right here, I'm going to
do this, and then this way you'll see
this would be 0, 0.1, 0.2, 0.3, and then the
rest of the space, and then it would
start at the next data point as well. So
there we go. We've got our four sets of
data, but this is kind of thrown off a
bit because now the axis,
or the ticks, are in the wrong position
and also they're labeled wrong. So what we're
going to be doing, well first we're
going to be adding the labels to
the values here, and also an alpha
setting. So, alpha is going to make it
look nicer, it's going to tone down the
the color, because the colors are very
vivid and vibrant and that's cool but
for this kind of chart it doesn't
work. So we're going to set alpha to .4 for
each of these, and then we're going to
set the label of each of them as well. So
this is going to be Korea, I'm going to drop down a
line. Do the same thing here, so alpha
equals 0.4, and then label i's going to
be Canada, and then alpha is going to be equal to
.4, and label is going to be equal to China,
and then the last one which is France
we're going to also set the Alpha here, there we go.
So now when I run the application you're
not going to notice any difference right
away, but we are going to turn the legend
on. So how you're going to do that is down
here where we're configuring the options
for the entire chart, think of this in
sections, like here where we're arranging
the data up here. So here we're creating
the data, here we're putting the data
into the chart, and then here we are
configuring and showing the chart. So
what I'll do is here plt.legend, and you
don't need to pass anything into that,
that's going to make the legend show, and
you can't configure the legend but for
right now these default values are
exactly how we want them, and now we're
going to take care of the x ticks here. So
the Y ticks are perfectly fine because
we want to see that data, that's the
actual scores that we're going to be
comparing, but what we need to do first
we need to
move this over to in the middle, so
between the orange and the green bars,
and then we also need to change the
labels. So, let's go ahead right here
above the legend call and we're going to
say plt.xticks. And, so we're going to
iterate through the indexes, we're going
to say index plus .3 divided by 2,
and you're going to
see now that it has moved correctly. So
basically what it's doing is it set it
to here, so what it's doing is it's plus
.3 divided by 2, alright, and so it's
1, 4, and then it divides it by 4, and then
it equals 2, plus the index. So, that's very
important right there, but then what
we're going to do is we're going to pass
a tuple into that as well, and these
are going to be the actual X data points
or the subjects that we're comparing, so
math, reading, and science. So I'm going to
save this, run it again, and now we're
going to start to see our chart actually
take form. So, what we're going to do is
we're also going to add a label on the
left-hand side to convey that it's the
mean score. So how we're going to do that
is the X&amp;Y label, so plt.ylabel, this of
course y is vertical, and it's going to
say, "Mean score in PISA 2012," and then
plt.xlabel is going to be "Subjects."
I'm going to add a title as well, and
it's going to be called, "Test Scores
by Country." Then we're going to restart
the application, and now we see something
that looks more like a complete chart.
You can also add more to this, and we're most
likely going to, but for right now we
have a good visualization of four
countries in three subjects, and we can
see well this is Korea so Korea is doing
second best in terms of mathematics
scores, where China is doing the best, and
Canada's pretty low there, so is France.
So, there we go we
with that. So thank you guys for watching this.
I'm probably going to be extending this
type of thing even further, or just cover
more options for different charts using
the same data points.