Alright guys, so, now we're going to talk
about making this even easier to read,
and that's by adding specific numbers
for each chart, and I'm going to show you
how we're going to do that. So, basically,
these items that we create here, these
objects, so for instance k1, has a lot of
different methods that we can call on it.
So, what I mean by that is this is just a
collection of items, okay. So what I'm
going to do is I'm going to drop down to
the bottom here, and just for an example
I'm going to say for item in k1: print
item.get_height. Then I'm going to save,
I'm going to re-run the application, and
down here it's going to give you
exact numbers for each of the
bars height. You can also get width, so
let's rerun this, and it gives us the
bars width and then you can also get X,
and you can get Y as well I'm sure, but
we're not really interested in that
right now. So as you can see this is
placed at minus -0.05 which would be like
right here, .95, and 1.95. So we can
actually use this data to pinpoint where
certain numbers would show and then show
those numbers there. So, we're going to be
doing that in this video. What I'm going
to do here is I'm going to create a
method called create labels, and it's
going to take data, and I've been writing in
C++ and you can tell because I opened up
curly braces. Alright, so what we
need to do is we need to do the same
thing for item in data, so this is
essentially the same as for item in k1,
or c1, or ch1, and for instance there's
three items in it
and the three items are this, this, and
this. Simple. So what we're going to be
doing, and each of those items has a
property like X, Y, height, width stuff like that,
so let's go ahead and we're going to set
the height variable and this is going to
be equal to item.get_height, and then we're
going to say plt.txt and we can
actually add text to the chart, and so
that's what we're going to be doing.
We're going to be defining the position
first and then the actual value, so the
exposition is going to be a bit of math
here, item.get_width, et's start with the
exposition, plus item.get_width / 2.
It's important to make that a float. The height
is going to be height x 1.05, and it's
going to put it a bit above the height
of the chart. Now we're going to be
getting into the actual printing the
actual numbers there, and how we're going
to do that is, and I'm going to show you guys
something neat here, and let's actually
do that before we get into this. So I'm
going to comment this out. I'm going to
show you guys something let's say we
have an integer here, and it's equal to 365 the
number of days in the year, and we wanted to
print that out. There are 365 days in a
year,
and then we ran this that definitely
would work, but it can get messy looking
especially with all this extra white
space, the plus signs, just converting it to
a string, etc. So what we do actually,
we're going to erase all this, we're able
to create placeholders in a string, and
then passing data afterwards at the end of a
string. So we're going to say data, and
then we're going to use a percent symbol
here, and then we're going to pass in
whatever variable we want, so integer
right there. And now if we rerun the app
you're going to see that it still says
the same thing but it looks nicer and that's
using percent symbols, and what we can do
is we can put another one there and then
say year.
No, we can't. Can we put that in the tuple?
...
Okay, sorry, that's how to put
numbers in to strings. There's a similar
way to do it for...
Alright, so, what I'm going to do is drop
down here and I'm going to print out,
well first we're going to set a variable
called integer, it's going to be equal to
365 let's say, and now we're going to
print "there are," you convert this to a
string, 365 days in a year, and if we save
this and run the application it
definitely will print out exactly what
we want. It should...oh, I added a 365 there.
There we go. But it can get looking messy
when you have multiple numbers that you
have to throw into a string especially
with all this white space, and the plus
symbols, and stuff. So what we're going to
do here instead is we're just going to put
a placeholder there, and then we use the
percent symbol, and then we define what
needs to go in that placeholder. So
then we can save it, and we can run it
again, and it's going to say the same
thing but this looks a bit nicer. So
we're going to be using that here in the
create labels method, and so the
parameter that it takes in third, so
first is the exposition, second is the y
position, the third parameter it takes is
the actual label that we want to give it,
so we're going to say integer or int
sorry, and then height because the height
is equal to you know what point this is
at. So this should be 507, and this would be 609 I
think. So that's the number that the
actual value is, and then we're going to
say horizontal align center, and vertical
align bottom. So now I can run this
method on each one of our data points
here before we
show the grid, so CreateLabels(k1),
CreateLabels(c1), CreateLabels(ch1), and create
CreateLabels(f1). So now when I run the
application we should see that each of
the bars has the exact number
correlating to it's score, and you'll see
right here they are kind of close together.
We could specify you know wider bars in
order to do this, and we might actually.
So let's set bar equal to 2 here, then what
we need to do is to 2, 3, 4, or 2, 4, 6? I think where
it's point .1 we're going to have to do...
yeah 2. So .2, .4, .6,
and .8. That's not right, what am I doing? 2, 4,
and 6, there we go. And these numbers
now fit better in here. We can also
stretch it out make it wider or we could
give a default width as well. So that's
how to add specific numbers to each,
and we could actually put it inside the
bar as well if we wanted to, and we can do
all that sort of fancy stuff with it as
well.