So we've got a functional chart now. If I run
this you'll see that it has specific
numbers, it's got colors, it's got bars,
it's got everything we want, and it's even got
a legend so that we can actually tell
which one is which, which is good but
this overlaps the chart, and so we're
going to be talking in this video a bit
about how to style this legend and how
to move it around. So, for instance, you
can change the edge color and the face
color of this legend just by using those
arguments, keyword arguments. So I'm going
to set the edge color to red so we can
see it clear, and I'm going to set face
color equal to a lighter red. I'm going
to save this and run the application again,
and you're going to see that what it has
done is exactly what I told it to. It's
changed the border color to red and then
the internal color to to a lighter shade
of red, but we don't want to do that. We
want to set the edge color to none, and
shadow to none, we want to set shadow as
well. So shadow equals false. Now if we
reset this, we still got the shadow it looks
like. I'm going to remove face color
here...
it definitely still does have that
shadow there. What we're going to do
we're going to set the frame to none so
basically you can turn on or off the
frame, and the frame is basically the
border of the background and the shadow.
So if I set the keyword frameon to
false, and then restart the application,
you're going to see that now there's
nothing behind it, which is alright
except for the fact that it doesn't look
right. So what we're going to do is
we're now going to change the position
to put it outside that corner, and how
you're going to do that is using the
lok, or the location keyword, and you're
going to use a string or a tuple. So if I
scroll down here you're going to see
these are the codes that you can use. So
you can set location equal to 3, 2, 1, etc.,
and I'm going to set mine to 2, and this
is going to put it outside of the actual
chart, actually inside the actual chart,
because what we also need to do is
bboxed_to_anchor. This one's a little
more complicated but basically it tells
it where to anchor it to. So, bbox_
to_anchor, mine is going to be equal to a
tuple, and this is going to be 1, 1, and
you're going to see that this
combination now puts it outside the
right hand side. So if we look at, where is that,
bbox_to_anchor, so it's a box base
instance. So, left, bottom, width, and height.
So we're not worrying about width and
height at this point, we're worrying about
left and bottom which we're setting. So that's
a little bit about how to modify the
legend, and if you guys want to try out
all of these keywords you definitely can.
You can set the color, the font size, the
marker, you know you can set all those,
the border padding, etc. So, go ahead and
experiment with that and we're going to
be making this chart better
in the next video as well.