Alright guys, so, we're going to start off
with one of the simplest examples that I
can think of, and that is the world
population by year. So,
what I mean by that is basically I went
to Wikipedia and pulled up world
population here, and when you do that
there's a bunch sections and it looks at
different populations differently,
however if you scroll down the page here
to past population it'll show you from
about 70,000 BCE right up to 2015 CE,
and so that's what we're going to be
building out in a line chart with Python.
So how we're going to do that is, let's
open up our IDE, first we need to import
one of the classes that matplotlib
with provides. So, import matplotlib.
pyplot as plt, and using an
abbreviation for plot just because this
class that we're importing pyplot that
has a method called plot, and so I don't
want to call this plot because that
might get a bit confusing. So I'm going
to drag this over here so that I can
actually see the numbers as i write them,
because we need to make two lists. So the
first list is going to be years, and
that's going to be the x axis, and then
we're going to create the actual
population numbers for each point in
years, and that is going to be the y-axis.
So, let's go ahead and create the list
years, and I'm going to go ahead and just
start right from 1 CE right on from
there. So 1000, 1500, and at this point
once you have 1700 it drops in numerical
increments from
100 to 50. So then 750, 1800, 1850, 1900, and
1950, and at this point it drops from 50
year increments to five year increments. So,
1955, 1960, 1965, 1980, 2000,
2005, 2010, and 2015. Alright, so,
let's go ahead and create our y-axis
which will be actual numbers. So, these
are in millions, so in year one there was
200 million people on the planet, and
once we get into billions it represents
it as a thousand million.
So, what we're going to do is we're going
to go along with that, but just so that
you guys are aware this means
3.6 billion, the means 4 billion, etc.
So, pops is going to be our second list, or
our y-axis, so let's go ahead and write
200 million, 400, 458, 580, 682, where was I,
791, 1000 million, that is
1 billion people, 1262, 2525, 2758,
3018. I'm going to
drop down and continue on another line. Where I
was I? Oh, right, 4061...
alright, almost done here. Oops...
Alright, so, these are both of our lists
here, and what we're going to do is we
just need to put both of the lists into
the plot method. So just run plt.plot,
and we're going to put the x axis in
first which is years, and then pops in
second, and then we're going to say
plt.show. I'm going to save it, and then run
the application, and you're going to see
that we get a chart that shows billions
or these are millions rather on the left
hand side, and years on the bottom. And so
you can actually roll your mouse over it
and on the bottom you can get the
coordinates, and you can kind of assume
different things about it. So this is
year 2017 there is 7.3 billion people I
guess, and as we go up we can actually,
can we calculate? Oh, no, we're
going to put points on here so we can
accurately get numbers, but for right now
it's just showing you know where the
mouse cursor is, and x and y on the chart.
So, that's a basic example of what we can
do and we're going to take this example
and we're going to keep adding different
elements to it to you know make it better.