Alright guys, so, what we're going to be
doing in this video is we're going to be
just extending our current graph a
little bit. So the first thing I'm going
to do is I'm going to remove some of
these just so we can focus in from about
1950, right up to 2015, and that's just so
that each increment is the same length.
So let me count how many I'm
removing from this list, and then I'll
remove that many from this list as well.
One, two, three, four...so nine are being
removed here, so one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight, nine. The second thing
I'm going to do is I'm going to turn
these into floats, because we're
going to be talking in billions from
this point on, and then there we go. You
raise the last two digits of each, on
each float here, just to clean it up a bit
and make it look a bit nicer. Alright,
so, I'm going to go ahead and run the
example again here, and we should see a
nicer looking chart, and we do. So you can
see that we went from about about two
billion, or two and a half billion, in
1950 right up to over seven billion in
2015. So that's exactly what we want
to see. There's also built in things here
that you can play around with
if you want. I'm not going to go over
these just because it's you know not
programming, and we are getting into
programming. So, the second thing that I
want to do with this list is I want to
add a color. So the color, the main color
that it drew the line I want it to be a
soft kind of
red, and so how we're going to do that
is we're going to in the plot method
call right here this can take keyword
arguments, and the keyword arguments are
all defined here that we can modify. So
we are going to be looking at this
page a bit as well, but for right now I'm
just going to show you guys how to add a
color. So the color of this line on the
chart is going to be equal to an RGB
color. So, RGB is a color format that
usually looks like this, and 255 is
completely you know right at the top, it
can't go over to 255, and it can't go under
0. So if all three of these values
were zero it would be black, if all three
of them are 255 it will be white, and so
we adjust this is red, this is a green,
and this is blue, and we adjust these to
make different colors. So what I'm going
to do is I'm going to set each one of
these to a hundred except for the red
one, and that's going to add lightness to
the red, and I should get a nice soft red
as the line color here, and I don't, and
the reason is because matplotlibs
plot method doesn't take this kind of
RGB, we need to divide it by 255, and
the reason is, and I'm not even sure
putting the math inside that
color function will work, but it did. Okay,
and as you can see now I've got
a red line, so that's how you can
customize that. Now another thing I want
to talk about is labels, and so what I'm
going to do is I'm going to add a label
on the bottom and along the left-hand
side here. So how I'm going to do that is
I'm just going to target our object
which is plot, and then y label, and I'm
going to set it to Population in
billions,
and then I'm going to skip to the next
line, and plt.xlabel "Population
growth by here" So I'm going to save this
and run it again, and you're going to
notice that we now have nice little
labels so that we can actually convey
the message of what each axis
means in context of our graph, and
pyplot automatically flips the y-axis up
vertically to save space so we don't
have to do anything there. Now another
thing we're going to do is add a title
to the chart. So all you have to do in
that one is plt.title, and we're going to
say Population Growth. Save it and run it
again, now at the top it will say
Population Growth. So, we've
extended this a bit, and we're going to
be extending a lot more, actually. So in
this video we learned how to basically
add RBG colors, and basically what this
means is it takes integers between zero
and one, so this would be 1
(255/255) 255, this would be about
.6 I think, something like that, and this
would be about .6 as well. So
these are floats and integers that go
into the color, and that's how matplotlib
defines colors.