Hey guys, in this video let's just jump to it.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
add another line and so we need to
create two new axes, and so
let's create an axis called deaths. So
we're going to compare the data of
births, or total population, to deaths and
I don't actually have data on this, so
I'm just going to kind of be making it
up. So let's say 1.2, 1.7...
that's four, so I need one more,
and drop down to the next line and I
need to go one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, I need to put nine in there. So, 2.7...and
these numbers are way higher than
actually would be I think.
Let me look one, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, three more, so 3.8,
4.0, and 4.3. So, this isn't
going to do anything as of right now
because i need to actually add another
line here, and how i'm going to do that
is this method right here is what
actually adds the line and configures it,
so I'm going to go ahead and basically
just add this again. So, plt.plot and
then the first one is going to be years
because we're using the same x axis for
this line of data as well. I'm going to say
deaths, and then color, and for this one I'm
going to make it a light blue, so .6,
.6, and 1. And so let's go
ahead and run this example again, and now
you'll see that we have two different
lines, and this would be used to convey
something like the risk of
overpopulation if the population grows,
you can see this is going up higher than
the death rate is, so at some point we're
going to see that
we're creating more people than we're
actually getting rid of. So, yeah, and
then what we could do actually is you
can also modify how the lines are drawn
themselves, and you can also pull the
chart around here by that control right
there. So what I mean by that is you can
add the way that the lines
look by the third parameter here, we can
just pass in like the dash there, two
dashes, and when we run the application
now you'll notice that, that line has
become a dash instead of instead of a
straight line. And so that's how we can
add multiple lines. It's really simple
you just just call the
plot method again and just stuff your
new data into there, and we can even go
further and do it you know multiple
times if we wanted to.