Alright, so, we're going to do things a
little bit differently here, and what I
mean by that is before we
were just calling plt.plot, and
then we were showing it, but in this
video we're going to do things a little
bit differently and that's so that we
have more control, and we have access to
more configurations. So what we're
going to do is we're going to put this
into a variable, we're going to
call lines, and then we're going to stuff
our x and y-axis into here. So it's
going to be years for the x-axis, and
then pops, and then years again, and then deaths.
Now if I say plt.show I don't think
anything is going to happen, ok, actually
it does show it. Ok, cool, so just by capturing
this it's going to show it, but what we
need to do is we need to, well what we
can do is we can use a different method
here and it's called setp. Where's that?
Here it is. So with this we can actually
use all of these arguments that we can
pass in to really customize how it looks.
So, what I'm going to do is just
something quick before I show you guys.
You can set lines equal to, or lines.
grid(True), and this is going to put a grid
on the background of your graph. It's
actually not going to happen...
and as you can see there's now a grid
background so it makes it easier to
find the coordinates of each line. Now
another thing is that you can actually
put different markers at each point, and
we're going to talk about how to get
the data from each marker as we go along
as well, but for right now what we're
going to do is we're going to use plt.
setp, and in here the first argument is
going to be our lines, and then after
here are going to be any of these
arguments that you see on the left hand side.
So, for for example, we're going to say
color, and we're going to say 1,
.4, .4, and this is going to
make both lines red. I believe we can
also pass a list in here where we define
two different colors, and it will use
them incrementally how we're telling
them to. So .4, .4, and 1,
and no, that's not the case.
Color only works with one color which is
strange, maybe I'm missing something.l
Alright, but what you can do is add markers,
and this is going to take a string,
and it means a difference, so you can use
different symbols in here, and each
symbol is going to be used as the marker
at each point where data is contained.
Now aside from what they show you here, I
mean you can use the period and it puts
a little dot there, so these are the
markers that it shows you, but I have also
found that it can do large circles like
dots, I guess, just by using the letter o,
small letter o, and then run the app and
you'll see that now those points are
larger and easier to see. So, you can also
put, I mean you can configure the
marker size, the market color, marker
width, etc. You can do a lot of things
with this. You can configure the line
style, and I recommend really exploring
these different arguments that you can
pass in to the set p method because
that's going to make things a lot easier
as we go along as well.