Alright, guys. What we're going to be
doing in this video is actually making a
pie chart. So let's go ahead and erase
everything we've got here because it's
going to be an entirely different chart
that we're making. The labels that we
want to use, we're going to use sicknesses or
something, let's make a graph of how many
people work in different professions, I
guess. So the labels are going to be, it's
going to be strings, so how many
people in the technology industry...
programming languages let's use that. How
many people in the technology or
programming industry use what type of
programming language. So, let's start with
Python, C++, Ruby, Java, PHP, and Pearl. I
can't remember if they spell pearl like
this or with the a. I think it's like
this but I really don't remember seeing
that any time recently. Alright, and
then we're going to make the sizes of
each one, so this is going to be a list,
and again you can name the variables
whatever you want to just make sure that
what it's time to use them to actually
build the graph that you reference the
correct variables. So Python let's say
there's let's say 10,000 people were, well
let's just say a bunch of people were
surveyed and they gave us these numbers.
So, 33, 52, 12, 17, and I need six different digits, or six different
integers. I need two more so let's say 62 and 48.
So there's my numbers that correspond to
each one of these values,
and how we're going to actually put that
into a pie chart is we're just going to
say plt.pie, and then we're going to pass
in sizes, labels=labels. Now we
should be able to run the plt.show,
and then run the chart and we do see a
basic pie chart, but one interesting
thing is that you'll notice it stretches
from a pie to more of a an egg shape. So,
the way that we fix that
is basically by setting the axis to
equal, so plt.axis, there we go, set it to
equal, and when we run the chart now
you'll see that it always stays in the
same aspect ratio, so it always looks
like a pie. Now, we can do multiple things
with this pie chart to make it easier to
see the data that's contained within
each one. So what we're going to do, and
also as you'll notice it arranges
our pie chart counterclockwise, so if
we start up Python and we go backwards,
then we see what we've got forwards here.
So the first thing I want to do is the
actual percentages from these numbers, so
I want to know what percent exactly that
you know each item is. So we're going to
use the keyword argument autopct, and
we're just going to set it to a weird
little number, and
I'm not sure why we use this I will have
to find out why this works. Anyway, so if
you restart the application it will show
you that 14% of programmers
use Python, or 23% percent of
programmers use C++. Now another thing
that you can do is you can explode
different pieces of the pie outward. So
if we were going to focus on Python here
we should create a variable here called
separated equals, and then this is going
to be a tuple, I'm not sure how to pronounce that.
In python it's essentially the
same as a list but you've got brackets,
and it's used differently in other
contexts, but for right now we're going
to use it as a list. So what we're going
to do is we're going to, this is going to
take the same amount of items as our
list, and the same amount of items as our
labels, we're just going to set zero for
the pieces that we want to be intact,
and then a different number for the
items that we want to be separated. So in
this case we want Python to be separated
so we're going to set that to 1, and
then every other number is going to be
equal to 0. And then the keyword argument
here is explode. So you can see this and
run this again, and you're going to
see that Python is way out here, but we
can make it actually closer by using a
float under one, so let's say .1
rather than 1, and it's going to make
it closer into the pie itself. So you can
actually explode this in different ways
if we wanted this to have .3, 0, and
this one would be 0 as well, and then
.6. So, if we run this our pie
is going to look all messed up like
everyone's had a little piece of it. So
that's a very basic pie chart, and I
think we're going to be exploring this a
bit further in the next video as well.