Alright guys, we're going to break away
from matplotlib here for a few minutes
and we're going to talk about another
library that we're actually going to be
using in conjunction with matplotlib, and
that library is called pandas. So, I've
got a little cheat sheet here which they
have just added I think with their most
recent update of the Python library, and
basically what this does is it
simplifies the process of creating data.
And what I mean by that is you can see
here in the example basically you know
you can create items easier, I guess. So,
I'm going to show you an example of how
to do that, and basically I'm going to
write one the first way without using
pandas, then we're going to install
pandas and see how much quicker it is. So,
doing it this way we're going to assume
that, and this is for the pie chart that
we're going to be creating after
probably in the next video, we're going
to assume that we are working as a data
analyst for a call center that deals
with technical support, and we are going
to have data of completed issues. You
know how when you call into your phone
company or your internet company and you
have a problem, if they resolve the
issue. So we're going to call this
issues resolved. So, normally how we would
do this is we would create a dictionary
and each item in the dictionary is going
to be a person, or something. So, for
instance, name is going to be Nick,
we're going to say January issues
resolved, it's going to be equal to 27
which isn't a lot so let's make that 124.
Feburary issues resolved equals 100,
and it's going to be a quarterly report
so we're going to do March as well.
It's going to be one of the 165. Alright, now
having created this we can then take
this object, and normally we would have
to just write it out multiple times,
actually let me indent this. This for
some reason is indenting with eight
spaces now instead of four, which is not
good. Alright, so now the second person
in here is going to be named, there
straightened that up, is going to be named
Panda. I'm just going to have to use 8
space indentation for now, and
we're going to specify January issues
resolved for Panda, and it's going to be 112.
Feburary issues resolved is going to
be 143, and March she got fired so she
only had 3 issues resolved before
getting fired. And it would take a while
to create an object like this, and we could
create a more programmatic way to do it,
but why should we have to when we can do
it really easily using the pandas
library. So, open up your terminal or
command prompt, type in pip3 install
pandas, I've got mine installed. If you're
on Linux i believe you should just be
using pip depending on your system setup,
not pip3, and then we can actually
import pandas as pd. So, this is the old
way of doing it and if we wanted five
different items here, we would seriously
have to do this, okay, and that takes up
about 30 lines just to create that, and imagine that the data's diffferent. So, what we can
do instead is we can create
a new object where we pass in names, and
then we're going to create a list of
different names. Alright, so now we've got the
five names, then we drop a line and we
say January issues resolved, and then
we're going to create a list and each
one of these is going to correspond to
each person's name. So, 143, 122, 101, 106,
and 365, and then we're going to say
February's issues resolved and we're
going to do the same thing, and then
March issues resolved I'm going to say
65, 88, 12, 32, and 65. Alright, so now what
we've got we've essentially got the same
data in here in four lines of code that
we do here in 30, and that's because we've
simplified it instead of writing each
key you know five times we just write it
once and then pass lists in, and in this
format we can then pass it into pandas
to create a data frame work that
essentially makes this out of it. So I'm
going to show you guys how to do that. So
we're going to create a variable
for the data framework called df, and it's
going to be equal to pd.DataFrame, and
in here we're going to pass in the data
so raw_data, and then we're going to tell
it what columns are what. So, in a list
here names, jan_ir, feb_ir,
and march_ir.
Now this has already created our
object here, so I can go ahead and print
out df, save this and refresh, and
you're going to see that the data has
been printed out in a pretty format. So
we've got a list of names from
the left hand side, and you know it
creates it like this, so each person has
its own row, so we can do really
neat things as though the data were in
this format at this point. So I'm going
to just keep that there, actually. We're
going to add a row to each person called
totals. So, let's go ahead and write df[
'total_ir'] and it's going to be equal to
df['jan_ir'] plus df['feb_ir'] and then
df['mar_ir'] and with just a simple
line instead of putting in a for loop,
which with this I would have to do that.
I'd have to say for person in data,
then i'd have to say person total you
know, and then I'd have to write that
line out and it would have to compute it
for each item in there, but what I can do
here as I save it and it's created
a new column for total that actually
works as a total combined of all these.
So this is a very basic example of
pandas, and we're going to probably be
jumping into this more as well just so
that we can do some really scientific
things apart from charting and stuff, and
we are going to be using pandas a little
bit with making charts. So we're actually
going to do that in the next video in
making a chart for for this data that
we've just constructed right here. So at
this point I can remove this unnecessary
30 lines of code, and just leave this.