Last time on Python Beginner to Advanced...
just kidding, but seriously last time
what we did in here is we used the pandas
library to quickly construct a data
frame that we can then take and use as
though it were a different type of object, and
this basically makes things a lot faster
in compiling and creating data. So what
we're going to do with this at this point
is we are going to create, we're going to
create a pie chart from it. So, first off
what I want to do is talk about colors
and how we can tell each piece of the
pie to have its own color, and that is
simply to create the colors list here
using RGB values, yeah. So, 1, .4, .4
is going to be the first one, that's
going to be a soft red, we're going to
say...
1, .6, 1. Let's say .5, .3, 1, put that in there
as well, I'm just trying to create
regular old items in a list here and
that is not going to work. Let's make a
green one so .3, 1, .5, and then one
more because we have five people that
we're going to be creating the data
for, and so we're going to say
.7, .7, .2, and I'm not
sure what these colors are going to come
out as. I can tell you this one is going
to be red, this one is going to be a
purple. This one is going to be almost
purple like between blue and purple, but
anyway aside from the colors themselves
what we're going to do is we're going to
say plt.pie, and the data that we're
going to be using is this final row that
we've created called total_ir. So, df
['total_ir']
And labels, so we're going to use the
names, so labels is going to be df,
what did we call that, names, colors is
going to be equal to color, and let's do
auto percent as well. So, autopct equals
again this funny string %1.1%%
I'll really have to figure out
why we use that. Then we're going to show
the pie chart. Let's go ahead and start
the app, and there you go. Some of these
colors were completely different from
how I thought they would be. Anyway, I was
way off. Alright, so that's how you can
use pandas with pie charts to make pie
charts, but again we can also do
different things with the pie chart as
well. What we're going to do really the
the only thing we're going to do here is
we're going to set, we're going to set
the access to equal so that it keeps
everything you know looking in the
correct aspect ratio here. So you're going
to create that and there, we've got our data.