Alright guys, so there's a few more
things that I want to cover when it
comes to data visualization, and so this
video is going to be about bar charts,
but it's also going to be about mapping
out some more data than just like
one or two lines. So we're going to be
making a bar chart and the bar chart
we're going to be making is going to be
based on different subjects from school
scores, the average score or country on
these subjects. So what I mean is if I
open up safari here I've got a chart
here that spells out basically the
scores, and we're going to be using the first
column the mean score here, and it's
going to be based on the year 2012. And
we're going to be choosing a few of
these countries and then putting in the
data for each subject here, math, reading,
and science, so that we can visualize it
because having exact numbers is neat but,
this is difficult to read especially
when you're trying to
trace and then compare numbers. A lot of
numbers are similar and that's why that
doesn't really work. Not that it is
impossible or difficult to do, I'm pretty
sure we can all read numbers, however it's
just easier sometimes to take a quick
glance at a chart, and be presented with the
same information just in a more visual
way. So what we're going to be doing here
is first we need to import a few things.
We're going to be using just pyplot
for this I guess, so import matplotlib.
pyplot as plt. We're going to be using
the same thing here, and so let's plot
out some of this data. Let's start with
Korea here, so Korea scores. Now let's go
ahead and create a tuple, and the first
one is 554, that's their
average score at mathematics, and now see
I have to trace the line over in order
to get the correct number, 536
in reading, and then pull this over even more, and then 538
in science. So as you can see it
takes you quite a while to to be able to
grab each number that you want to, and that's
why we're going to be putting this into
a chart. Let's go with Canada. Alright, so,
Canada math is 518, and now I'm going to
trace this again way over here, 523,
and 525, and this is gonna kind of be
boring because this chart is actually
already organized from most to least. So you could
just read the list here and find out you
know who has the higher mean score,
but, yeah. So, let's add in a Shanghai,
China, so China scores. I'm going to create another
tuple, and that's the first row here so it's
going to be easier, 613
for math, 570 for reading, then 580 for
science. And then one more, let's go ahead
with France. So, france_scores, so
we're gonna say math is 495,
reading is 505, and 499. Alright,
so, I've got all my data plotted out here,
well I've got it collected now and
arranged, so what we're going to do is
we're going to, I'm going to show you
guys just one thing printed out, and
we're gonna have a problem when we try
and add a second line. So let's go ahead
and we're going to say k1 equals...we
don't have a lot there so let's go ahead
and include numpy as well. import numpy as np,
and what we're going to do with that is
we're going to create an integer
variable with how many of these values
each item has, or how many columns each
will create, so in this case col_count
equals three, and we're going to need to
use this to manually space
some of our things. And then in order to
iterate to we're going to create a range,
so index equals np.arange, we're
going to pass in the column count. And
now this is going to act as the x-axis
for us, so we don't actually need to
create an x-axis at this point. We're
just going to pass in index, and you'll
see why we're doing this in a moment. Now
what we need to do is pass in the y-axis
which is vertical, so it's Korea stores,
the bar width for right now let's
just leave this as is. Let's drop down
here a few lines and I'm just going to
show the chart, because
this is where we're going to start. So
plt.show. So I'm going to save this and run
the program here, and I don't have
anything happening. Let me find out why,
that's weird. Label is Korea, let's add a
color, so
.3, .3, .7...
...
Okay, something terrible just happened,
and I can't figure this out. Okay, let me
see what's wrong. I'm going to erase this
because something went terribly wrong
there, and I'm going to redo this. Korea
scores, and then the bar width let's set
to .5 right now, and now let's drop down
here and put color. Why is it doing that,
when I'm trying to add the color? Oh, okay,
well I feel a bit silly right now. I'm
just creating a
tuple here, I'm not actually creating a
chart, so obviously this is a method of
the plt class or object that we're using
right now. So, plt.bar and that's where
we pass in all these variables, and
that will actually create the charts. Now
if I start it you will see this chart
right here. We're going to add a grid
just so that we can better identify between
the different subjects. So plt.grid is
going to be true. Now when I restart this
we're going to see a grid on the
background there. Makes it easier to find
out what goes where.