Hello everyone and welcome to the Python course that we're going to be doing. My
name is Nick and i'm going to be the
instructor for this course, and it's
going to be my job to get you completely
immersed in the Python programming
language. Now, this course is going to be
aimed at somebody who may have basic
knowledge about what a programming
language is but this would be your first
programming language, and this is a great programming language to start with. It
does have some limitations and sometimes this is not the right tool for the job,
but a lot of times this offers people
who have no experience programming a
really great way of understanding what a
programming language is and how to use
one. So, the main differences between
Python and other languages like C++, or C,
or Java is that Python is built around
two main focal points which I believe
are code readability and simplicity. So,
we're gonna jump into the
language here and in a few videos but we
need to do a few things first. First we
need to discuss what Python is, and then
we need to get it installed, and then we
can start discussing you know what's an
interpreter, how do you run a
Python script, and then get into the
language itself. Now, the language is
different but it's easy, and once we get
past an understanding of how the
programming language works, and the
syntax, and all the different stuff you
do with it,
we're going to move on to actually
programming real applications and
showing you guys different practical
applications of the python programming
language. So, for instance, we're going to
be building a website,
we're going to be building a web scraper,
and a graphical utility we're actually
going to be building multiple graphical
tools because there are a few different
graphical or GUI, GUI, whatever you want
to call it there's a few different
frameworks for Python that we could use.
So we're going to explore three of them. So,
right off the bat here's a fun fact if
you didn't know python is actually named
after Monty Python who's made some great films, so if you if you haven't seen
Search for the Holy Grail or the Life of
Brian go do it,
they're great movies, which is completely
beside the point.
So, Python is actually a pretty old
programming language. It was first
introduced in 1991 which makes it 25
years old.
There's two current versions, now this
may be confusing as well, so there's a
Python 2 series and there's a Python 3
series. The Python 2 is currently at 2.7.11
and the 3 series is at 3.5.1. Now we're going to be
using Python 3 in this course however
Python 2 shouldn't be much different if
afterwards you want to explore using
Python 2 that's completely acceptable.
Now as I said Python is based around
simplicity and readability and this
means that when you look at Python code
it's all indentation based. So, if you
looked at another code like Java you would see a lot of curly braces, and brackets, and a
lot of things that are just there to
confuse the the novice programmer. Python
is based on indentation so you don't
need to wrap blocks of code in curly
braces and you guys will see what I mean
coming up in the next few
videos. So, that's all we're going to talk
about today. I hope you guys enjoy this
course and find it useful.