So, the first thing that we need to do to
get into programming in Python is
installing it.
So, let's go ahead and discuss about the
three different ways that you're going
to be installing it.
First, we're going to cover Mac because
that's what i'm using and so it's
easiest to show you how to do it. So, what
you're going to do is open up terminal
which I've moved into that folder and put
right here. Now, if you haven't installed
Homebrew, what you're going to do is run
a Ruby command that's going to download
and set it up. So, basically what Homebrew is, is a package manager that you
can use to install a lot of packages. So,
if you're used to Linux basically on
Linux if you want to install a package
you don't need to go all around the
internet and search for packages on
websites and then download from shady sources
and get viruses, that's just a bad
construct of computer operating systems,
but unfortunately that's how Windows
works and so i'm going to show you guys
the right way to install in Windows as
well. Using Linux or OS 10 you're going to
be installing through terminal. So, first
setup Homebrew, this is how you do it,
come to brew.sh and it's going to
give you this line of code here. You just
paste this in terminal, run it, it's going to
install brew. Once you've got brew
installed what you're going to do is run
"brew install python" Now that's how easy
it is.
OS 10 does ship with a version of Python
but the the version included
in OS 10 is 2.7 series and I think
it's actually an old really something
that's like to 2.7.5 or something like
that so it's pretty old.
At least I think it was that. We can
actually run "--python version" here, so okay
so the version that OS 10 El Capitán
ships with is 2.7.10. When you run brew
install Python it's going to install
python 3,
that's the command that we're going to
have to be using because there's already
a Python version installed, so we're
going to be using Python 3 and you can
check the version we've got 3.5.1 that's the version that
homebrew is going to install for you. Now
similarly if you're on Linux what you
would do
there's a few different ways because
there's a few different package managers.
So if you're on Arch Linux I don't think
you're gonna need help setting it up, and
actually a lot of Linux distributions
have Python/Python 3 pre-installed, so
you can just run "python --version" and "python3 --version"
and see what version you have installed,
you might need to upgrade, it it might be
fine. If you have 3.4 you can follow
along with this course I don't think
there's that many differences between
the two versions and there's definitely
not code-breaking differences, so that
shouldn't be a problem.
However, if you do notice that you're
having a problem you could upgrade
the version of Python either through the repository or otherwise. If you're on Ubuntu you're
gonna be using the apt-get command, so
you'd run "sudo apt-get install
python3" That's going to install
Python 3 for you. If you're on Fedora I
believe it used to be yum, I think it's dnf
now.
Yeah, so let's just review exactly what
commands you're going to be using, I
think it's like dnf install.
So, you can still use yum I guess, ok so you can use yum to install. So, what
you're gonna do is we're gonna run "sudo
yum install" and then I believe the
package is just called python3, Python 4 is going to be pretty amazing but
right now we're using Python 3. So,
there we go. Now if you're on Arch
and I said I don't think you need any
help getting it setup but just for you
know if you are new to Arch you'd run
"sudo pacman -S python3" but
again
python3 should be pre-installed, so you
shouldn't even need to do any of this
but if you do that's gonna do it. Now on
Windows you do need to go download a
file from the internet and run it, the
the difference between what I said
before what I'm saying now is this is
not a shady location. So, what you're
going to do is go to python.org, go to
the download sections, and if you just
hover over this it's actually going to
show you a drop-down and you can choose
what platform you're on. So you would
choose windows and they actually have a
3.6 which we're not going to we're not
going to be using because this is in
alpha. So,
click latest python3 release python 3.5.1, it's going to take you to this page
and basically give you a changelog and
whatnot.
If you go down here make sure you get
the version that's compatible with your
system. If you have a computer that is
not obsolete it should be running a 64-bit
operating system which means it has a
64-bit processor. S,o you would download
this one right here,
Windows x86 64 executable and what
that's going to download is an .exe file
which you can use to install the
program. If you're running a 32-bit
system you're going to download this one
just the x86, and yeah just install it.
Now, there is one note on the
installation, when you run the
installation there's going to be a
certain step where you have some
checkboxes and one of them is going to
say add python to the path variable, make
sure that's checked because if it's not
checked if you try to run Python in the
command line you won't be able to
because it won't know where to find this
mysterious Python command. So, by
checking that box basically it tells
windows where the Python binary file is
located,
so you want to make sure Windows is
aware of where that file is. And that's
all there is to installing it. To confirm
that you've got it installed open up a
command prompt to terminal and just type Python3 and it should drop you down into
the interpreter, which we're going to be
discussing in the next video.