So the interpreter, and this is going to
be a short video I think, but we're
basically going to talk about the
difference between an interpretive
programming language and a compiled
programming language. So, first, with a
compiled programming language you write your code and you save it into this file,
and you can't run that file yet.
Let's say you're writing C++ code. So you
write a function, you write a script that
will do something, if you try and open
that file with the .cpp extension.
which is for C++ files. it's just going
to open that in a text editor or code
editor because that's not an executable
file. What you need to do with a compiled
programming language is once you save
your file you need to compile it into a
language that the computer can read, so
binary with the ones and zeros. And by
compiling this file into an
executable file, then you can double
click it and it will run. So if you're on
Windows building executable files for
Windows they will have a .exe
extension. If you're on Linux I don't
believe they have an extension. So the
difference here is with python when you
write a script you can instantaneously
run that script without having to
compile it into binary, and
because we can do that what's actually
happening is when you run the Python
command you're not running the file
standalone. So when you compile a
programming file into a binary file,
you can just type the name of that file
in the terminal command prompt, and hit
enter, and it will run that program as a
standalone program because the
computer already knows how to run it. But,
when you run python scripts you're going
to run it with the python command, and
then the name of the file. And what
basically happens is you're running the
program python which is interpreting
your code and running that. So, what
happens is it does compile into binary but it's
called just-in-time compilation, and what
that does is every time you run it it's
going to parse all the code, and it's
going to convert it into a temporary
file, and then run that temporary file. So,
let me break out of this...there. So how
you would run a script, and we're going
to talk about that later,
but basically how to enter the
interpreter on it's own you just type
python3. to use the 3 version of Python.
You can see the version we're using
Python 3.5.1. So, basically, in the
interpreter you can run real time code.
So if I were to type print("Hello World")
it's going to instantaneously run that
line of code. If I run 4 + 6 it's
going to return 10, because that's the
sum of 4 and 6. And so the interpreter is
great to use if you want to test
something really quick, if you want to
debug a few lines code, or if you just
want to see if something would actually
work. So we're going to be starting using
the interpreter, but as things get a
little more complex we're going to get
into writing scripts and executing those
scripts. So, now we need to learn how to
run a Python script.