So, let's go ahead and create a Python
script and learn how to run it. So, i'm
going to be doing this in terminal
completely we will discuss other options
later, what I need to do first is change
directory into "pycharm projects" and
there's nothing really in here so i'm
going to create a file using the nano
text editor, you guys don't have to
follow along,
however if you want to that's great too.
I'm just going to call it test.py. Now
all Python scripts need to have the .py
extension. So, what we're going to do is
just a simple, simple script it's going
to print "hello world"
So, I'm going to control +
O to save, and control + C to exit, control + X to exit.
Alright, now if we just type "test.py"
you'll see BASH doesn't know what to do
with this command because test.py is
not an installed program. So what we need to do is run "python3 test.py" and it will
return the result of anything in that
script. So, that's how to run python
scripts, in the next video what we're going to be doing is setting up an actual work
environment using an IDE, and get you
guys all ready to start with the basics.