Hey guys, welcome back. I wanted to take
this opportunity to help you guys let us
help you,
and so basically when you're picking up
a programming language, or just the
programming skills in general,
you're going to have problems and you're
gonna do things incorrectly most likely,
hopefully not if I've done a good job at
explaining things you shouldn't, but even
still you most likely will make some
small problems. In PHP it's common that a lot of beginners, well actually a lot of
advanced programs as well,
will face eventually the fact that their
troubleshooting a problem for eight
hours and pulling their hair out and
then they realize that the problem was
just that they missed a semicolon on line
56, and luckily with Python we're not
going to have that problem with the
semicolon,
however a lot of the problems that you
might encounter are likely going to be
very simple like that, and so I want to
show you guys a way to let us help you
better and also for you guys to help
each other. When you have a problem with
your code and you want it reviewed or
want someone to look at it and see if they
can find the problem because sometimes
looking at your own code for a really
long time trying to find a problem
you're looking at it too close,
you need to stand back, and sometimes you just can't get the proper perspective to
figure out the problem yourself. So, you
guys are going to have to share your
code in the discussion to the right of
this video you're gonna you know
basically say hey I got a problem with
this, this is what I'm trying to do, but you're
also going to include a link to pastebin. So, if you guys don't know what
pastebin is it's pastebin.com, and you
basically come here and you're going to
copy and paste your code in here. Now
also you have a way to highlight for
certain syntax, in this case it's going to
be Python. Paste exposure should be
public or unlisted basically if it's
unlisted anybody that you give the link
to will be able to view it and
you can also title it, and then you just
create the new post, and then it's going
to give you a URL. So, I'm just gonna do
this really quickly so that you guys can
have an example.
So, i'm going to write out a simple
line of code here that wouldn't work, it
wouldn't do anything, but then i'm going
to share it. You can set expiry so just
leave this to never, paste exposure can
be public or unlisted, and you can give
the name "problem instantiating
webpy" and I have selected the
syntax highlighter of Python because
that's the programming language we're
using, and then just click create new
paste. Now as you can see it did syntax
highlight it, it gives it line numbers
and everything, you can download it, you
can clone it, etc. Now all you need to do
to share is just come up to the address bar
here and just copy this, and you're going
to put that link in the discussion
section to the right of the video so
that when we look at the problem that
you're having we can come here and see
your code, and we can tell you okay well
the problem is on line 12, and this is
what's wrong with it, and then you can
modify it accordingly.
Now this also allows it to we can copy
this into our own code editors and then
run your program on our computer just by
copying the text, so that's going to be
helpful as well. So, thank you guys for
watching this video and for joining this
course, and i'm excited to get started.
This is going to be fun!