Alright, so before we actually get into
functional programming, or object
oriented programming for that matter,
with Python we need to discuss some
basic types, and then variables, and some
other stuff. So in this video we're going
to be covering numbers. So, what is a
number? Well, i'm sure you guys know what
a number is and I'm sure we've all been
through grade primary and one so we're
all familiar with that. Now there's two
different types of numbers, one is called
an integer, and then a floating point. The
floating point is basically any number
that has a decimal included in it. So
let's go ahead and write out some
numbers on the screen. Now i'm going to
be using the Python console down here
for this video so watch down there,
that's where stuff is going to happen. So,
for an instance of a number we can just
write a number, it's going to appear in
the console, or the ID, or whatever you
know has syntax highlighting that you're
using it's going to show as blue or it should you know, actually that really depends
on your color scheme that you've got
going on, it's going to show a specific
color. Now, we can just use numbers in
Python just by writing the numbers and
if we hit enter it's going to print out
5. Now with numbers we can perform
mathematical operations on these numbers as you saw in some of the previous
videos that we've done so far. So I could
write 5 + 6 and we're going to get a
response of the sum of 5 + 6. Now
what would happen if I wrapped these
numbers in quotations? So let's go ahead
and write "5 + 6" if you think
that this will produce 11, you're wrong,
It's going to produce 56, and you might
be thinking, hold up, 5 + 6 does
not equal 56.
You're absolutely right. Not in math,
however when you're concatenated strings it does. So basically when you wrap
something in quotations in Python,
Python is going to treat it as a string,
not a number. So if you're trying to
perform mathematical operations just
remember don't wrap your numbers in
quotations. Now additionally we can use
floating points to perform math
operations, and you can see it returns a
floating-point. Now if we ran 5.5 + 5.5
it's going to still return a floating
point, however you know
it's 11.0 because we've passed it,
you know, decimal floating-point
numbers and so it's going to return with
one because that's just how it works. Now, we're going to talk about how to convert
different types of types, I guess. These are called types. A
number is a type, a string is a type, and
right here we've got, we've shown, both
numbers and strings and we're going to
cover strings in the next video, but for
right now let's say well I have some
numbers but they're wrapped in
quotations and I still want to perform
mathematical operations on them, how can I do
that? So, basically in Python there's a
built-in function called int which will
convert a string to a number if that
string contains only numbers. So let's
look at a correct usage of int and then
an incorrect usage and see the output
for both. So let's say I have the number
"5" wrapped in quotations, what I'm going to
do is wrap that in the int function and
this is also how you write a call to a
function
in Python, and then i'm going to perform
a mathematical operation on it with
another number wrapped in quotations. Now this is not going to produce 57, in fact
it's going to convert both of those into
integers and then perform the math
operations on them. So that's how to add
up different numbers that are contained
within quotations, let's have a look at
trying to convert text to an integer. So
let's write "int" and let's write
"(hello)" and hit enter. As you can guess it's printing out an error because
there's an invalid literal for int with
base 10. Basically, what that means is
we've passed it something that is not an
integer. So think of this function
basically as it takes whatever you put
into the function, it removes the
quotations, and then returns that. Same if
I just type this, Python is going to
freak out because it doesn't know what
hello is because this is going to be
interpreted not as a string, but it's
going to be interpreted as computer code,
and we're going to get more into strings
in the next video.