Alright guys, welcome back. In this video
we're going to expand on this function
here and we're actually going to implement arguments into the function. So what
this means that this is very static right now, nothing would change this even if we
wanted to change it. I could call this
function let's say 10 times and each
time it's going to print out very static
strings. So how we can change this to
make it more dynamic is by using
arguments and the arguments again go in
the brackets here at the end of the
function name, and what you're doing is
creating a variable so we don't even
need to know the value that's being
passed in we just let's decide to use
two arguments here in this function, and
each one is going to be used in its own
print statement. So we're going to name
it "str1, and str2" there and this
basically we've abbreviated string 1 and
string 2. It also tells us right now
it's not being used.
You're going to find PyCharm pretty
smart. So what we're going to do is
change this line of code to print out
string 1, we're going to use this print
statement to print out
string 2. Let's go ahead and save it and
run it.
We're going to get an error and the
reason is because we're calling this
function without passing anything into
it, and it actually tells us right here
parameter string 1 unfilled. So it knows
that this function is looking for two
values here separated by a comma, one of them is string one and one of them is
string two, we haven't passed anything
into it so it's calling this function
and immediately the function is freaking
out saying I can't find this information.
So what we need to do is pass in two
strings here and how we do that is
similar to how it looks in here except
each one is going to be the value and
not the variable name. So, the first
one is going to be called "This is
argument 1",
"This is the second argument which is
also a string.")
Now if we save, go-ahead run,
you're going to see that this is now
printing out string 1 as defined right
here, and string 2 as defined right here.
So, why would we need to do this? Well,
let's say we're always going to want to
print out two things.
Let's go ahead and call the function
again, but this time we're going to pass
in different strings. Let's fall back to the
good ole hello world. Now we're going to
save this and what's gonna happen is it's
going to print out four lines. It's
going to print out "This is argument 1",
"This is the second argument which is
also a string." being called from the first call of that function, and then "Stringy" , "Hello World"
from the second call that function and
so that's how to use arguments. Now in
the next video we're going to be
discussing keyword arguments and what
those are.