Alright guys, in this video we're going to
be talking about arguments a little
further, we were going to move onto
keyword arguments but before we do that
it's going to make more sense to cover
default arguments first. So, let's go
ahead I've cleared out my script here I
suggest you guys do the same just for
repetition. I mean you could remodel your
current function to work with this,
however repetition is the key to mastering
something. So let's go ahead drop down
two lines, define a new function, we're
going to name it "print_something" and it's going
to take two parameters, one is going to
be "(name, age)"
let's open that with a ":" and print out
one string which we're going to
concatenate with name and age. So "My name is name " + name + " and my age is " + age"
Now we're going to go down here and call this function "print_something("Nick" , 27)" I'm
sure you guys already see a problem with
this, so I'll give you props for that because
this is not going to work,
that's exactly why I'm showing you. We're
going to run it amd it's going to say that it
"Can't convert 'int' object to a str implicity" Now there's a few different resolutions to
this, one I've already shown you, you can
just wrap this in a string. Now you can run
it and it will work. Now, this is why I
mentioned this earlier because you can
definitely do this, however what we're
going to do is instead of concatenating
the string we're going to remove all these
extra characters, we're going to separate
things by a comma, going to
remove the extra spaces around the text
as well because we don't need them and
you'll see why. Now this will work
without converting this integer to a
string, and the reason is because when we use commas it just says print out
these four things one after another.
We don't need to concatenate different
pieces of data, it's actually printing
out a different number of things. So, it's
going to print this out as a string, it's
going to print this out as a string
because we're passing it in as a string. This
is going to be printed out as a string
and this is going to be printed out as
an integer, however when I save it here
and run it you won't know the difference.
See it says my name is Nick and my age 27. You don't notice that this is an int so
this is a perfectly acceptable way to do
that. Now, what if I only wanted to pass
it one argument? What we can do
there is we can create default arguments.
Actually, let's pass in "Nick" So, let's go
ahead and change these to accommodate
only passing in some of the values. So,
what we're going to do is set a default
value and how you do that is inside the
parameter list of the function you're
going to assign values to these
variables. These are just variables that
you're creating right here, so you can
create a variable and assign a default
name, and then same with age. You're going to assign a default age which we're
going to say is "Unknown" Now we're going to save it. Now when I run this what we have
here is my name is Nick and my age is unknown because I'm only passing in this.
So what happens is you think well,
shouldn't name equal someone? It
would if I didn't pass anything in so we
can do that as well. We're going to save
this
and run it and it's going to say my
name is someone and my age is unknown
because we're not passing in anything.
However, we're going to pass in the first
argument here and this is going to take
priority over this value here. This
basically means this variable is going
to be equal to someone, if no value is passed
in.
Age is going to be equal to unknown, if
no value is passed in for it. So, that's
how to use default arguments in
functions. In the next video we're going
to be talking about passing in specific
parameters by using keyword
arguments.