Alright guys let's go ahead and talk
about an infinite number of arguments
being passed into a function. So what
we're going to do is define a function
called "print_people" and here's where
we're going to pass in the the arguments
for a function but we don't know how
many were going to get, we may get 3,
we may get a 100. So what we're going
to do is start off we're going to only
pass one argument into this function and
that's going to begin with an "asterisk" and
this "*" tells this argument that it's
going to be an array of all of the
arguments that are passed into the function, so you're going to see more how this
works in a moment. Now with an array we
need some way to loop over it and so
we're going to be using a for statement
and we're going to go more into this in
the future, but for right now all you need to know is you're going to write "for person
in people:" and you're going to notice
that when i drop down to the new line
after putting the colon here it further
indented my code which means what I'm
writing here is going to be a different
block, it's going to be one level deeper
than right here so, and that's not sure
why that's underlying red maybe because
it's expecting me to type something here.
So what I'm going to do is "for person in
people:" I'm going to "print("This
person is" ,  person)" there we go. So that's our function, we're done with that.
Basically how a for loop works is this
is a list or an array as we're defining
right here. This is going to take in all
of the values we're passing to this
function and create a list called people.
Now you can iterate over the people list
by using a for statement, so for person
in people and this person can be any you
could write this for item in people, but
where we are using the variable name
person that is going to be available in
this block of code
as the next person in the list and so
you guys are going to see how this works.
Again if you're familiar with other
programming languages this is not a new
concept, it's just a slightly different way
of doing it
Let's go ahead and call the function
"print people" and let's pass it some
names so "("Nick" , "Dan" , "Jack" , "King" , "Smiley")" I'm not even sure if this
is a real persons name but we're going
to pass it into this function anyway. So
what we're doing is we're passing in 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 arguments. Now if we
knew we were always going to expect five
arguments we could accept each
individual argument as its own variable,
however we don't so we're capturing all
these, we're going to create an array out of
them, and the array is going to be stored
in the variable called people. So we're
going to run this and you're going to see
that for each person it prints out this
person is and then the name of the
person. So that's how to include an
infinite number, or a flexible, it's not really infinite eventually if
you were going to pass in an infinite
amount of parameters you would never be
done with your program, you could pass it on to your descendants they would never be
done, and so on. This is truly a flexible
number of arguments. So, with that being
said we're all done with that. In the
next video we're going to be discussing
return values and then we're going to
build a calculator.