Alright guys, this is the last video in
the subsection for functions and we're
going to be talking about return values
from functions. So, again this is not new
to some of you, to some of you it is, so
if I mean it's a pretty basic concept
basically in the past we've created
functions that do something in which
case each time the function was called
it printed something to the screen
because inside that function that's what
we've done, we've told it to print. But,
what if we want to return a value from
the function and don't want to print it
out and do something else with it? So
let's go ahead and define a function,
call it "do_math" and define two variables
"(num1, num2)"
It's going to be a very simple function
here, and we're going to "return num1 + num2"
Now, if we call "do_math" and pass in
"(5, 7)"
it's not going to do anything because
we're not printing anything out, right. So
what we could do is actually let's
create a variable called "sum1" or
rather "math1" and this variable is
going to include the sum of the two
numbers that we pass in. So we're going
to call it a second time as well,
"math2 = do_math(11, 34)" and we're
going to save it. Now when I run this
function, or when I run this script, again
nothing happened because we haven't done
anything with it yet. So what we're going
to do now is print out both results in
one print statements. So we are going to say "print("First sum is", math1
"and the second sum is", math2)"
So we save this and hit the the run
button you'll see that the first sun is
12 and the second sum is 45. So
let's go over this again
so you guys, I'm not sure if I've
explained it well enough so i'm going to
do that again. We're defining a function,
we're calling it do math, and we're
passing in number 1 and number 2, so
there's two arguments going into this
function. Inside this block of code we
are only returning the sum of num1
and num2, so in the case of the first
sum it's going to be 12. So we are
returning to whatever part in our code we're at,
so this is going to become 12. So math1
is equal to 12 and then math2
we're going to call that function again
we're going to pass 11 and 34 in and
again it's going to return to the spot
right here with the value that we tell
it to return with. So this line of code
right here is going to become 45, so math2
equals 45. Then what we do we just
print it out and math1 knows that it's
45 because that's what the result of
that function is, and so this is going to
be useful for a lot of reasons later on
in programming. So in the next video
we're going to create a calculator using
Python and it's going to be a
command-line tool, so we'll be able to
run it and perform different math
operations.