Alright, so let's discuss lists and what
they are in Python. So, let's open up
terminal again and launch a Python 3
console. So, if you do have experience
with programming in other languages,
let's say PHP, you know how to create an
array and what an array is. For anybody
else it's a way to to keep data organized
and within one construct. So we're going
to go ahead and define an array and how
we do that Python is just open up and
close square brackets, and then in them
we're going to have some items and those items are going to each have their own
index number within the array. So, let's
say we're making a list of things that I
like. I'm going to type "["Movies", "Games", "Python"]" Now what this
becomes is a list that has three indexes
and we saw earlier when we split a
string apart that created one of these
and so you guys already know how to
access items within this array, however if
you forgot we're going to go ahead and
do that. So, basically I can put an index
of 0 "[0]" and it's going to print out movies.
Now if we put that in a print statement,
we're going to concatenate it, "print("I Like" +"
Alright, we're gonna get there so...let's
go ahead and print this out it says "I like
movies" if we change that index number [1] it'ss going to say "I like games" and if I
change that to [2],
oh not 3, so "I like Python" as well.
Now what happens if one of these are a
number? Let's say I replace this with the number 16,
let's say "I like 16" go ahead and change
this index to "[1]" then hit enter. It can't
convert the integer to string. So what we
would do is if we were trying to print,
and this specifically printing out an
array and then choosing an index that
time of recreation or list, that's
impractical and we're never going to do
things that way. So, what we just saw
this error message doesn't really matter.
Basically again if you're trying to
concatenate strings with an integer it's
gonna freak out because it doesn't know
how to do that. So that is what a list is,
it's just a way to to create a collection
under one variable name and when we
discuss variables we will revisit this
so you guys can see what i mean. In the
next video we're going to be talking
about dictionaries, and basically these
are like in JavaScript you can create
JSON objects and that's basically what
they are. So, let's get into that.