So let's get into dictionaries and
that's gonna end the subseries I guess
of types, this is going to be the last
type that we're going to talk about. So
let's go ahead and open up a terminal
here and jump into Python. Now the
previous video when we created a list we
used square brackets and we entered
comma-separated values in there which
became our list,
however in order to create a dictionary
we're going to open up sand close curly
brackets here. Now in a previous video I
told you guys that we don't use curly
brackets in Python and that was a lie,
and just so you know there's going to be
a few of those throughout this course, so
keep your eyes open for them. What I meant to
say, and just to clarify, you don't wrap code blocks in curly brackets like you do in
PHP and JavaScript. Instead the only use
that Python has for curly brackets is to
define a dictionary. So, rather than
entering comma-separated values we're
going to enter comma for separated
values but each one of those is going to
be a key and a value, so let's go ahead and create one. Let's create a person so the name is
going to be  and that
becomes our dictionary. Now, again, you can...you can access, I had tried to do that
the JavaScript way here which you put a
dot and then the name of the key that
you're looking for,
in Python you do it like this kind of
like when you define an index number
here. If you were to do this it wouldn't
be able to find it because it's not a
list but with an array we would have
done that, in here we just type
the name of the value we want. So name is going to print out "Nick" if we put in age
that's going to print out "27" and if we
enter hobby that's going to print out
"code" and so that's how to define a
dictionary and how to retrieve certain
values from the dictionary.
This is also going to become a very
useful later on once we get to, well once
we get JSON itself because we are going
to do a video on JSON, but also once we
start once we start working with a lot
of data some of it's, some
of it we're going to explicitly convert
into JSON data just so we can parse it
like this because this is one of the
easiest ways to parse data is using
this form. So thanks for watching this
video and I hope you guys enjoyed it.
This ends the sub section of types and
in the next video we're going to be
learning about variables.