Alright guys, we are going to talk about
some built-in functions before we move
on, and then we're going to get onto
defining our own functions, and the
different parts of a function. So, let's
go ahead and open up a terminal here. I
want you guys to loosely follow what I'm
doing here so that you guys can get used to
using these functions which I think
we're going to be using some of them
quite a bit and you're going to be using
some of them quite a bit once you, once
you're done this course. So these are
some basic, very basic, functions that we
need to learn about, we're not going to
go through any modules like the
math module or anything like that,
we're just going to go through a few
basic functions. So let's jump into a
Python console here and we've already
learned about a few so they're just
going to get a quick mention here. You
can print out on the screen in
the terminal, whatever you you want to
basically use the print command, you can
convert things to a string using the str
function, and you can do this for both
integers and floating points, and
actually booleans,
and then for each of these types you can
also convert them to their own types if
they are a string. So I can use int here,
and it's going to convert that to an
integer. I could use int that...oh sorry
"flo("5.6")" I can use float to convert 5.6 to an
actual number, and then you can perform
mathematical operations on if you want.
Now, let's say we have a string like true,
and we want to convert that to a boolean
to actually be able to test things with
it. What we would do is type "bool("True")" and there we
go that's going to convert that to a
boolean operator.
Now let's also talk about a command
called "len" Basically, what this is is
it's going to determine the length of
something so it can work with arrays
and strings. So let's go ahead and try
and figure out how long "len("Hello")"
Hello is which means how many characters are in this, and there are 5. Now this
command can also be used on an array. So "len([1, 2, 6, 3, 4])" just a few random numbers in
there and it's 5 digits long. Now also
if you were put strings in here
each with different a number of characters, you would see that this is still going
to be equal to the number of items and
not the number of characters within each
item. So that's how to calculate the
length of an array. Now another thing
you can do with an array that's pretty neat is sort the array. So let's go ahead
and create an array which is let's say
we're going to put some random numbers
in here in you know
no specific order
there "[16, 3, 8, 6, 9, 133, 435, 21, 823, 45]"
Now as you can see this is incredibly
random but let's say that we wanted to
sort the array into lowest to highest, or
you know first to last. What we would do
is actually wrap it in a function called
"sorted" and this will shift around the
array until all numbers are in
ascending order. Now let's do the same
with an array with strings instead. So
let's create some letters here,
"sorted(["B", "R", "a", "N"])"
couple issues with that line of code there. So it sorts it but as you'll
notice the "a" is at the end. Well, why did
that happen? If we were to capitalize
it the "A" would that be at the beginning.
So, again if we turn some of these
letters into lower case which obviously
come before other letters here, and one
more, you can kind of see how it's
working. The capital letters are parsed
first because that's just the way
it works, and then lower case letters,
what if we threw a number in
there? You'll see that it can't do
that,
so what you would have to do is wrapping
quotes and let's throw another number
right here, and a floating-point
wrapped in quotations, and you're going
to see that the way this sorted is it put
numbers first regardless of if it's a
floating-point or integer type. They have
to be wrapped in quotations in order to
be sorted with other strings in an array, and then it parses the capital alphabet
and the the lowercase alphabet, so that's
kind of a priority order there. Just so
you guys are aware of that.
So what we're going to do next is
actually explore functions, this was just
a few basic building commands in Python
that we are going to use through the
rest of the course, and we're probably going to, well we definitely are going to, find
other built-in functions as we move
along, as we need them. So let's get into
functions.