Alright, just needed to close that file.
What we're going to do, we're going to
get rid of some of these, we don't need
them anymore, I want to keep our first
program though. Let's go ahead and create a new project, we're going to call it
battle. We're just going to use the
default interpreter which should be 3.5.1
if it, if it's not you know if
it's not the 3 than you know
go for it. Looks like this is actually
the name of another another project that
I had, so what I'm going to do is I'm
going to delete all this so we can get
started again, there. So let's go ahead
and create, first we're going to build
out some class definitions, we need a few
of those. So let's go ahead and create a
directory called classes. Then in here
we're going to create that blank Python
file called "__init__" close that right away,
don't need that. Going to create another
Python file called "game" So in this game.py file what we're going to define
are two classes, one of them is going to
be colors class which is going to
provide the ability to use colors inside terminal, and then the
second class is going to be person which
we're going to be using both for enemies
and ourself, our own player character.
So let's go ahead and start the defining of
classes. I actually have the class b
colors here and i've copied this because
I don't know any of these off
by hand, but this basically assigns
variables to two colors that we can use
in terminal. So what we're going to do is,
I'm just going to erase this, I will also
provide this in my,
I'll provide that in the code that
I host on git, there, that was just some weird
indentation from another program, I guess. So, let's go ahead and get started with a person
class. So let's drop down here to define
another class called person "class Person:" and right
off the bat we know we're going to need
to initialize this class or the
object from this class with a few
parameters. So think of these typically i
guess we'll think of these as stats. So, if
you've ever played a role playing game
we're going to need hitpoints, we're
going to need attack power, defense ,magic
magic points, etc. So let's go ahead and
let's "def __init__(self):" and what
we're going to pass it is "(self, hp, mp atk,
df magic):" and what we're going to do
is we're going to set "self.maxhp = hp" and the reason why we're
setting max HP and HP separately "self.hp = hp"  is because, this one is think of that is
current hitpoints so, as we go through the battle this is going to change, but we also
always want to be aware of what our
maximum hit points are, we don't want to
over heal. So if we set the hit points
to 300 and then we heal and ends up
going to up to like 450 or something, we
don't want to allow that so we set a
maximum right there, and you guys
will see how we're going to use this. So
let's go ahead and set "self.maxmp = mp" "selfmp = mp" and we're just
setting a bunch of instance variables
here. Now we're going to set attack high
and attack well based on what's passed
in as attack, minus and plus 10. So,
there we go. "self.atkl = atk - 10" "self.atkh = atk +10"
And now we need to set the defense, magic, and some actions. So, self-defense "self.df = df"
"self.magic = magic" and the magic object that's being passed it's just going to be a
dictionary of different magic spells
that we have and their MP cost.
We're going to need actions "self.action" so this is what's going to be displayed
every time it prompts us to take a turn.
So for right now it's just going to be
"= ["Attack", "Magic"]"
there we go. Now we're going to have to
create some utility methods here to, to
handle different actions that we can
anticipate are going to be in the battle.
So we want our player and the enemy to
be able to take damage. So in order to
generate the damage, much like we did I
believe in one of the previous videos, we
are going to use random. So what we're
going to do here is "import random" spelled that
wrong. So let's go ahead and
define a function called "def generate_damage(self):"
and basically all we're going to do is
"return random.randrange" and this is
going to be attack low attack, actually
self attack low, right we're inside of a
class, and self attack high. "(self.atkl, self.atkh)"
That's just going to generate a number so
that we can see ok, it's attacking us we
we need to generate the amount of damage, and we want this to be a little bit
dynamic so we're going to use our the
random range with the attack low and
attack high. So we're done with that and
that's what a lot of our methods are
going to look like. Alot of them
are going to be like one or two lines,
they're they're all going to be pretty
small though.
So, now we need to do the same thing but
for spell damage. What we're going to do
let's go ahead and create the spells
first.