Alright guys, so what we're going to do
is we're going to extend this to allow
us to have multiple party members. We
still need to do a lot of AI or
artificial intelligence for the enemy,
and we're just that's just not a
priority right now.
So, what we need to do is make a space
for our multiple players and what I mean
by that is over here in the terminal
when we're actually playing the role
playing game it doesn't look as pretty
as I want it to, and so we're going to set
this up to make it easier on the eyes
for when you're printing out multiple
party members data. We are going to make
progress bars and they're going to be
the hit points are going to be 25
characters long so that we can turn the
remaining hit points into a percentage.
Let's say we have 60 out of 100
percent, so 60% hit point left,
then we want to divide both of those
numbers by 25 so we can get how many
spaces we need to fill up the progress
bar in. So, it's going to be a little bit
of math, but not too much. So, what we're
going to do is I'm going to print out a
very static version of it and we're also
going to change this in a way that
each party members hit points and stuff
are going to be printed at the top of
each turn instead of the bottom. So, what
I'm going to do is at the top of the
script I'm just going to drop a couple lines
here right off the bat, and then we're
going to print out name, hitpoints, and magic
points. So, the top line is going to have
each column's values, so say name let's skip
a bunch of spaces there, hit points, and
then magic points and we will align these up
after. So, we're going to start printing
here the name is going to be a
Valos, and then we're going to...
we can line it up because
we know about you know that these are
fixed width and so they're going to
display the same in the terminal, so
that's good. So, what we're going to do is at
HP here, and actually we're going to create a
first-line first let me go ahead and do
this. Now we're going to skip a bunch of
lines until the hit point, and we're gonna put up a
line of underscores to wrap around the
progress bars,  and I need to make sure this
is 25 characters long. So, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10
11, 12, 13, 14, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19, 20, 21, 22, 23, 24, 25. And
I am going to do the same for MP,
so the only difference is that is going
to be ten. So, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
Now we have skip down
here, and what we're going to do is I'm
going to put a
straight-up line there, it's called a
pipeline actually that right there,
and this is going to be each line so I
can copy this to make three characters.
But, before we do that I'm going to put the
hit point value here first. So, Valos
is going to start out, we're going to
modify this but, 460 hit points so let's put
460/460, one space should be fine. We
can actually move that a couple
characters that way and then reposition the
rest. Same for magic points. We've got 65
of those right now and again we will
rebalance them.
So, if I save this and run it you will see
that I have a line, it shows this we're
going to make it prettier, I can copy
these two lines for each additional
character that we have. Now you'll see
that there's three rows, and I'm going to
actually drop it down another couple lines here to
separate it a bit.
Alright, so, this is what it's gonna show
at the beginning of each turn, so just
above actions here there's going to be
a line break, and then this, and then another
line break, and then an action. We'll actually need to
make the terminal a little bit bigger while we
play it. Now, I thought about how to fill
the progress bars up, I was going to use
equal signs and that didn't really look
right, and I was going to use forward
slashes and that looked a little better and I'll show you
how that looks here.
You can kind of see it looks a bit
more full, and then I decided that neither
of those is going to work. So, I actually
went and found an ascii character, it's this
one right here it's a block. So, it's ASCII
code to 219, so I want you guys to go
ahead and search for ASCII code 219.
For me the first site that comes up is
theasciicode.com, if it's not for you guys I
mean you should be able to get it from
any ascii table at all. I'm just going to
come here, we're going to click on that,
and I'm copy it up here. Going to come back
over to my editor here, we're going to
paste it, and as you can see this looks a
little better.
If I restart this we've now got progress
and it looks a lot better.
The only thing is we need to add some
color formatting here to make it more
visually pleasing and to separate things in
a different way. So, what we're going to do is, and
we're going to be using a lot of
plus-signs and string endings, so
we're going to start off by making
everything bold, and then the name. I'm going
to end it here, plus and drop a line here. For the
hit points were going to say the bcolors.
OKGREEN...
and I'm going to end it right here, start it right up
again, and I'm going to say bcolors.
OKBLUE...it definitely does add a
little bit of complexity to it to the
code here anyway, but you're going to see
the end result looks a lot better.
Now we need to...where did I miss...
forgot the quote right there. Now it should
look a lot better.
There we go. So, as you can see we actually
need to start the color bold again right
there, and goes a bit off-screen so I'm going to
do that. So, now you'll see that we have
three lines with hit points, and
magic points, and for instance this would
actually say like 210/460. Now
another thing we're going to have to do
is account for white space, so if this
only had 10 points out of 460 it's one character
less so everything is shifted this way.
So, we would need to determine how long
that string is and if it's not long
enough we're going to add a space to the
beginning of it when we dynamically
create it. But, for right now we're just
going to
statically create them, and in the next
video what we're going to do is we're
going to bring these into the player
class and we're going to print out each
person so that we can call it in the
main script here at the beginning of
each turn we will instantiate three
players, and then we will say player 0
print stats, player 3 print stats, etc.