So, the very first thing we need to add
here to the player class is a name
attribute. So, we need to pass it in here
and we're going to say self.name =
name. Now, when we instantiate the player
we need to specify their names. So, the
first one is going to be Valos, so
let's go ahead and create player 2 and 3,
there we go. So, now we got player 1, 2, and 3
and they're all named Valos right now,
so let's change that.
There we go. So we've got got player, player  1, player
1, player 2, player 3, they're all named
Valos right now so let's change that.
Second one I'm just going to name him Nick,
and you'll see that I'm actually going
to add a space to make them the same wdith just to make
things easier, and the third one let's just call
them robot. So, we've got three players
instantiated and players is going to be
the list that we reference. So, player one,
player two, player three. Now what we're going to
do is we are, I think the first thing
we're going to do is just copy the
static version of this that we have
right here, and we are going to add it to
the class. So, I'm going to make a
function here called get stats and we
are going to just leeave it like that and paste
our code here. So, instead of printing
this here we're going to, did I instantiate
that with a colon there?
I did.
That's going to look funny there, I should. What we are
going to do in the game file is we're going to replace
this right here with self.name. Now we
need to do the same thing here and here
so it's going to get even messier than
it was, so
let's go ahead for right now we're not going
to worry about alignment we're going to
print out the self hitpoints and self max hitpoints.
So, self.hp, actually that goes right there,
and then self.maxhp right there. And then
for the magic points we are going to, and
I need to add a plus sign there actually, for
the magic points we're going to do the
exact same thing, so I'm going to remove that and
put self.mp out of self.maxmp.
There we go. So, and this is going to
break our entire script because each
player has their own attacks an we've
been using the word player, player.choose_action,
so we will say player 1 choose action.
Actually, for what we're going to do
we're going to say for each player in,
yeah that's what we will do. So, we want the name player
available right there except for taking
damage for right now, so we are going to
have to change this a bit.
So, for player in players we just
need to indent all of this
one space further, and the enemy is going
to attack player one always for now. We are also
going to remove this. At the beginning of
the turn we're going to say print
two line-breaks and then print one
line break. In here we're going to say
player get_stats. So, let's see if we broke anything
yet.
Yep, enemy is
missing a name. So, let's go ahead and say the
enemy let's say it's from chrono
trigger, let's try this again.
Alright, so, we've got all it's stats the same, so let's
mix things up a bit. I'm going to make this guy a bit
stronger, we're going to make everyone a bit
stronger actually, we're going to make
the battle quite a bit longer, and
3089. Alright, let's restart this and we
should see different enemy moves and we don't,
because the only thing that's printing out
here is up here. So, let's go ahead and
remove this, we've got everything we want, and we're
getting an error. L:et's check out what
that error is. So, they are
ints so we actually have to go and specify
it's a string before each number, and I should
have known that. Actually, I did know that, I forgot
it.
Something terrible just happened.
I didn't close these so it's probably freaking
out about that.
There we go. For some reason it only printed
out one player and that's for each
player at the beginning of their turn. So, what
we've gotta do you actually have to
change that, here's what we're going to do we're
going to create another for loop here, it's
a bit confusing but basically if you guys
can't see what happens
we're saying for player in players first
print out that individual players stats
and then do all of this. What we want to
happen first is one loop that actually
prints out the stats, and then
the other one for all the attribute stuff.
So, let's remove that...there. So, let's skip two lines and
print out each player stats, and then
let's start the action. So, let's go ahead and
restart and you'll see now that I've got
my three actual characters and something is
terribly messed up because i forgot the
mp line.
Alright, let's add that here too. Print
"NAME" and the spacing is going to be off for
sure, let me check. 1, 2, 3, 4, 5...21.
So, hit point and then from hit
points 25...
36. So,
there go that should be about right. Let
me go ahead and restart it, and this needs to go one
back, I think, and then the lines here at the top
of each bar need to go forward one space. So, that forward one, and that
should actually fix it. Nope, one more. There we go.
So, that is our dynamic player
creation we have at the top of each turn,
and each person is going to take their
own turn for their actions. So, we need to
specify at the top of actions which player
it is attacking. So, it's going to go in
order so Valos, then Nick, then Robot, so we
need to actually print that out. So,
let's just one line above it maybe,
yeah. There we go, bcolors.BOLD, self.name, bcolors.ENDC.
We remove that beginning line there. So,
Valos is going to attack,
Nick is going to use magic, the magic
is going to be meteor, then robot is
going to attack. Now, we also need to
print out each person's damage summary after each
one, so instead of printing that at the end
I believe we're printing it outside that loop right
now.
No, okay. So, you attack then it says meteor
deals okay, so we need to specify
that, so it's getting a bit messy as you can
see. Yeah, what I'm going to do is
actually indent that as well. So, not over here, where
it says name skip four spaces. It's action
same thing.
So, all actions are going to be printed
this far in, and then details about is
going to be printed down there.
There we go. Alright, and actually, okay. So, let
me do this so I can show you. So, the text of
what's happening is going to be printed
at the beginning of the line, menus
are going to open four spaces in, and
then
options are going to open four spaces in
from that. So, I'm going to go and add
four spaces to actions, magic, and items. So,
1, 2, 3, 4...1, 2, 3, 4...and 1, 2, 3, 4.
There we go. It should look a little better.
There we go. As you can see, there we go, and as you can see
Robot chooses he's going to use an item, uses the potion, and
the enemy attacks but he didn't attack
anybody because there's now three
targets that he's choosing via
different values. So, that's how to
implement three characters, kind of,
we now need to rig up the magic points
to each person. So, actually, hold on a sec.
Oh, yeah, it did okay, so that was the top one.
Alright, so yeah the MP what we need to
do next is the progress bars here and
makes them actually work, we're going to
save that for the next video.