Alright guys, so in this video we're
going to make these progress bars
actually update. So, how we're going to do
that this calculation is going to be
slightly different from this one and
that's because this is 10 spaces wide
and this is 25, and both go in
to 100, they're divisible by 100 or go
into 100, divisible by both, so for the
first one for instance let's say, and
we're going to use a really basic
example calculation first so you guys
can see. So, in order to calculate
the difference you're going to divide
the max HP by, or no a divide the
current hit points by the max hitpoints,
and then divide it by or times a
100 divided by 4. Divided by 4 just because we
want the maximum number to be 25, and
then
the other one divided by 4 as well so you know
that would look accurate here. So, let me show you
guys so let's say we're trying to get
let's say our maximum hitpoints are 100,
or 200 let's say, so let's say we
have 200 hit points and we want to be
able to put that into this grid of 25.
What we're going to do is we're going to
say our current hitpoints are 150, or let's
say 50, so 50/200 is the maximum points,
that's 0.25. Now to get that
percentage we're going to multiply that
by a 100, we're going to 25%,
and then we need to divide that by
four in order for it to fit our progress
bar there, so divided by four and that's
6.25 and that's going to round down to 6. So, it's
going to be six spaces here. Let's go
ahead and implement that.
So, let's just do the entire
calculation on the first row, so
bar_ticks is going to be equal to self.hp/
self.maxhp, we're going to do this first, then
we're going to multiply that result by
100, and then divide that by 4. Now
what we need to do is we need to start at
that number and work down to zero and
for each tick, so for each integer in
that, we need to add one of these to the
bar. So, create a bar here equal to an
empty string. So, what we're going to do
is while bar_ticks is greater than 0,
we're going to say bar += and then that.
Then, we're going to say bar_ticks -=, so
we're going to take away one and we're going to
continue along until that reaches zero,
Now I think I need to make that greater
than or equal to,
but we will find out. What we're going to
do is we also need to figure out how
many empty spaces we need, so let me just
think about that for a moment we'll
figure out how to do that. Let's create
a second variable here, and I know hold
on, and then we need to create a while
len(bar) &lt; 25: we need to
go bar += and then just a space, this
should work. Then what we're going to do
is we are going to print out our bar,
hitpoint bar actually, right there.
So, let name this hp_bar because we're
going to be doing the same thing for
magic points after as well. So, this
should work, now it should, we need to give
the enemy and the enemy is actually
attacking the first character for some
reason, so that's cool. I don't remember
if I did that, yeah we did, player 1 always
takes damage. Alright, so we need to give
the enemy since we increase the hit
points we need to actually give the
enemy quite a bit more attack power
there, and we'll give ourselves more
attack power as well. So, we'll say 132,
this guys is going to have 188, and he's
gonna have 174. Save this.
Alright, so let's go ahead and start it, and
something terrible has happened right
there. Let me see is that...
yeah so that's definitely it right there. So, we
forgot to end some colors somewhere.
Start this again,
there we go. But, now these got pushed back
for some reason. Anyway, let's just make
sure that it works.
Everyone's going to attack him and he's
going to attack us. We need to give him a
big attack power for this to work I
think. Let's go ahead and give him 701
attack power, there we go.
Alright,
no, that's magic points.
Alright, well, everyone has more magic
point so I guess that works. Let's try this again through
the order that I passed those
things in through. As you can see a notch
has been taken off our hitpoint bar, and another one,
we're going to keep going until...oh,
I already won, cool.
Alright, and that's because we have
higher hitpoints so let's make him have 11,200. That's
going to be a little more difficult plus
he has a lot of magic points. So our
progress bar does in fact work, he needs a
bit higher attack power though. Let's try 315,
and if I use magic and I cure myself,
now the cures are still pretty weak
because we've scaled a lot of other
things up, we haven't scaled the magic.
Let's go ahead up here...
the standard spells do 600 points
of damage, this does 1200, and then cure is
going to heal 620 points, and cure
is going to heal 1500. So, let's try
this again.
Let's attack and let's get damage going for
our first character. Now I'm going to choose
magic, I'm going to choose cura, and we
can see that my hitpoints have gone back up for
the most of the part but then he
attacked me again.
Alright, so, we are also going to
need to create another potion let's just
make that heal for a 1000, grenade  500,
yeah. Alright, so, we also need to modify
the hielixir to go ahead and heal you
know all party members, etc., etc., but first
we need to make the magic points bar
work as well, and that is exactly the
same but instead of divided by four its going to
be divided by ten. So, mp_bar equals an empty
string, and then mp_ticks is going to be equal to self.mp
divided by self.maxmp *
100 / 10. And then down here we're going
to say while
mp_ticks is greater than 0: mp_bar +=
we're going to say this,
and mp_ticks -=, and then fill up the rest of
the mp_bar with a blank space. So, while
mp_bar length is less than 10,
mp_bar += an empty space.
What we're going to do is replace this
bit right here with mp_bar. Let's save
that. Now when I use magic you'll see
that my magic will reduce as well. Not
much though because we chose to, but the numbers
are working correctly, because we need to
now scale up the cost of each of these.
So, 25, 25, 25, meteor is going to be 40
magic points, and then quake is a really weak
spell. Cure is going to cost 25, and then
cura is going to be the next step up and it's going to
cost 32. So, there we go. So, we're
going to adjust strength and everything
as well because as you'll notice the
attack does 63 points of damage where
magic is now doing about you know the
standard spells are doing 600, so we're
going to set the strength of each
character to about 300.
This one's going to have the weakest
attack i guess at 288, and we're going to
make the enemy's strength a lot stronger
so that it feels like more of a
challenge. We're gonna set that 525 and
the defense we're actually going to make
that take effect as well, but for right
now we've got a basic
multi-party system working. i need to
straighten up that line by adding one
space in front of the words mp and the
align, So, mp, doesn't show it there, so
one space in front of the line there, and then
in the main.py where the mp
printed there. Let's add a space and it should look a
lot better.
Nope, one more.
There we go. So, back over here, that other on there, and
then right on.
So, what we need to do the same thing
here the hitpoints we're going to assume
are always four digits, so what we're
going to do is we're going to add well,
yeah let's do that right quick as well.
So, if ok, so let's set chp = self.mp
because we only want to modify in this
instance. So, if len(chp) &lt; 4: I'm
going to say...
yeah, okay. So, we're gonna have to get the lenght of it, I'm just trying to
think of the best way to do this here.
We're going to create another string
called shp, it's going to be a blank string for now,
we're going to get the length of chp.
So, if it's less than 4, a while it's less
than 4 I guess?
While...
this might have catastrophic
consequences. So, let's assume that the
current hit points were like 200
something. Actually, let's see if we can...
I'll just do this in the next video, I'm
going to try to work something out for a
really easy way to do that. So, yeah,
for now we've got the these working
completely and that's all we're going to
be focusing on right now. In the next
video I guess we are going to account
for white extra white space if this
falls below three digits and if this
falls below four digits we're going to
preceed the string of hit points with an
extra space, or however many spaces are
needed.