Alright, so, I figured out how we're going
to do this and it's simple in concept it's
just once we get a bunch of variables
created it definitely gets bit confusing
because there's only so many variables
that you can use that sound relevant
before you just run out of them and have
to start using different variables. So,
what we need to do is first create the
resulting HP string, which is whatever
out of whatever, so HP string is
str(self.hp) + "/" + str(self.maxhp), and
that's exactly what we were printing out
before. So, let's print out hp
string,
and it's nine characters long so 4 plus
4 and that, so the length is nine, so what we
need to do is we need to set the variable
that we're going to end up printing down
here, so the variable that we've already
figured out how many spaces we need to
proceed it and put it in, so we're going to create a
variable called current_HP which is
right now going to be blank. That's what
we're going to be stuffing everything
that we need into including the hp string. So, if
len(hp_string) &lt;
9:
we know that you know there's not nine
digits there's probably eight, or if
we're really lucky there's just you know
six, but I haven't yet seen our
hitpoints go below a hundred, so it's
really going to be if it equals eight. So,
what we need to do is we need to create
a variable that contains how many digits
it is left. So, we're going to go
decreased = 9 - len(hp_string)
and for instance if
string was 8, so let's say we had 260
points left, that would be equal to 1,
decrease would be equal to 1. So,
what we need to say is while decreased
&gt; 0: we need to add a blank space to
the beginning of current hp. So,
current_hp += " " and then
we need to remove one from the
decreased, and at the end of that we need
to set the current HP equal hp string,
or well we need to add HP
string to it. So, what it's going to do is
current HP let's say now is one empty
space that we're going to add onto that.
So, current_hp +=
the rest of the hp_string. Otherwise, if
the length is not less than nine what
we need to do is set current_hp
=  hp_string. There we go.
Now, what we're going to do is print out
current_hp here, and this should work,
let me go ahead and try it. So, we're
just going to attack until
we can see the top characters hitpoints fall below a
thousand, which is the next attack here,
so as you can see it did in fact work and it
added one blank space to the beginning
so that everything else lines up.
We need to do the same thing for the MP
bar as well. So, that's going
to give me another
opportunity to explain it I guess. So,
mp_string is going to be equal to this,
and then current_mp will be equal to a
blank string. Now these are going to be
seven characters long assuming that we
have street digit magic points. So, if
len(mp_string) &lt; 7:
we know that we have maybe two digits. So,
decreased = 7 - len(mp_string)
And then
while decreased &gt; 0: we're going to go
current_mp += " " a blank space, then
decreased -= 1 Then outside
of this while loop we set current_mp to...
well we add to it actually.
+= mp_string
else: current_mp = mp_string
And then we need to implement that down here
instead of current_mp it's going to say,
well it is going to say current_mp, instead of all
that string self mp stuff it's going to
current_mp. So, let's go ahead and
rerun this and let's use some magic, and
we're going to use the strong meteor spell,
and actually right off the bat it fell to under
a hundred, and you see that the extra space
was added there as well.