Alright, what we're gonna do now is
change the enemy's hitpoint readout
which is going to be something to this, but a
little bit different. So, let's go ahead
and create a function within the class
person. It's going to be get_enemy_stats. So,
we can run this method on enemies and
it's going to print it out like this. So,
HP bar is going to be equal to nothing,
and then bar_ticks is going to be equal to (self.hp
/self.maxhp) * 100 / 2
So, instead of having a 25 character
progress bar it's going to have a 50
character, so it's going to go from here
to about here. Now, what we're going to do
is the same thing as down here actually,
while bar_ticks &gt; 0: hp_bar += " "
and we're going to copy that
character right there, and then bar_ticks
-= 1. And that's enough to,
alright we need to do while length more
than 25, or less than 25. While
length of the HP bar is less than 50, set
hp_bar += " " What I'm
going to do is copy this right here,
I'm going to remove some from it, we're not going to print
out the magic points of the enemy.
We will print out the current HP and
everything too, so
we're going to be copying and pasting
that bit of code as well. So, I'm going to remove that so
that it just ends at the hit point bar, and print hit point bar there.
So, what I'm going to do now is copy this
bit of code right here and paste it here,
it's just where it you know adds whitespace
to the beginning of the the hip points
there. So, if I save this, come back here,
what I should be able to do is for
player and players print get stats,
but then after that also I want to
print or I want to run enemy_get enemy_stats.
Let me save it.
What I'll see here, right this is a bit
longer than 9
characters it's 11, so I need to change
that 9 here to 11. Then I need to move this
one space in, and I need to add a bunch to
it. So, let's see how many I have to add
into it. So, 1, 2...oh, that's as far as it goes. Let's try
10. Let's try 13, actually. There we go two more.
There we go.
So, that's all good let me remove some
spaces here from in front of the name, or
after the name, and let's add another space.
I'm trying to get it to line up exactly with
those rows and that works. So, I will remove one
from there, should be good to go,
one from the front. There we go.
Alright, so, at this point what we're
going to do is we're going to make this
red.
That is easily distinguishable from ours.
It's fine. So, let's go ahead and
make sure that this actually works. Let's
start attacking you can see his hit
points are going down. We're gonna cast,
we're making progress,
we gotta heal by using the elixirs...
So,
what we got to do at this point we've
got to make a mega elixir effect
everybody, so let's go into our main here
and elixir. So,
where i in players we're going to do
this. We're going to go...
so a mega elixir will do that, and a
regular elixir will only heal the
player. Well that's all good and fine but
right now the enemy does not attack
multiple people. So, what we need to do is
generate a random number between 0 - 2
for the enemy. So, how we're going to do
that is, and also the enemy's only
attacking, so what we need to do is
create an enemy target. So, target is
going to be equal to random, I need to
import random here, random.randrange(0, 2)
and then there
players. This is going to target the array or
the list, and this is going to tell it
which list we want based on 0, 1, or 2.
So, let's go ahead and start this again and
let's make sure that he's actually
attacking multiple people. So he attacked
the middle character there, and then the first
character,
there we go. It still hasn't chosen 2, maybe
I should make this 3. So, it won't...
there we go. So, now that will select
0, 1, or 2 but it will not
select 3.
Alright, we're also going to need to give
it some magic, give it some items, and then do
different things with that which we're
not going to do in this video. What we
are going to do is remove down here
where it says enemy HP.
We're also going to have to do other things to clean
this up, but that is fine for now. We've
got a big graphical display of everyone's hit
points up at the top there.