Alright, so we've got just about a
finished role-playing battle game here. A
few more improvements that I want to
make though is first we are going to
need to give the enemy both spells and
items, and secondly right now he only
attacks so we want to be able to add
some sort of conditions in there to make
him seem as though he was artificially
intelligent. Meaning if his hit points
are under 30 let's generate a number
between 1-100, and it's over 60 that means
he'll use potion. Ir if his hitpoints
are less than ten percent you know let's
generate a number between 1-100,
and if it's over 60 he uses the
hipotion, if it's over 40 he uses the
regular potion, etc. So, we need to
determine some of those things and we're
going to be doing that soon as well.
First of all we're going to be extending
this to allow us to add multiple enemies
and then target different enemies when each
person attacks. So, we're going to create
enemy2, it's going be person, and so there's going
to be one main enemy and that's
going to be Magus here. He's gonna be
the strong one as you can see with almost
20,000 hit points, and there's going to
be two smaller enemies which are going to
be henchmen, so they are going to be weaker.
So, we're just going to call them Imp, and
we're going to say they're going to have
about 1,250 hitpoints, their magic points
are going to be 130, their strength I
believe we pass in next is going to be
relatively weak, well
actually, no we want these guys
to be easier to defeat but also cause more
damage. So, we're going to set that to
about 560, what I have no idea what I
just did there I pressed something wrong,
560 and then their defence is going to be a
325, and the defense we're also going to
make important as well because what
we're going to do is we're going to take
the attack, the generated attack damage
and then minus the defense of the person
who they're attacking, and then the
resulting number is how much attack it's going to do.
Enemy3 is just going
to be another Imp witht the exact same stats
here. So, I'm going to name this enemy1, 2,
and 3.
And actually
I'm going to do it different because I'm
going to want just for preference
I don't want Magus then two Imps,
I want Magus to be in the middle, and that's
just you know because I can kind of
see how how it would lay out on a
typical RPG screen in the battle.
So, there's our enemies what we're going
to do is we're going to create another
array here or a list called enemies, and
it's going to be equal to enemy1, enemy2
enemy3.
There we go. So, what we're going to do
down here is see it says enemy.get_enemy_stats
we're going to say for enemy in enemies,
enemy.get_enemy_stats. And then what we're going to
have to do is we're gonna have to print
out so after they choose their attack,
there you know etc. here, we're going to
need to determine who the person is
attacking. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to create a function called
choose target, and actually we will put
that into the player class here, player
choose target and then we're going to
pass him enemies. So, now let's jump over to
our game here, and up with the other
choices like choose item and stuff we're just going
to create another method here called
def choose_target, and we're going to be
accepting enemies as a parameter. So, for
enemy in enemies: we are going to just print
out basically what we have been before.
We need to set an index to 0 so we can count, and
put a number actually it's going to be
1 there. So, for enemy in enemies we're
going to print out
the exact same kind of structure we've
been doing, so it's going to be FAIL and
bcolors, BOLD, 1, 2, 3, 4, TARGET, and then
bcolors.ENDC, and we're going to end the color. And actually
this needs to go above that for
statement otherwise it would print it out
three times, or four however many enemies we
have. Right now we're just setting it up
with three. So, here we're going to print
out
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, and then the index number
here plus a dot, and then we're going to
say enemy.name, and that's it.
And then we're going to say i += 1.
So, what we need to return is the enemy
that they have chosen,
so this isn't going to be just a print
and then we capture the index in each
one as like we would have to capture
here and then if they're using magic we
would have to capture the target here,
etc., so what we're going to do is put this into a
variable called enemy, and we're actually
going to return the index number of that
enemy, or the object itself.
Let me see...no, just the index number. So,
we're going to say print choose, and I
believe choose was on four spaces in
yeah four spaces in it says choose, so I'm going
to say choose targets, and then we're
going to put actually that's an input i
believe
yeah that's an input. So, choice
equals input, turn this into an int right
off the bat, negative 1, and then we're
going to return choice. So, this is going
to let's say it's going to print out the
enemies and then we're going to select
the first one which is going to be the
first one in the array, so technically
that should be a zero, so we're reducing
the choice by one so if we input one it's
going to actually become 0 and then it's
going to return that is an integer to this
right here. So, enemy is now going to
be 0 so what we're going to say is
enemies, and then we're going to say the
correct enemy like that. So, we're actually
going to copy this bit
and we're actually going to also print
out which enemy you're attacking here, so
enemies enemy, and then their name.
Yeah, so, we're gonna copy this and then
we're going to bring this down to the
magic as well, so if we choose black
magic we need to then choose the target
here. So, same thing they're going to be
taking magic damage, and then we need to
print out which you attacked. So spell
name does X points of damage to
there, and then if we choose an attack
item we're going to, I think that
looks right, so if we choose an
attack item we're going to need to be
able to choose the enemy as well. So, I
take damage so it's going to take item.prop
as the damage, that's the value of
the item, so for instance if we choose a
grenade the grenade's prop property is
going to be equal to 500 i believe. So,
we're going to say item name deals
points of damage to enemies(enemy).name.
Now this should work and we're
gonna test it out here, we should be able
to choose targets, so
let's go ahead and save. Now still the
enemy is not going to be able to attack
us so what we need to do first is we're
going to say enemy0 is going to be
the one who attacks us. So, let's go ahead
and save, run this, and then we're going
to extend that to make each enemy attack
us. So we actually need to fix the names
well those should go in two spaces is
it, yep two, because it's twwo characters less. So,
where is that, there we go. I forgot about that.
So, let's refresh, there we go.
So as you can see we've now got two Imps
and a Magus. So if we select attack
we're going to have to choose a target,
so let's choose an Imp.
He's going to use magic, let's use
thunder on Imp, and then robot's going to
attack Imp. Here we get an error,
enemy damage is not subscriptable.
Enemies damage...oh enemies...I
forgot to change that there. Were is that?