Let's try this again just to make
sure everything works. Hit the attack,
we're just going to attack right now, and
enemy.get_hp so that as well and this is in
line 150. So, now what we're going to need
to do is we're going to need to change
this to check
you know for each enemy if each enemy
is dead then we win.
So what we're going to do is we're going
to create an index of...and then defeated
enemy means equals 0, and then for enemy
in enemies, if emey.get_hp == 0: we are
going to say
defeated_enemies += 1. And so
down here, out of this if loop
statement, we're going to say if defeated
enemies equals 2 then
we've obviously won. We're going to do
roughly the same thing for the players,
so right here.
defeated players = 0, for player in
players: if player.get_hp == 0
defeated_players += 1. This might not work...we'll find
out though I mean I don't think it's
going to. defeated_players
Oh, no, that's going to work
because we're going to set it to 0 and then it's
going to check each time. I thought it
was for some reason, I was thinking, it's
going ok, so, defeated players let's say
one person dies this is going to be 1,
and so it's going to add to that so that
each turn that went by it the same
person is dead it's going to keep adding
one, but it's not because we're setting
these variables right at the end of the
function. So before any of this
runs it is already set to 0. So, if
defeated players equals 2, your enemies
have defeated you.
So, now I believe this is the last bit, it
should all work, there are a few other things
we need to do. As you can see right there
the Imp
we're doing a great deal of damage, but
Valos has taken some damage of magic here...
alright.
So, once targets hit points are zero,
let's do this. Let's come back in here
where we choose target for enemy and
enemies, if enemy.get_hp  doesn't equal 0 then
we're going to do this stuff. Once an
enemy is dead
we basically don't get the option to
target. So as you can see now we've got two
targets, but now the problem is that
we need to remove it, we need to remove
the enemy from the actual
enemies list because if not we're going
to choose one and it's going to actually
attack Imp still, because that's making
that is 0. So we're going to have to fix
that as well and the way we're going to
do that, let me return that hit point there,
in the main script here let's see if we attack,
let's also add another bit of code here. So, if
enemies[enemy].get_hp == 0
we're going to basically just delete
enemies[enemy]. Then we're going to say,
before we do that we're going to print
out the enemy's name.
There we go.
We're going to do the same thing where
we choose the enemy here in magic.
So we're going to do it below that there,
and then we're going to do the same
thing under attack items right there,
and we can actually clean up this code
a bit. We can document it as well and
probably before we actually do
the well before I uploaded to the
repository I will comment it so it's a
lot more you know documented, so you
guys can understand it. So, now what
what should happen is he should have
been deleted, so first off two things are
going to happen. The next time it shows
this readout it's not going to show that
enemy, and two once we choose attack
we're going to have an option to choose
Magus or Imp and this should actually attack
Magus now, and it does. So that's exactly
what we want to happen. Now we're not
going to really focus on if we're going
to be able to beat this guy,
what we're going to do is when we attack
an enemy we're going to strip the white
space from it. So how we're going to do
that is where we print out enemy name we're
going to say replace.
We're going to do this each time we
print out a string about an enemy.
Up here where we do damage,
oops that's what I meant to do, and
then up here when we attack as well.
Where is that?
So, if they have died we need to do the same
thing.
Then we need to print out which enemy is
attacking. Does one enemy attack only attack?
Yeah, right, that's what we did we only
made one enemy attack, so we will leave it
there for now. So, let's save this, re-run it, and
let's make sure that everything works
se we're going to just demolish first
character there. There we go and as you can see
we're attacking Imp, and the white space has
been removed. So, that's as far as we're
going to go this time. I think I'm
actually going to re-upload the code
here to GitHub so you guys can see it, but
this battle actually won't be too
difficult. So we can just keep hammering
with attacks and magic, until we have no hit
points, but we also do have a mega
elixir. So I'm gonna go ahead and use
an item and I'm going to use a mega
elixir,
and then we're going to keep hammering
this guy with magic until we
defeat him. So I mean it's as you can see we
haven't really made this too difficult, you
don't really have to think, but that's
again because one enemy is attacking you
and not all of them, and they also don't
heal. So once we implement those bits of
code,
there we go, then you know it's obviously
going to make it more difficult.
There we go. So, enemy damage the Imp has died.
So, that's in line 155 right here, if the
enemy has died they obviously can't
attack. So that's obviously a
problem we shouldn't have but we are
going to fix it at some point as well.