Alright, so, we got maybe two videos
left in this specific project, and I just
want to cover a few more things just to
make it feel semi complete. I do want to
mention though and this is something I'm
not going to be doing, but if you watch
the videos, or if you do watch the videos
not really sure where they are in the course, but
there are videos dedicated to using
JSON which is basically a way to save
data and then load data from a file. What you could
do and I would be really interested in
seeing this, I would like to do it myself
but I don't think we're going to have
time to venture onto that, but if you
guys want to do it and send me a link
what I think would be really cool if you
could at the beginning of the script
here try to load a save file. So, let's
say you had a file called save.json
and the save would contain a character's
name, hitpoints, you know all the stats,
and also experience points. You can
create a leveling system where your
characters could actually level up, and
you could create a ton of enemies, and
then randomly you know basically what
you would do is for each battle the
players would get experience points and
then after each battle you would have the
option to save back into that json file,
and then also continue on to other
battles. What you could do is make a
list of let's say 50 different enemies,
and then in each battle determine you
know two or three enemies to throw into
that battle, and also makes the enemy's
data scale to these guys levels. So, that
is a bit complicated and it would be
tedious to watch me do it because it's
just gonna be covering a lot of the
stuff that we've already learned, and I
think this specific project has already
gotten too long. So, I just want to finish it
up at this point, get it done, and we can
move on to some other fun stuff.
So, what we're going to be doing I
believe we're at this point right now
where one enemy attacks, so we need to
make all enemies attack but we also need
to code this into somewhat intelligent
attacks, and give them a cure spell, maybe
some potions, and allow them
to heal if needed and that's going to
make the battle a lot more challenging.
So, what we're going to do is right here we're
going to say for enemy in enemies: so
first we need to indent this bit right
here because that's what wwe're working with. So, we need
to generate an enemy choice between 0
and 3. So, random.randrange
between 0 &amp; 3, and then what we need to do
obviously is 0 is going to be attack, 2
is going to be magic, and three is going to be
item. So, what we can actually do is copy a
bit of this. So, actually, this is
unnecessary because we've already got
that coded, so if enemy_choice == 0:
we're going to print the enemy's name. So,
let's say enemy.name.replace,
I'm going to replace all spaces with a blank
character, I'm going to say attacks for and then enemy damage.
Actually, they attack player. So,
we're going out the player's name as
well. So players(target).name, and then we're going
to replace all spaces with that. So that's
just the attack itself and what we need
to do is we need to put this bit of code
before our enemies so that if we have no
enemies left, if we've just killed
them,
obviously they can't attack, and that's the error
we were getting in the last video.
There we go. First we Check if
battle is over, so let's add a comment
here, Check if player won. Here Check if
enemy won. I'm going to label that as enemy
attacks phase.
So, let's just comment right here Chose attack,
elif enemy.choice == 1: we now need
to generate a random number from
the enemy's length of magic. So, let's go
ahead and let's set magic_choice ==
random.randrange, and it's going
to be between 0 and enemy.magic, and
it's going to be the length so we need to
wrap that in the length method here. So it's
going to generate a random number
between 0 and the length of their magic
list, so let's say they have five spells it's
going to generate a number between 0 and
5, so that's going to be the magic spell
itself. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to come up here and copy the
magic, and we're going to say that's
going to be spell and this is, well let's just
type this out on our own. So we need to
generate the damage and get their MP. So,
magic_dmg is going to be equal to
enemy.generate, actually magic.
I believe we have that in the magic itself
let me just check up here what we did
with the player here.
Yeah, alright, so that's what we did. We
basically said spell equals their
actual individual spell, and then spell
generates damage. So, we're doing that
in the same way just in one line, and then we need
to get their magic points. So, if enemy.mp
is less than...alright, that's why
we did that. So, because we're using spell
multiple times here so mp_cost,
well actually let's just name that
spell. Spell = enemy.magic
[magic_choice]. So, spell.cost we are going
to basically re-run it...
let me think about this for a moment.
We could break that out to its own
function, or make this recursive which
would require putting it in its own
function. So, what we're going to do here
let's go ahead and we need to pass in
the enemy. So, let's copy this up here at
the top left, can we put that into into its
own
person class? Let me check. Yeah, we
can. Alright, so, let's drop this down,
choose enemy spell. So enemy is going to
turn into self.
Yep, this should work.
Alright, else return: the spell
itself, or the magic damage, let's return the
spell. That should work.
Actually, let's return spell and magic
damage.
Alright, so, back up here and let's say
enemy.choose_enemy_spell. Let's print
out
just make sure we've got these correct here.
We're going to have to play this a bit
to make sure,
well to actually to get...alright, so empty
range for randrange, okay. So, we screwed up
there, let me just check.
Self.magic...
alright because we haven't passed any
magic to the enemies. So, let's go
ahead and give them a few spells as well.
The magic is going to be lets say enemy
spells equals fire, meteor, cure.
Copy this, and there we go. So it looks
like the enemy did
choose magic but something went terribly
wrong.
Let's just attack, and enemy chose spell,
so they did choose the spell correctly
which is awesome.
now all we need to do is actually take
that spell they chose, they had enough
magic points to do it, we need to reduce
their MP and we need to
determined this bit right here.
Alright, so, enemy.reduce_mp, and we're
going to reduce it by spell cost, then
we're going to print that right there. So
if spell type equals white we're going
to say enemy heal for magic damage. So,
we're going to say it heals enemy.name
for X damage, and we're going to also
have to turn this into
basically another if condition that if
their hit points are less than 20%
or so then choose a white magic
spell, otherwise and then randomize it,
otherwise you know just keep rolling
until they choose a black magic spell. So, let's say
their target, was their target already
chosen? No, alright. So let's just stop that
right there.
So players[target] take damage,
we pass it magic damage. So
what we're going to do is print out enemy.name.
replace, add spaces, and we're going to go
so it's going to say Imps fire deals you know
however much damage. So, players got target,
get_hp, print players.target has died.
Then we're going to remove that player
just for now.
So let's comment out this, and let's see
this run.
So Imp attacked,
so it's still one player is attacking...
that's odd.
Let's see what happens now.
Alright,
so, this is on line 202, and the issue is
list indices must be integers or slices, not person.
Where is, what?
Oh, I didn't even see that bit right there.
Alright, let's go ahead and try again.
So, Imp heals, cure heals Imp for 634.
That's strange because
Magus is not attacking. There Magus
attacks.
So it's actually working, for the most
part, except Imp keeps healing. Oh, yeah, this is
definitely going to make it a lot more
difficult.
Nobody attacked that time. You know what,
so here's the problem. We're
generating the wrong numbers, so enemy
choice there because we don't have three
right now, we don't have item, we just
have one or two that's why some of them
weren't attacking. So there we go, so we've
got three people attacking correctly, and
alright, good stuff. So Imp attacks,
Magus's meteor deals damage, so this is
looking a lot better. Now what we need to
do is just make sure they're not using
white magic unless their hit points are
less than 50%. So, what we're
going to do is if spell.type ==
"white": hold on that's in the, okay hold on.
spell.type == "white" and self.hp, well
it's going to be equal to let's say self.hp
dived by self.maxhp * 100. So, and
percent of their hit points
is over 50, then they're going to choose a
spell again. So if they don't have
enough MP or if it's white magic and
they have more than fifty percent
health they're going to choose again, and
they are going to choose black magic
So let's go ahead and save this and make sure
it works, we should see enemies not
healing unless they are under fifty
percent health. So, let's go ahead and
start this and we're again just going to
attack just for the sake of it.
Alright, so, we see that Imp is really
low, we have a bit of a issue there. So,
when the enemy's attack we need to skip
one more line, so there is definitely an
for enemy in enemies right here. So we'll go print("\n"), and
then above magic we need to remove
that one right there.
There we go. Alright, so, that's fine for
now. We should we're going to play a
little bit and see if we can see a heal,
actually we're not going to get to that
point because we are going to lose.
Alright, so now we need to do a bit of
healing, let's just use one of our mega
elixirs. Alright, so, Magus attacks
Valos, there we go. We're still good,
let's go ahead and attack, and we might
see a heal here soon. Let's give it another
go and see what happens.
Cure, oh his cure is so bad! Especially
for his, let's give him a different
cure spell. So let's go ahead and make curaga
which again is from Final Fantasy, and
it's going to cost
50, it's going to cure for a 6000, it's going
to be white, and this is going to be the only
white magic that enemies have. So, if he
does heal it's going to do a lot of
healing, it's going to heal 6000, so that should make it more
difficult. So I think we're good, we're
not going to go through the items. The
items would be the same thing for an
enemy but in games enemies don't
typically use items, so we don't even
need to worry about that.
So, I think we're done with this. This was
a lot of fun actually I really enjoyed
this. This code base is going to be
updated on the github repository, so go
ahead and go over to, and I'll put the
link up there, it is github.com/
nickgermaine. So, I will put this link in the
video's discussion section you guys can
go check it out, if I haven't already
I'm not sure if I have i'll have to check. There are other
repositories in my list of repositories.
There's also other repositories there
some of them also which relate to
this course as well. So,
thank you guys so much for watching this
section of the course. Personally I would
love to spend like so much more time on
this but I just don't think we have the
time, and we're going to be moving on to
other more awesome things as well. And at
some point we are going to be covering
a video game creation library for
Python. What I'd really like to do, if we
have enough time to do it, would be to
put a graphical front end to the logic
in this game. I think that would be super
awesome and we already have a lot of
this created, so we would just need a
plug it in to the PyGame which we would
be using. So, i'll see you guys
in the next video.