So, let me see,
let's go ahead and just go ahead over to
our main scripts. Let's go create a main
script I guess, it's going to be called
"main.py" So "from classes.game import
Person, bcolors" We're going to need
both of those eventually. We're going to
instantiate the person class here, with an enemy, so let's go ahead and, with
a player, so "player = Person(460, 65, 60, 34, magic)" and we're going to pass the HP, so let's say
460, MP going to be 65, attack power
is going to be 60, defense is going to be 34,
we are a mage, and then magic what we're going to do is we're going to create an
array, and then inside of that array
we're going to create multiple objects,
and actually let's create that up on the
line above so it looks a bit nicer. So
let's just do this,
there. So, let's go ahead and create a
magic array "magic = []" and each spell is going to
have a "name":
This is going to be "Fire", going to have a
"cost": 10,
it's also going to have a "dmg":
property. The damage for this one is
going to be, lets say, and I mean I really
haven't balanced any of this out in my
head but let's say "60}]" and then
what we can do is copy this a few times
and make multiple spells. We're going to
name this one
"Thunder"
and then once more I'm going to
my name this one "Blizzard" and again if you've played any role playing games you'll
note these are three of the most common
spells that you have. So, once we get the
player instantiated we have a class that
can actually do something, so we're going
to generate the damage, and
we're going to run a few times. So "print(player.generate_damage())" and again, and
once more just so we can see that it is
in fact working. So let's go ahead and
save this and then run it, we see the
first time it says 57, 67, 60 so it is
generating a bit of a random number for
the damage, that's awesome.
Let's go ahead and now that we've
got the spells setup let's go ahead and
look at the generate spell damage how
we're going to do that. So let's define
another method called "def generate_spell_damage(self, i): and we need an ink index number
here because it's an array, so we'll be
able to pass it the number 1, 2, 3,
or actually 0, 1,  or 2 and we'll be
able to access each object and we can
take the damage. So let's say Thunder did
80, you know, it's going to look up a
different so we need to be able to select
that. Let's go ahead and jump into this
method. So how we're going to do this is...
we're gonna say the same thing. So we're
gonna set "mgl = self.magic [ ]"
this is where our magic spells are stored, then we get the index
number and so we're going to put that in
here "[i]", and then we get the "["dmg"]" property
and we're going to do "-5" and
then "mgh =
self.magic[i] ["dmg"] + 5" and what we're going to do is we're
going to "return random.randrange(mgl, mgh)" So, let's go ahead and jump over
here and let's "print(player_generate_spell_damage(0))" and then we will also
"print(player.generate_ spell_damage(1))" save this and go ahead and hit the Run button, and
what we'll see is that it is grabbing
them properly because if we're only I
think doing negative or -5 of their
60 would only be able to go from 55 to
60, and so 76 is four less than 80 so it
is actually picking those up correctly.
So that's how we're going to be
calculating both the regular attack
damage and the spell damage. Now what we need to do is create a function for the
player or enemy to take damage. So we're
going to "def take_damage(self,dmg):" and it's
going to take self and damage. So we're
actually going to pass that number into
this function, so let's go ahead and
basically all we're going to do is a
subtract the amount of damage from the
current HP. So, "self.hp -= dmg"
So what that's going to do is
that's going to basically just take away
the damage mount from the HP, and then
what we need to do is a bit of truth
checking, I guess. we need to check
"if self.hp &lt; 0: which we never
want it to be because all of our code is
going to assume that the hit points are
either 0 or higher.
We're going to "self.hp = 0" then what we're going to do is we're going to
"return self.hp"