So let's create a few utility classes to
get properties so "def get_hp(self):" we're just
going to "return self.hp" "def get_max_hp(self): going to be the same except with the
different property "return self.maxhp"
We're going to "def get_mp(self):" "return self.mp"
and "def get_max_mp(self):" and going to be "return self.maxmp"
So, what we're going to do now is
a way to when we cast a spell it's going
to be able to generate spell damage and
then run this method on the enemy to
reduce the enemy's MP, but we also need
to be able to reduce the magic points
that we have because there's going to be
a cost.
So what we're going to do is we're just
going to define a function called
"def reduce_mp(self, cost)" parameter and it's just going to
reduce the cost so return,
actually we don't need to return anything, so "self.mp -+ cost" Almost
done,
we've got a few more methods then we can start on the procedural stuff. So, we also
need to get the spell name because we need to be able to return data to the user
about what they've chosen, so we're going
to define a method called "def get_spell_name(self, i):"
and pass it an index number, and we're
just going to "return self.magic[i]["name"]"
as you can probably guess.
We're gonna get the spells MP costs as
well, so "def get_spell_mp_cost(self, i):" We are also going to pass it an index there and
we're going to "return self.magic[i]["cost"]"
I believe i've named that "cost." Let me go back
here,
yep. Alright, good stuff. So we need two
more methods, one to be able to choose an
action like attack or magic, and then if
we choose magic we need a way to then
choose the magic. So, we're gonna define
those two right here. So let's go ahead
and create the first of those choice
options which is going to be action. So,
"def choose_action(self):" we're not going to pass anything in here, we're just going
to set an "i = 1" because we want
the option to start with 1.
So then we're going to go "for item in self.actions:" "print" we need to convert
the index number two string so that we
can do this "(str(i) + ":",  then we're just going to put
"item)'" then we're going to increment "i += 1"
Same kind of thing for choose magic
except it's going to also print out the
cost of the magic. So, let's go ahead and
define choose spell, actually it's going to
make more sense to "def choose_magic(self):" so we're using that word quite a bit in here and
I don't want to forget what we're doing.
So index is going to be set to one "i = 1" as
well, and "for spell in self.magic:" print
same thing we're going to convert the
the index number to a string "print(str(i) +" going to concatenate it with a ":" then we're
going to print out the spell name, and
then the cost. So ", spell["name"], "(cost:"
", str(spell["mp"]) + ")")""
Then we're going to also increment "i += 1" So, we're actually going to before we
get the list of actions I guess we
should make it say what this relates to.
So we're just going to "print("Actions")"
and then here we're going to
"print("Magic")"
So that is all we need for right now in
our class, so let's go ahead and get back
on over to our main file here, and we're
going to generate an enemy as well.