Alright guys, an infinite battle when
your hit points are zero is not very fun
because you can just keep going and
there's no sense of achievement when you
finally defeat the enemy just because
your hit points have been 0 a long time
ago, and even still you're both dead and it
still goes. So, what we need to do is
determine if the battle is over. So at
the end of the while loop here, in each
iteration of the loop, we need to check
if the enemy's hit points are 0, or our hit points are
zero, and if they are we need to print
out that the battle is over, essentially.
So, if enemy get HP equals 0, going to
print out bcolors
green, it's going to be green, you win, and we need to end
the color there. We need to set running
to false.
If player HP equals 0,
we're going to print out basically that
you lost. So we're going to print that
out in fail, enemy has defeated you. There we
go and in that color as well, and we're
also going to set running equal = false.
Now what we get as you can imagine if we
run the script we are allowed to attack,
and they attack us, so we're just going
to keep going, and at some point enemy
has defeated us, that's very unfortunate.
Now, what we can do to actually defeat
the enemy is adding some more options like the
ability to heal and use magic, and the
magic is going to do a bit more damage
then our attack. Let's make it do more
damage actually. So, what I'm going to do is up here going to
add a 1. Let's make that
100, 100 and 124. So, now we need a
way to choose the magic, and this is
going to come down to in this if
statement if index is 0 obviously we want
to attack,
if lf index equals one we're going to be
using magic.
So what we need to do is basically just
allow the player to choose magic and
then generate the spell damage and then
attack the enemy, and that's basically
going to take the same flow as here. So,
magic damage is going to be equal to player generate
spell damage for, we haven't even
chosen the magic yet. So, let's go ahead
and player choose magic, and then we need
to capture their input so magic choice
will be equal to input.
Actually, let's do it this way.
Ok, so, choose magic.
However, what we're going to do is we're
not going to do the same thing we did up
here where we separated it into two
variables to be able to reduce the
number of the input by one, what we're
going to do is we're going to do that
all in one line. So how we're going to do
that is we're going to wrap the input in
int right off the bat and then reduce it
by one, so we can pass that right through.
So this is going to generate the spell
damage and as you can see what it's
going to do we're passing in the number,
it's going to get that index of the list
of magic, and it's gonna get the damage
then you know choose a random between
magic lower magic and high which is going to
be -+ 5.
So, after we've generated the spell
damage we need to also reduce the magic
points by the cost of that spell. So, I'm
gonna set spell equal to player get
spell name, my magic choice, and then also
the cost is going to be player get spell
and np cost. I'm also going to pass in magic
choice so that we can get basically each
thing we need from the spell right here,
and then we're going to get the current
magic points of the player. So, get MP. So,
if we have enough magic points we want
to successfully cast the spell, otherwise we
want to say you can't do this.
So, what we're going to do is if cost is
more than the current MP, we need to
basically say you don't have enough MP.
So, print out bcolors, fail, we're
going to skip a line say
not enough MP, then bcolors, end color.
Now what we need to do at this point is
we need to skip back to the beginning,
well actually for right now
they're just going to miss their turn, so
otherwise they're actually going to we
need a way to restart that. We will come
back to this in the next video. What
we're going to do right now is we're
just going to continue along and we're
going to reduce the MP cost if they're
able to, so player reduce MP and it's
going to reduce it by cost. Then we're
going to generate the magic damage. It's
going to be equal to...
we've already generated the spell damage
damage right there. Okay, cool. So we
don't need to generate that here,
got a little mixed up there. What
we're going to do is we're going to tell
the enemy to take the damage, and the
damage that they're going to take is the
magic damage. Then we're going to print
out that the magic spell deals x amount of
damage. So, print and for this we're going
to be using the okay blue color. So, let's
print out a line break, spell name, deals
going to use a comma here, convert this
to a string, magic damage, another comma,
points of damage. Then we're going to end
that and we need to then print out the
enemies current hit points. Actually, let's
at the end of the statement we're going
to print out everybody's hit points just to
make it a bit cleaner here,
so where is player hit points as well.
Alright, so down here we're actually going to
go ahead and print out the hit points,
your magic points, and the enemy hit points. So,
in order to separate that from the rest
of the turn
we're going to put a single line here.
Enemy's hit points are three colors
let's make that fail so it's red,
HP I'm going to put a slash here so the current HP
out of enemy get max HP, and then we
need to end the color. So and we're also
going to do a line break there because
we're going to print out your
information next. So, print your hit points
equal to bcolors,
ok green so just convert to a string, player
get HP out of player get max HP, and then
we're going to end that color. And then
you need to print out your magic points
because we have begun to use magic now
and so your magic points are going to
reduce, and it's helpful to know what
your magic points are. So, your MP is
going to be equal to bcolors,
okay blue, convert this to a string player
get MP out of
get max MP, and then we're going
to end that as well and then skip a line
because we're all done here. So, we did a
lot here so let's go ahead and run this
and see what happens.
So we can choose to attack and we get a
problem there because we did not add the
parentheses after the get HP I think
that's the only problem there, let's start
again. So we have attacked and as you can
see now we actually have the actions
being printed out, and then the stats
being printed out, and then the next term
again.
So if we continue doing that let's
choose magic. So now if we choose magic
let's go ahead and choose thunder. As you
can see thunder deals a 120
points of damage
so now things are looking a bit better.
We can then go ahead and choose thunder again,
we've got 41 magic points, some fire, there we go.
We're definitely going to lose
still, although we're striking for a lot
more damage right now than the enemy is.
If I had not started at...I don't have
enough MP. Oh, yeah, that works. Okay, hold on
look up here. So basically what
happens is if you don't have enough
magic points by putting continue here, I
totally missed this, by putting continue
here it we don't miss the turn the enemy
doesn't attack us and stuff because it
just skips back to the next iteration
which allows us to choose our action
against so we can then choose attack
instead of magic.
Let's go ahead and lose this battle,
enemy has defeated us, and the problem
here is that we don't have a way to heal.
And so what we need to do, we're going to
be doing
the next video, but we're going to add a
way to heal.