Alright, so, we've got a magic system and
it works but it's not ideal and that's
simply because it's taking up space in
our main Python file here, and in order to
get that out of there what we're going
to do is we're just going to create as
with our game.py classes here, we're
going to create a new file in the
classes directories, it's to be a python file,
and we're going to call it magic. Now in
here we're going to create a class
called Spell, and what we're going to
have, if we look over at our main python file, we're
going to have name, cost, damage, we're
also gonna have type and I'm going to show you
guys why. So let's go ahead and create
our init function, and we're going to
take in name, cost, prop, and type.
Actually, let's name this damage, and I will
show you guys why we're doing this in a
second. What we're going to do is we're
going to create instance variables
from the variables or from the
values that we pass in. So, name = name, self.cost = cost, and
self.type = type. So, we're just doing very
basic stuff here. Just to recap, when you say self
you mean this instance of the class. So, if we
instantiate, and let's look back here just to  recap, we're instantiating the person class
twice. This instance of the person class
goes into player, and this instance goes
into enemy. And as you can see the values
and variables here are different, and we're
able to access different variables. If we
say enemy.HP it's going to turn out
this. If we say player.HP it's going to say that, and that's
because in here we set HP equal to whatever
we pass in
there. Which it's not a difficult concept,
I think you guys remember, I just wanted
to you know go over that again just in
case as we're, that's something we're
doing right here. So, we have our spell
created and we don't really need to do
anything except, we have generate spell
damage there, I think...
We don't need that function, I'll show
you guys why. We don't need spell name, I'll  show
you guys why. So, I'm going to delete these,
and remove the heal, actually no
we're going to keep that one because
that is more player based than spell based.
And the spell damage we're going to
remove that as well. Alright,
let's go ahead and save this. Now that's
going to break our game here if we try
to play it again and we choose a spell.
It's going to have a dangerous effect because
we've just removed some essential code.
So what we're going to do is we're going to
fix this up by instantiating multiple
spells and we're going to reference them by
name.
Fire is going to equal spell...fire cost,
what order did I pass that in? Name, cost, damage, and
type. So, the cost is going to be 10,
the damage is going to be a 100, and
the type is going to be black magic.
Now as you can see this underlined
because we didn't import magic yet. So,
from
classes.magic import spell.
We're going to do the same thing with
thunder and blizzard as well, I'm also going to throw in
meteor, quake, and that's good for now. So,
thunder, blizzard, meteor, and quake.
They all do the same level of damage and
we're going to fix that a moment, I'm
just going to add a comment here, okay
black magic and now we're going to
balance this. So, meteor is going
to be about double the cost and double
the damage, quake is going to be about
.2 higher than both fire and thunder in both
MP costs, well .4. So, it's going to cost 14
and going to do 140 damage.
Now I'm going to create some white magic.
So we're going to create cure, I'm just going
to copy these, well I will print them out. So, cure
equals spell, the name is cure, the cost is
going to be, well let's look at a few
things first. So, the person has 400 points hit points, so
I think 120 is a decent amount here. So
the cost is going to be 12, and the damage is going to be that, and
we're going to say it's white magic.
We're going to create a more powerful
cure spell called cura, and that we're
taking from Final Fantasy. So it will
cost about 18 but it's actually
going to feel for 20, and we're going to classify that as
white magic as well. Now what we're going to
do is we don't want the player, well the
enemy can't use magic right now we're
going to fix that I think in the next
video, right now what we're just going to
do is create player magic. And then we're
just going to pass you the variables
that we created up here as magic for
whichever spells we want to...actually you
know what we're gonna move that all
together, we're just going to do it
straight in line.
And so we're going to create a list here,
and spells we want we're going to say
fire, thunder, blizzard, of course the
basic ones, then meteor, and cure, and cura. And
they're going to have no magic for right
now. So, if I save this we still need to
modify a few things. I believe we took
out generate spell damage in the player, so
what we need to do is add that into the
class here. So, I'm just going to say generate damage, and
what we're going to do is thing as
before, we're going to set low equals
self.damage - 15, and high is going
to be self.damage + 15. I believe
we used the random in the generate
damage, we have random randrange. So what
we're going to do, and this is as you
remember the randrange here generates a
number between a low and a high number or
guess you can use high and low as well,
it doesn't really matter what order you
pass in, so we need to import random.
Let's go ahead and do magic, let's drop down a few
lines, and run import random, and then
we're going to return random.randrange,
and we're going to pass in low
and high. So let's save this now, go
back over here, and we need to fix the
generate spell damage. So, what we're
going to do is, this is awesome, so as you
can see we passed our index number here
into an actual function, and what we're
going to do now, we're going to do the
opposite actually, we're going to
say, so this is going to be entirely
different, so I'm going to drop some
lines here and I'm going to rewrite the code
in the new way so you guys can see the
difference. So magic damage is going to be
equal to
player.magic, and we're going to
say the magic choice, and then we're
going to target the magic's function which
is generate damage. And then we're going
to see the spells name,
well what we can do is actually a little
bit easier. We're going to set spell, it's going to be equal
to player.magic, magic choice,
and so this is going to be the spell
itself. And so what we can do is we can
remove a lot of this, simplify this to
say spell.generate_damage, and then cost is
going to be spell cost. Actually, we forgot the
equal sign there, we don't even need to
do that because it's so short. What we can
do...alright. What we're going to do
down here is spell is set there, but we need
to target spell.name, and magic
damage there is a number
already, and that's all we need to do.
Actually, right here we need to say if
spell cost is more than current MP
than it fails. So I think we're good to go, I
think I did everything necessary, so I
can remove these old lines of code here,
I can save this, and let's try this again.
Oh, no, we're not gonna be able to choose
our magic because that's stored in player, so
we're going to have to put that...actually
we can't do that what we need to do is,
where's our game class?
Self magic is being set to what we set in
there, and then choose magic is now
that will work. Ok, so, we're going to list our
magic,
ok it's not gonna work and the reason is...
let's try that use an instance variable. Spell
object is not scriptable. So, let's go ahead
and import from .magic import Spell.
So, let's go ahead and look back at this.
Alright, in here
what I'm going to do what it says choose
magic I'm just going to print...
this is pretty print by the way, we are going
to pprint(self.magic), and as you can see
I've been working a lot in C++. Alright, let's go
ahead and rerun this and have a look...
ok.
So, we're able to print self magic, so
for i in self.magic:
print(i)
So it prints out each object correctly. I
should be able to target the name of
each one, and I can. So, it could be this
right here that is causing the problem because I can't
see anything else that would cause the
problems. So, let's remove this, save this,
rerun this, let's choose magic, and there we go.
We've finally got our magic working. I was looking for the problem like
there is not a problem here, but it's
just I was targeting that in the way that
you target a list and an index, rather
than how you target an object and an object
attribute, class attribute. So, that allows us to choose
our magic. We should be able here to say
we're going to choose fire, and reduce MP is not defined because cost is not defined,
so I missed something. Reduce MP is going
to be spell.cost, there we go. Let's try meteor,
meteor deals 211 damage. So, again we're
going to go with fire, and we're doing some
good damage here,, now we're losing so we
need to heal. So, we need to build in the
heal functionality, and we'll save that for
the next video, actually. I think we've done enough right now so in the next video
we're going to be focusing on creating a
heal function.