Alright, so we're able to do damage with
our magic but we also want to be able to
heal. Now instead of checking against the
name which I did previously and then the
video didn't get recorded or uploaded so
I have to re-do it again, so basically in that section of
video which technically I guess doesn't
exist
we just checked against the name. We said
if spell name equals cure the heal, but
the problem now is we've got two
cure spells but the good thing is that
they're defined both as white magic, so
we can check against the spell type
if we heal. What we're going to do is
we're going to go to our magic section.
So, if we choose magic what we need to do
here is right here outside of that if
statement, and after everything else,
so basically what's going to
happen is we get the prompt, we choose
magic, and then we actually input our
choice, and then we set spell and then the magic
damage which is basically just the value
of it either heal or damage, we're going to
call that damage even though it's not
damage it's still hit points, okay we
should have called that hit point
modification, or something. Anyway, we get
current MP and then we basically say if
there's not enough MP to do this, otherwise
we're going to do this. If spell type
equals light we're going to say, actually
we can also reduce the MP there
automatically, that's not part of the
condition, so up here above this bit of code, so
if spell type equals white we're going
to say player heal for a magic damage did we
call it?
Yes, magic damage.
Then we're going to print out
bcolors.OKBLUE, we are gonna do a new line, spell.name heals for,
and we're going to say bcolors and
ENDC. elif spell.type == "black": so if it's
black magic it's going to be attack
magic. And I put
that in an elif statement instead of just
an else statement because we might add
red magic and that status effects to our
RPG as well. Now let's go ahead and rerun
this, we're going to start by attacking,
and as we can see our hit points are
dropping quite a bit here. So, now what I'm
going to do is I'm going to choose magic, i'm
going to choose cura which cost 18, and as
you can see cura heals from 195 and my
hit points go down from to 234 - 45 + 195
and I'm left with 384 hit points. So our
cure spells do in fact work. We'll heal again
to get up to 416 and we're going to
devastate the enemy with a meteor
attack, and they have a lot of points so
doesn't really impact that much. So
that's how we heal and the enemy is
going to be able to heal as well, so it's
going to make it more difficult, and
we're actually also going to add items
in to the mix.