Ok, so, what we're going to do now is make
our elixirs and attack items work. So,
it's really simple just down here what
we're going to do is elif item.type
== "elixir" and remember we have a,
we're gonna need to also target the elixir
by name because mega elixir makes, well it
heals the entire party, and we've only got
one party member right now anyway so it
doesn't really matter. We will come back
to this in the next video, I think we're
going to add multiple party members. So, for
right now just player.hp =
player.maxhp, and player.mp =
player.maxmp.
Then what we need to do is print out what
happened.
So, bcolors.OKGREEN..."fully restores HP/MP"
And then bcolors.ENDC. elif
item.type == "attack": we say enemy.take_damage
the damage they're going to
take is
(item.prop), so whatever value it has.
So, for instance, if we use this it's going to say
okay we will do 500 damage to the enemy. I'm
going to print out, I think attack is red,
ah keyboard...
So, I'm going to say item.name deals item.prop,
"points of damage"
Alright, so to see this in action what we need
to do is
let's start off using magic,
so we're lowering our hip points and
magic points are lowering, so let's do that
one again.
Meteor and then one more, we've got 5 magic
points and we can't do much with that. Let's go
ahead and use item and the item we're going
to use is elixir. So, yourself 4, hit enter, as
you can see our hit points and magic
points restored entirely, so we know
that's working. The one thing that
doesn't work right now is the quantity.
I'm still trying to decide a way to do that, I
think what we're going to do is in here
where we create the list
we're going to set spell and then quantity in
here so that different players can have
different well item quantities. So, let's go
ahead and end this, we're going to end this
video here, and we're going to be doing
that in the, actually let's do that right
now as well. Item is going to be potion, and
quantity is going to be 5 so we will have 5 of those.
Now I'm going to copy this...
alright, cool.
So, "item":
hipotion, "quantity": let's say we have 5 of those. Let's
say we have 15 regular potions. Let's skip down another line
here, actually superpotion.
Superpotion we've
got 5, "item": here is going to be
elixir. We are going to need to change some
things within our script for this in order to work.
"item": hielixer, "quantity": 5 and then "item":
grenade. So, hielixer we'll have 2
of those, there we go.
So, what's gonna happen now when we try
and run our script and choose an item, if we
try to list the item it's going to fail. What
we need to do is get is in here when we're
listing the items...item so this is going to be
item.item.name,
item.item.description, and then here
I'm going to say str(item.quantity).
Let's go ahead and save, 'dict; object has no attribute 'item'
Let's go ahead and find out what,
so player_items is set to list,
I am not sure if that's what's wrong but let me
try.
Yep, alright, so that's what it is.
Again it's just be accessing variables and
values in the wrong way. So, as you can see
we've now got actually individual
quantities,
the only problem here is that it's causing an error.
So, let's restart that, and
that looks a little better. So, what we're going
to need to do also is reduced the
quantity of the item when we use one, so
what we need to do
in here is actually use the item as well so
i'm going to attack a little bit,
try and use a potion, no. So, player.items and
then [item_choice]...let's try that.
Alright, and then you put that after the end
I was just getting mixed up a little with the
order of how we built that object. There we go.
So, now we're able to actually see this
action, so let's go ahead and choose items.
Let's go ahead and use and we've got 5, so next
time around we need to reduce the number
that it will allow us to use. So, let's
set
item_quantity =
player.items
[item_choice] and I'm going to target
["quantity"], we're going to say item_quantity
-= 1.
There we go. So, this is going to handle now
reducing the number of the items as well.
So, 3 let's use that,
let's go back here and we can see that it didn't actually work.
So, let's print(item_quantity),
Alright, so what we need to do is we actually
need to set that directly.
Let's try this again...
potion and now you can see that this number is being reduced.
So,
what was happening before when I stored
this value in another variable we
modified the variable that we created,
but we didn't actually modified this
itself. So, what we need to do now if we
use an item that we have two of, so that's 5, so let's
use MegaElixer and we'll see that's 0, and then we go
down into the negatives. So, what we do is
we need to say if we have enough items, or
rather if player.items
[item_choice] ["quantity"] == 0:, we need to say
bcolors.
OKFAIL, skip a line, alright let's
just say "None left..." and then lets say
bcolors.EDNC, and let's continue from the top
to allow us to choose again.
Let's choose an item, let's say 5, so as you can see the MegaElixir
dropped by 1...whoops...
I need to put this before the
reduction. Otherwise, when we have one left it
would think we got 0 because it was after we
reduced it, so it would be 0 after we
actually use it,, but it would use it. So,
we've got one left, and we've got 0,
so let's try and use it again and it says none left.
So, we choose again and that's exactly what we
want, we want a way to be able to limit
its kinda like checking the mp
costs if you have enough magic points
to actually cast a spell.
So, the next video we're going to clean
up the UI a bit and probably add multiple
party members.