Hey guys, welcome back. So in this section
what we're going to be covering are
different tools and utilities, I guess
libraries, to make graphical applications.
And so that's why it's gonna be really
fun because it's cool to make command
line programs, but what's really
awesome is to make programs that anybody
can use without having to feel
comfortable in terminal. So the first
package that we're going to cover is
PyQt5 and so you actually need to
have Qt installed in order
to have this work.
So, what we need to do is we need to
first go to qt5 so www.qt.io, it's
pronounced cute, go to the downloads
section here, and I mean you can also
install it via brew, so if you want to
go ahead and brew I'm just going to
search brew search qt5 it
should return a bunch of packages and
you can build it from brew or you can
install from this right here.
So what you need to do you can either
use a commercial if you want to pay for
a license
we're just going to go ahead with
open-source. Are you prepared to make
your application publicly available, yes,
and we're going to comply with the LGPL
license, yes, then you can click the get
started button. You can go ahead and
choose a download link for your system.
If you want to view all downloads you can
do that. You can either use an online
installer or offline installer. Now the
difference between the two is an online
installer works like the chrome
installer works. The initial download is
really small as you can see 11 megabytes
here, and once you launch that then
that installer goes to the internet and
downloads a whole bunch of necessary
packages, I think it's around a
gigabyte of a download it may be about 700
megabytes, 800, something like that. So you're going
to download that and install it. Now the
easiest
way to do that would be to compile
from brew so just run brew install
qt5. Now once you've done that you
need to install two packages from pip. So
go ahead and run pip3 install sip and
pyqt5. I've already got these two
installed you're gonna need both, so
sip and pyqt5. This is gonna be
the package were working with but this
won't work without this so that's why we
need to install that. So, once you've got
qt5 installed, pyqt5, and sip
we're now ready to actually get programming,
and the installation is probably going
to take a bit of time so feel free to
pause this video here and come back when
you've got all this set up. Now what I
I'm going to do is I'm going to open up
pycharm here, and we're going to write a
really simple program, and then we're
going to go over some documentation in
the next few videos, and then we're going
to get really deep into it. I'm going to go
ahead and create a new project, going to
call it qt5test, and we're
going to use the default py3
interpreter here, and I'm going to go
ahead and create a Python file called
main as we normally do.
Now the first thing we're going to do is create
crunchbang here, usr/bin/python3.
This should be done in every program, I
don't think we've done it yet, but you're
going to want to. Then we're going to
start importing packages. So the way we
do this is pyqt5 has multiple
classes that have classes within them,
and so what we need to do is go
from PyQt5.QtCore import *
and we're just going to import
everything for now, and the same thing
for widgets. So, from PyQt5.QtWidgets
import * everything.
So the first thing we're gonna do is
we're going to create a class that is
going to have our basic page in there,
it's gonna be really stupidly simple
right now, so let's go ahead and create a
class called Page, and it's going to
inherit from (QWidget): We need that
inheritance there. So now we're going to
define an initialization function where
we actually build out the page itself.
So go ahead and def __init__(self):
So, in order to instantiate this we
need to do something a bit
different and
we need to instantiate the parent as
well. So how we do that is super, we're
going to instantiate the Page class that
we just created, pass it self, and then
we're going to add .__init__ and then
we're going to instantiate the (parent).
Unresolved reference to parent, alright.
In init I actually need to pass
parent=None just that it's set by default and
it's going to be set afterwards. So, what
we're going to do we're just going to
create a label, so let's make
this peppy, my_label = QLabel, and
then it's really simple in here you just
put whatever text you want to be there
so ("This is my label") And then what we're going
to do is we're going to create a
layout kind of button. So we're going to
create a widget called
qvbox layout. So I'm going to name this
layout = to QVBoxLayout
just like that, and you don't
need to
pass anything to that to instantiate it.
What we're going to do at this point is
we're going to add the my label into the
layout. So how we do that is you type out
the name of the layout, so in this case
it's layout.addWidget, and we're
going to add (my_label). What we're going
to do at this point we're going to...
that's it for now, let's just go ahead
and do this. Let's create a grid layout in
here, so we're going to create a
mainLayout = QGridLayout( ), and then
we're going to put our layout into the
main layout, I should have named these a bit
differently. So, mainLayout.addLayout and
we're going to add a (layout) in here. And
then here need to put since it's a grid
need to choose how many rows and columns
you need. Alright, now we're going to
set the layout, so self.setLayout it's going to be
(mainLayout). And then we're going to set
the title of the window so this is
what's going to appear up in the title bar
right there. So self.setWindowTitle and
we're going to name it ("My First Qt App")
I hope this has made sense so far. Then down here
we're actually going to instantiate the
application itself, so go ahead and write if
__name__ == "__main__": we always need this
when we're creating a package,
especially in qt5 this is how we're going
to be doing it through the entire thing.
Let's go ahead and import sys, this is
what we're going to need to be able to
exit the app. Let's go ahead and let's
assign a variable here called app, it's
going to be equal to QApplication, going
to pass in (sys.argv). This is going to be system
arguments, in this case they're going to
be none. So let's create the window
itself. So window equals our class there,
it's going to be Page, and then we're going to show
our window. So if we don't run this the
windows just going to be blank it's
never going to show it. Then we need to
call an exec function which is going to
execute the window itself, not in a bad
way in a good way, it's going to make it
you know instantiate, so we're going to
put that in to a sys.exit call, and
we're going to exec just like that.
We're going to save this, and we're going
to run the file, and we should see this right
here. This is our first qt app. As you
can see it has full capabilities of any
other application, it looks really stupid
right now, but that's what we've
done. We've actually created a graphical
user interface using python and we're
going to extend this a lot farther. So, I
hope you guys got everything set up
correctly, I hope I've explained this well,
we're going to go over documentation to
see all the different kinds of widgets
and elements that we could use
within qt5, and we're going to be
using a lot of them coming up in the
next few videos.