Alright, so, what we're going to be doing
now is entering these buttons in a more
dynamic way. Now when we think about how
we're going to be adding the buttons we
don't want to be typing all of them out
right there. So what we're going to do is
remove all this, so remove the button
declarations and the adding the widgets.
What we're going to do is we're going to
create a list called buttons, and it's
going to be in the order of the buttons
we want. So on the top row we want to see
an AC button, this is going to reset it,
it's going to be a placeholder for now,
placeholder, and division. On the next row
we want the numbers 7, 8, 9, and
multiply. On the next row we want 4, 5, 6,
and minus, put the plus down under it. On
the next row we want 1, 2, 3, and
then plus, and on the very bottom line we
want 0, a decimal, and then the equal
sign. So what we're going to do with this
is we're going to say for button in buttons,
add a button to the grid. So how
we're going to do that we need to know
how many rows and columns have been used
up. So, let's go ahead and for button in
buttons: we are going to need a few
variables. So, row, the current row that
we're on, and then column is going to be the
current column we're on, so they're both going
to start at zero. So what we're going to
do here is grid.addWidget and we're
going to add the button itself,
but we're going to add a QPushButton.
So, the widget that we're going to
be adding to the grid is a QPush
Button with the button's value in it because
we're accessing that through here. Now some of
these are going to be strings and some
of them are integers, so what we need to
do is manually create strings just in
case it is an integer. And now we need to
set the rows and column number. So, for
instance it's going to be row, column,
and then 1 and 1. And then what we
need to do is increase row, so row +=,
actually no col += row, and we
need to be able to set the row
based on how many columns have been
used. So, this is going to be a little
confusing. In the beginning of this
loop here we're going to say if column
is more than 3,
we're going to set column = to 0, so
we're going to start over again, then we're
going to set row += 1 so this is going
to make it skip rows.
Let's go ahead and save this, and run the
application, and as you can see we've
magically built our calculator already
within a grid simply by iterating
through these numbers. One thing you'll
notice though is at the bottom here it
doesn't really look right. So, what we're
going to do is we're going to make this
take up two columns, and the way we're
going to do that is basically if button
== 0:
we're going to do something different. So,
grid.addWidget(QPushButton) and it's
going to take in string button, and then the other
parameters we're going to say row, column, it's
going to take up 1 row and 2 columns.
So that's what's going to happen if our
button is the 0, otherwise it's just going to
do what we just told it to do before we
added that bit of code.
So now we should see that our 0 is two spaces wide,
and what we're going to have to do is we
need to tell it that we've just used two
spaces so that the next one should go
into the next column, and so we're going
to set column here += 1 again. This
is going to increment it by the correct
amount, and basically what's happening,
what happened before is 0 was set to
column 0, and the period was still set to
column 1 even though this one is
taking up two spaces, so we just add an
additional 1 into the column variable,
in addition to the other one that we're
already adding. I hope that makes sense.
Now what we've got here is the basic
calculator itself but it's not going to
work just yet, and that's because there's
no button event. So, what we're going to
do is to wrap up this video we're just going
to create a line edit up here on the
top. So, our results is going to be equal
to QLineEdit, and then before we start
adding the buttons and everything we're
going to say I grid.addWidget, and we're
going to add the results in row 0, 0,
actually, yeah we can do this. It's going to
take up 4 rows, and
4 lines, and then we're going to
manually adjust the row here so that
the buttons start on row 1. We're going
to rerun the application, and we're going
to see something that's a little bit
messed up. So what we're going to do is
we're going to set this to use one row,
yeah that's my mistake, that was set to
use four rows instead of one. So now
our calculator is looking a bit better and
we can actually type stuff in, but it
doesn't do anything just yet.