Alright, now the next problem we're
going to face is that we can't add each
one of these push buttons, we can't
connect that to a handler for the
click event, and then pass in additional
methods because it's going to not know
which button was clicked, basically. So what
we need to do we're going to create a
class up here for our bottoms, and that's
going to inherit from nothing actually, it's
just going to create a button and then give it
it's own method to to call it's click. So, class
Button:
and we're going to say def __init__(self): and down
here it's going to create a button so
self.b = QPushButton, and it's
going to take the text, and we need to
actually pass that in here so text, then
we're also going to pass in results.
You're going to pass in text there,
we're going to set self.text equal to
text, and this is so we can reference
elsewhere, then we're going to set the
input or the results area where it's
going to show the results to results. Now
we're going to connect the button to it's
own event handler. So self.b
which is the button itself, clicked, and we're
going to connect it to a message that
we're going to call handleInput, and
it's going to be part of this class so
self.handleInput.
So let's go ahead and create that. Now,
unfortunately, this method needs to be
able to pass in a variable, so v for value.
Now if we try to do this, so let's
just print out "clicked" v, actually we can
just to that. What we're going to do in here
is instead of creating the QPush
Button within the grid what we're going
to do is we're going to set a button to
the grid, and then add the button in
there. So let's go ahead, if that sounded
a little confusing
don't worry, it it was supposed to. So
b is going to be equal to Button, and
we're going to pass in the buttons text.
We're also going to pass in our results
input here, and as you guys remember this
is going to call this class up here, and it's
going to pass in the text of the
button itself, and then the input area so
that we can modify that when we need to.
What we're going to do is we're just
going to, we're just going to add the button
itself, so button.b I think that's
what we called up here...
yeah, button.b is the push button
itself.
So I'm going to save this and rerun the
application, and it says name 'v' is not
defined so that's what's going to happen
when we try to pass arguments into a
connected slot within an event handler
for a qt widget. So how we're going to
solve that is we are going to use lambda,
and I can discuss this more in different
methods if that makes sense, but
we're going to set that to text so self,
text, and now we can capture that v in
here if I connect it...string object has
no attribute 'b' so where is that? Widget button
b...
oh, I set that to b here. So button is
the actual string, i need to change this
name to buttonObject, let's say. The
object and that's the problem when we
start using a lot of variables is it's hard
to make different variables make sense.
So this says arguments did not match
overloaded call, so self.b equals Q
PushButton and text. So the problem there...
let me let me just check here.
OK,
unexpected type integer. Alright, okay,
that's because some of the values were
passing in here are integers, so we're
gonna wrap it in text just to make sure that
all buttons are being created with the
labels in text. So as you can see it
still creates our buttons, but now it's
printing out that we're actually clicking
whatever we're clicking. So that's cool we
need to now make this make sense.