Alright guys, so we're just going to
recap here, and I'm going to see if
I did miss explaining anything I'm going
to explain it better just to kind of
bring you guys up to date. Just in case you skipped
any videos, or are watching this out of context.
So what we're doing here is we're
creating a grid layout, and then we're
creating a few objects themselves. The
first one is results which is just a
line edit and that's right here, then
we're creating a list of buttons and
we've got them segmented into four
columns on each row, and we're using
actual integers for the numbers and that's so
that we can actually run mathematical
equations on them when the time comes.
We're starting at row 1 and that's going
to make more sense once I do this, so I'm
going to copy that.
So we're adding the input to our grid
right away on row 0, it is in column 0 so
it starts in the first column in the
first row, it's one row high, and then
it's four rows wide, and that's because
we're going to have four rows everywhere
else so it's going to make it the same
length.
Once we use the first row we need to set
the row variable equal to 1 because
we're going to be using that within a
loop to create the buttons, and then the
column is going to be 0. So then what we
do is for each item in the buttons
variable here we're saying if the column
is greater than 3 so if it's 4,
so if we've gone 1, 2, 3, 4, then what you want to
do is you want to reset it to 0 and then
skip down to the next line. So, column
equals 0 and then row +=1. We're
instantiating our custom button class
right here, and we'll talk more about that in
a moment, and then we're saying if the
button is 0
we're going to make it take up two
spaces. So we create the button object up
here, we put the push button itself so
the b attribute of the button object is
the push button itself, we're setting the row
and column numbers, we are going to say take
up one row and take up two columns,
and then we skip over the next column
number by adding one to the column, and
if it's not the number zero just you
know add, it's the exact same statement it's
just adding a button in one column
rather than taking up two columns. Then
at the end of the loop each iteration is
going to add one to column. Now in order to
successfully actually connect a method
to each button, each button is going to
have it's on the handle input method, and
it's going to print out the value of
self.text which is being set to the
number on here. So when I click this you
can see that it's printing it down here
which button I'm clicking, which isn't really
useful as of now. So what we're going to
be doing is we're actually going to be
evaluating the equation that we're
putting in, but first what we want to do
is we want to get the text of the input
there. So, let's say
current value is equal to self.results.
text, and then we're going to
set new value, it's going to be equal to
current value plus, we're going to wrap in the string
here,
whatever value we passed into
it. So let's go ahead and set self.results,
set text equal to new value. So
go ahead and save this, and rerun the
application, and now when we hit numbers
you'll see that they actually go into
this but it still doesn't do
anything yet. So what we're going to do
is we're going to create an if statement
in here. So if v is equal to equals, which
basically is the the button press, so if
the buttons value is to equal symbol
we're going to evaluate, so we're going
to create a res object
shortened for results, because we are already using
results.
It's going to be equal to eval and we're going
to evaluate self.results.text. So,
let's say we type 4 + 5, res then is
going to evaluate to 9, and then we're
going to set self.results.setText
equal to string, going to set it to
result. And we're going to say else do
this, so it's just going to add to the
input. So let's go ahead and cancel out of
the application, run it again, and say
4+5 equals 9. You guys can see that
that's actually happening, or 5, I can't
delete, that's a problem.
Let's go ahead and add a delete button
here. So, AC is going to be the reset
button, so what we'll do is ekuf v equals
"AC" we're just going to set the results
self.results.setText, going
to set it to nothing so that we can
actually cancel out there. So, let's restart
the app. 5 * 5 equals 25, and then press
AC and it clears it out.
Awesome! So, what we're going to do at
this point, I mean we've got a working
calculator for the most part, let me see
if there's anything else we got to do
here. 9/5 equals, I want to be able to
calculate the square root here. So, I'm
going to be replacing some of these
buttons here. Let me open up Safari,
search square root symbol
so I can copy and paste it here, and it's
right there. So I'm going to go ahead and
copy this, and let's replace the C
button with that. We're going to
replace this with %. elif v equals
square root, and
I'm just copying and pasting that so
just copy-paste. e're going to calculate
the square root and in order to do that
we need to import math, and then down
here in the square root method right
here we basically just convert the
value to a float, and then we set the value
of the results line input equal to,
you'll see in a moment. So,, let's go ahead
and create a value, I guess, value equals
float self.results.text, and then
we're going to say self.results.setText
equal to, we need to wrap this in
strings so that it becomes a string,
we're going to take math.sqrt
and pass in value.
I'm going to save this and rerun the
application, and if I say 25 square root
it becomes 5.0. If I say 30
square root it becomes 5.4. So if I say 36
square root it becomes 6. That's now working as
intended.
We want to be able to erase just the
last button there.
So what I'm going to do is we need to
create I think another row, which is very
unfortunate because this is arranged
alright
already. So let's just erase this one
right here and type DEL. So what we're going to
do is elif v equals "DEL" we're going to
get the value, so current_value equals
self.results.text, and then we're
going to slice the last character
off of that text. So what we need to do
is convert it to a string first, actually it
should already be a string,
yeah it's strength. Alright, that's already
a string. So what we are going to have to do is
remove the last character, and actually
will do this in the next video to finish
up this project.