Alright guys, so to finish off this set
of videos what we're going to be doing is
we're going to be finishing up this delete
function here. So, in the last video what
i did was I have replaced one of the
buttons with one that says DEL, and then in the
handle input for that button we check if
it's equal to delete, then we're going to
get the current value, and then we're
going to, we're basically just going to
set the current value equal to the
current value minus the last
character. So, let's go ahead and type
self.results.setText equal to
current value, and then you open it up as
a list, put a colon, and 1, or minus 1, sorry. So I'm going to save
this, and run the app, I'm going to type 55, we're going to
delete, and as you can see it works. So 84
x 99, and we can delete each number,
and then perform operations on that, or
just reset it right there. So that is our
calculator guys, and this is as you can
see a lot of Python here. I'd like to see
your calculator, I will host this
code on github as well so you guys can go
ahead and look at my code. I will add
comments to it before I upload it as well.
So thanks for watching this, in the next
video I think we're going to start
creating a text editor.