Alright guys, welcome back. In the last
video we learned how to actually create
a qt window and the basic application
and you could follow that path and build
programmatic interfaces in Python itself,
however since pyqt5 QML has been a
thing and what QML is it's I believe it
stands for the qt markup language, and
it's more declarative the way that it's
written works more like a mix between
javascript, and HTML, and CSS rather than
you know python and so that's what we're
going to be learning today. When you
install pyqt5 you instantly get
access to QML through qt quick
it's called, it's a module installed in pyqt5.
So, what we're going to do is we're going
to create a new application, it's going to
be again just a basic application, but
we're going to do it in QML so you guys
can kind of see how to do this, and then
we're going to be following that path
further to make some awesome applications.
So, the first thing we need is obviously
a crunchbang, so #!usr/bin/python3, and
then we're going to import some things.
So, we're going to import os, sys and
then from PyQt5.QtCore import * we're
going to import everything for right now.
From PyQt5.QtGui import *
import everything, and we may not end up
using some of this but we're going to
important anyway. You are going to also import
from PyQt5.QtQuick import *
Alright, now what we're going to be
doing at this point is basically
building a qml application, and so how
we do that is in the
if__name__  == "__main__": we're going to
instantiate the application so we're
going to create a variable called
app =  QGuiApplication
and we're going to pass in (sys.argv),
then we need to create an engine. So what
an engine does is it connects the
main qml it's the qml application engine
that we can use to use qml in our
applications. So I'm going to create a
variable called engine and it's going to
be = QQmlApplicationEngine, and it
doesn't look like it picked it up so I'm
just going to make sure that I imported
everything.
Alright, now our engine once we get it
created we're going to have to load, we
need to load a qml file. So we haven't
created it yet but we're going to be
calling it main.qml. So let's go
ahead and write engine.load and here
we're going to load a (QUrl) so
this is going to make...that doesn't look
right...
QUrl, and in here the URL path we're
going to be fromLocalFile,
and then all we have to do is
add a string here representing the file
path. So it's gonna be ("main.qml")
This is going to load up our qml
and then what we're going to do is we're
just going to show
everything, so we need to target we need
to create a window variable equal to
window = engine.routeObjects( )[0] and this is
actually a method, root objects is a method
that returns route objects from the
engine, so this is going to be the first
node in our main qml file which is going
to be an application window. Then we're
going to write window.show( ), and then
sys.exit(app.exec_( ) ). Alright,
so this is literally all we need in
Python, now we can start building out a qml
file. So I'm going to go ahead and create
a file called main.qml, and
unfortunately we are not going to have
syntax highlighting in this with
pycharm, so that's unfortunate. However,
we're going to deal with that,
alright. So in qml we need to make some
imports as well. Now if you're
up to date on this the versions
should be similar but you can always go
look at the 5.x documentation
on qts
website and they should show you some
examples of library versions. So,
import QtQuick 2.7, again we have no
syntax highlighting, we have no
auto-completion, but that's fine for
right now. We're going to import
QtQuick.Window 2.2, import QtQuick.Controls
1.4, these are all different version
numbers I know, import QtGraphicalEffects 1.0
Now in addition to this I mean this
should be fine for what we're doing
right now actually so let's go ahead and
and get some stuff rolling. So, we're
actually going to start writing in qml
now so this is going to be different
from python you're probably going to
recognize, I mean again it's declarative
so it's more similar to HTML, CSS, and
JavaScript than anything else, so we need
to create our route object in this case
it's going to be ApplicationWindow, and how you
open up elements in qml is you put curly
braces like that. Now we're going to give
it an id: equal mainWindow, and this
is so that if we want to change anything to
do with this from other elements we can
do it and in that case it's kind of like
JavaScript and i'll show you guys that
in a moment. We're going to set the
height for right now the default is
going to be 160, and the width is going
to be say 300,
and we're going to create an item in
here. So, go ahead create an element
called item and this is going to be our
main page that we're going to be putting
stuff into. So go ahead and give it an id:
page, and again right now this isn't
really important to give them all ids.
Visible is going to be set true we need
to do this in order to make the window
of the application itself visible, and
then the width of this is going to be
parents.width. Now what we're going to
do is add a rectangle in here, if I can spell
it correctly, and as you guys can see
creating elements is very similar
as you go down, so it's again like HTML.
We're gonna take away some space there
to keep the attributes separate from the
child elements. Height is going to be 160, so the
same as the main window, and you can do
this in JavaScript as well. So, let's go
ahead how you add javascript to a
property here is you open up curly
brackets and in here you can type stuff
like regular JavaScript, and then you can
return 160. Now it's important to note
that in here you do not use semi-colons
to end statements,
it's kind of like JavaScript but it's
not really javascript. We will go over the
differences soon. Now the color we're
going to set it to is going to be lets
say, actually you don't need quotes there,
going to be not white because that's the
default color so let's go with red.
And now we're going to create text, the
text node itself.
So go ahead and create text, the property in
here that's going to be relevant is text. In
here you can type in "I am some regular
text" Now we're going to set the height
of this to 50, we're going to set the width
equal to parents width so parent.width,
and we're going to set the pixel size, so
in in CSS you type font size, here you
will type font.pixelSize and i'm
going to set it to 12, and then you can
also set some other parameters in here
but I'm not going to this should be
enough right now. I'm going to go ahead
and save this, I'm going to run the main
file, and we should see a window you
created...engine.rootObjects index out
of range.
Alright, well that's not good at all.
Let's come back here and have a look...
we got the application created.
That's unexpected token, so that's
because in here we have that. We could
escape that then restart. Line 22
don't need to put these quotes I
believe, I think you should just work
like regular x colors...
There we go and as you can see we've got,
let me toggle back here let's focus on it,
we've now got a window that just has
some regular text here. Now what we could
do is we can move this text around, we
can set the window title, and in fact
that's what we're going to be doing
first.
So, in order to set the window title
you're just going to give the application
window a title: "My Window" so save it
and restart it. You're going to see now the
window has a title called my window and
we can also move it. Now we can also set
other properties in here and we're going
to be going over that in the next video.
We're going to be going over
different elements and how we can use
them, and then we'll get into making some
programs.