Hey guys, welcome back. So we learned how
to create some qml elements and we haven't
even touched on it yet. So I'm actually
going to go back one page here and the
controls all of these elements become
available when we import QtQuick
controls right here, and so we're going to be
using some of them in this application.
So what we're going to do is first off
we're going to create a button with the id:
mainbutton, and let me just click in
here so you guys can see an example too.
Basically, all it takes right now is
going to be a text property. So as you
can see here that's going to create a
button.
Let's jump in here and add text to say
"Push Me" going to save this and run the
application, and you're going to see this.
This is a very pretty application so far.
We've got a button overlaying text so we
can't see what the text says. So how we're
going to fix that in qml basically
everything needs to be positioned to
some degree. Now you can import a layout, it's
QtQuick layouts, and we're going to be
talking about layouts later. For right now
we're going to be adding an id: to text
and we're going to call it mainText, and so in
in the text here we can we can define
some anchors, you can go anchors.top: and
you can set the
position based on the top in pixels from
the top.
That sounds a little complicated so what
I'm going to do is I'm going to set this
top equal to this bottom and what should
happen is our button will show up
underneath the text. So anchors.top:
mainText.bottom and this seems
pretty simple. Going to refresh the
application, and
as you can see it's actually worked and
this is because we've set the height of
the main text to 50, so this is 50
pixels right here. Now we can also center
content and we're going to talk about
that a little bit as well.
You can basically center items
horizontally or vertically and we're
going to talk about that right now. Right
here we're going to set horizontal
alignment, so horizontalAlignment: is
going to be equal to TextAlignHCenter
and this means horizontally centered.
We're going to save it, refresh, and
something went terribly wrong here.
This is 300 pixels wide. So let's set the width,
it's actually maybe not getting that
property in there. Let's start this again.
There we go. So when we created the
rectangle it was actually technically 0
pixels wide. That's also why it wasn't red, I
didn't even notice that it wasn't red there.
And then this we're going to set anchors
and you can open it up like this too. So
we can say top: it's going to be 20,
and that's it for now. You could create a
list of all of the different anchor
points.
Alright, I will have to check into
that. That worked maybe in an older version,
maybe I did it correctly. Unsupported
type "QQuickAnchorLine" does text not
have access to that? I don't think it
does.
You can also set padding though but for
right now we're just going to run this
application, we're going to center the
button as well. So you can see a list of
all of the members for the button
including what it will inherit from others. So,
clicked is a method here, we can use
anchors.bottom, bottomMargin, etc,
alignWhenCentered, horizontalCenter, etc. So,
what we're going to do at this point,
we're gonna make it do something...so
what we're going to do at this point is
we're going to make it do something when
we click it. So I'm going to quit the application
there, and then what we're going to do is
on clicked, I'm going to to open up some JavaScript here,
and we're going to set the main page
here so let me give the rectangle an id:
of myrectangle, and we're going to set
myrectangle.color = "#000" As
you can see it does that. Now what we can do
is we can say if my color is black, so
if(myrectangle.color == "#000")
we're going to actually turn it red.
Wow, my keyboard sucks today...else we're going to
turn it black.
Let's go ahead and save this, rerun the
application, we should now have a button
that works as a toggle...it doesn't. So
let's print out the console.log
(myrectangle.color) Let's see what color
were getting back from qml here.
Alright, so it actually takes you from
the shorthand into the standard right
there.
So if we push it and push it...
I'm setting colors not color.
Wow, okay, there we go.
Let's refresh and this should now work as a toggle
button, and it does. You can also set the
the color of the text as well if you
just add color going to set this to gray.
I need to put that in quotations. Alright,
start and there we go. Now you can see it no
matter what. We could also change how
that looks as well based on the
button click we could turn it white or black.
So we're not going to do that right now,
but you guys to see a bit of event
handling here embedded into each element
that you create, and also why the ids
come in handy, and how you can change
properties on the fly.