Hey guys, welcome back. We are not going
to learn more qml within this section
just because qml is something for
another tutorial series all on its own,
or in another course. What we're trying to
learn here is Python and so when we're using
pyqt what we're going to be doing
from here on out is programming the
interface in Python. So, what you're
looking at right here is the native
calculator app of mac OS, and the reason
you're seeing it is because we are going
to be building a calculator. Now before
we get to that we actually need to
understand some other things about pyqt,
and so the first thing we're going
to be doing is just talking about
different layouts that a pyqt
application can have. So I'm going to go
ahead and open up my pycharm here, I've
already created a project called
calculator because that is what we are
going to be building coming up here. So
what we need to do is we need to before
we even start I want to talk about
different layouts, and so when you create
a pyqt app it's every widget that you
create is just going to throw it into
the UI. Now you can absolutely position stuff,
so you can tell it you know where it
should be on the screen, and that's kind of
static, it's always going to be in that
exact position within your application.
So a layout is a way to basically create
a layout. So you can create a vertical
layout, a horizontal layout, or a grid
layout. Now for the calculator obviously
we're going to be using a grid, so we're
going to cover some of the other ones
here first so you guys can understand
them. So the first thing we need to do is
make some imports so we're going to
import sys for the system-level
operations, and then we're going to be
including some pyqt widgets that
we're going to be using here. So, go ahead
and type from PyQt5.QtWidgets
import. In here what we're going to want
right now we're just going to import a
few that we're actually going to be using. So,
we're going to import QWidget, obviously,
QApplication, these two are essential
just to get the application to run, and
then we're going to import some layouts so
QHBoxLayout and QVBoxLayout, and then
also QPushButton. So those are our
imports. Now, something you'll notice that
I want to cover right now is that this
line will end up getting really, really, really long, and
so what you're going to want to do is
use multiple lines there. So the way
you're going to do that for an import is
wrap all of the imports in brackets, and
then you can split it up into multiple
lines until it looks right. This is going
to keep the import statement all as one.
So now down here we're going to actually
create our window that we're going to be
working with, or this is the main widget.
So let's go ahead and create a class
called main window, and the main window
class that we're creating is going to
inherit from the QWidget class. Now
we need to set the initialization
function and this is going to basically
run all of our code as soon as this
initializes. So, go ahead and define the
init function, and now we're going to
initialize the parent, which is a QWidget
class here, so let's go ahead and type
super which is a method, and then init.
Now once the qwidget is initialized
within our main window class, what we're
going to have to do is call a function,
we could put all our code right in here but
in an effort to make this more readable
we're going to create a self.init_ui,
and then we're going to create that
function here. And this init_ui that
we're building here is going to
actually
run all of our code. So, the first thing we
need to do is create our buttons, and so
the way that you create a button is you
create a variable to instantiate the
object that is a qt push-button. So
let's go ahead and name it
okButton, and it's going to be equal to
QPushButton, and noticed the
capitalization within here Q and P.
Basically with the pyqt framework
it's camelcase, so the beginning of each word
in the statement itself is
capitalized. And then we're going to pass
in a variable and this is going to
become the text that is on the button. So
in this case we're just gonna say "OK"
and then cancel button is going to be
the same QPushButton except this one
is going to say "Cancel" Now what we can
do is we can put both of these into an
HBoxLayout, and HBox again is
horizontal so it's going to position
each thing as necessary to have them
horizontally interesting line. So let's
go ahead and make a horizontal variable
and it's going to be equal to QHBoxLayout,
and this does not take in any
arguments or anything so we don't need
past anything in there, and we're going
to make it stretch so it's going to be
dynamic in the way that it looks. So
we're going to say horizontal.addStretch,
and then we're going to start adding our
previously created widgets, which
QPushButton is here, we're going to start
adding those into the HBoxLayout. So,
what we need to do is type horizontal.
addWidget and when you call add widget
on the layout it's going to allow you to
add a widget. So examples of a widget in
qt are a label, a push button, a notebook
or tabbed interface that's a widget as well,
and so you can basically use this add
widget method of a horizontal box layout,
or vertical box layout, or a grid layout,
and you can use this method to actually
stuff things into that layout. So we're
going to say okButton, and then
horizontal.addWidget(cancelButton). So, what
we're going to do since this is the qwidget
and this is the main window we can
target it by using self, so this is going to
be equal to mainwindow.setlayout.
So what we're going to do is we just type
self.setLayout and then we tell
it what layout we want to use in case we
create multiple ones. So in this instance
our layout is called horizontal and the
layout is of a horizontal box layout
type. Now once we set the layout we can then
set the window title, and
then we're just going to show its, so
self.setWindowTitle("Horizontal Layout"), and then
self.show. Now this in and of itself
isn't actually going to do anything
because we need to actually run the code
at the bottom of script, so w're going to type if __name__
== '__main__': first we need to instantiate
our app so app = QApplication,
and we're just going to pass in the
system's arguments which there aren't
any. And then we set the
window object to MainWindow, and then we
just tell it to run. So how we're going
to run it is we're going to type
sys.exit, so this means until it exits it's
going to run this code so we are going to
run app.exec_( ).
So we can save this and we can run this
now, and you're going to actually see
what all of our hard work has done.
Ok, I don't know why it showed me that. So as you
can see there is a horizontal layout and
it doesn't stretch, so let's go ahead and
add that one in there, and it still
doesn't stretch. Alright,
oh it's stretching, okay, yeah, because you
can see these are like that the buttons
themselves are not stretching but
the layout is definitely stretching. As
you can see these are moving. So that is
the horizontal box layout. Now what
happens when I just change this one
letter here to V, so now it's a vertical
layout. So if I run it you're going to
see that the buttons are now in a
vertical dimension. So what we're going
to do is we're going to create a vertical
layout, and then put the horizontal
layout within it.
So, let's set this back to a HBoxLayout, and
we're going to create a variable called
vertical which is equal to QVBoxLayout,
and then we're going to say
vertical.addStretch because we want this to
we resize when we actually resize it, and
then we're going to add the horizontal
layout to the vertical layout. So, we're
going to say vertical.setLayout,
actually it's addLayout sorry,
horizontal, and then we're going to set
the main layout to vertical. So I'm going
to save this and run it again, and you're
going to see now that there's different,
I can't really see so what I'm going
to do is I'm going to throw in a label
in there as well. So we will talk about that
as well. So after QPushButton right
here it's within the QT widgets
directories I guess we're going to say
QLabel. And up at the top here we're
just going to create a label called
label, it's going to be equal to QLabel, and
it's going to say "Hi there, I'm a label.
Woot."
Now what we're going to do is we're
going to add to the vertical here, we're
going to add a widget. So vertical.
addWidget, and we're going to add label.
So now when I save I can go ahead and run it you're
going to see that it appears on the top,
so there are different sections here as
you can see. And those are basically what
layouts do. So if again if I add a
vertical layout to a vertical layout and
then use that it's going to show it all
on different lines here, and that's what
you know that's to be expected, I guess,
If you understand vertical and
horizontal or X &amp; Y. So that is basically
the two layout options that you have but
there's also a grid layout, and we're
going to go more into that when we build the
calculator, so we're not really going to
talk about it right now.