Alright guys, so I'm going to actually
remove everything from the init_ui
method right now except for setWindowTitle
and the show method, because what
we're going to be doing now is we're just
going to create a very simple graphical
application using horizontal and vbox
layouts. And so we are going to create a
button here first, so button is going to
equal to QPushButton, and it's going to
say "Set Name" And this is going to be
added to the bottom row, so we're
gonna set that there for now, and
above the button instantiation here
we're going to create both a label and a
QLineEdit which is basically a
text input, that's what it's called here
in qt. So, let's go ahead and create a
label and it's going to be equal to
QLabel("Name: "), and then label let's name
it name_input. It's going to be equal to
QLineEdit, and this doesn't take in any
parameters. So, what we need to do now
once we've got these three things
created, i'm going to drop down a few lines, we're
going to create our horizontal layout
first. So we're just going to name it h
just for simplicity here, and we're gonna say
QHBoxLayout. We're going to add stretch
to that so h.addStretch, and then we're going
to start adding our two widgets to the
first line. So, in this instance it's
going to go like this h.addWidget(label),
and then
h.addWidget(name_input). Now we're going to
create a vertical box layout and we're
going to add the button down under the
horizontal line there. So, let's just type
v for vertical, and we're going to create
QVBoxLayout, going to say v.addStretch, and
then we're going to add the layout so
v.addLayout and we're going to say h, and
then we're going to add our button. So
v.addWidget and we're going to add button
here. Now what we're going to do we've
got everything set except we need to
tell the main window that we're going to
be using the vertical layout as the top
level. So, self.setLayout and then we set it to v. Now
we're going to save this and run the
application and we see that we have a
name input here, and what I'm going to
do is I'm going to remove that
add.Stretch and rerun this application, and
now you'll see that it actually does
stretch now. So, I'm going to remove the
stretch from vertical as well.
So, we've got a name input and we can
actually type in here but it doesn't do
anything. So, what we're going to do in
the next video we're actually going to
talk about event handling within
Python here. So we did a bit of qml
event handling and we're going to learn
how to do the same thing in Python.