Alright guys, what we're going to do in
this video is just discuss the button
a little bit more, and we're going to
be specifically talking about signals
and slot. So, this is related to C++
because qt's native bindings are C++. So
you're going to see a bit of C++ code
here and it's cool if you're not sure
what it does because this is not a C++
course. What we're going to be doing is
using this to understand the basic
concepts of the widgets that we're using
and we're going to basically implement
this within pyqt. We should be
able to access clicked, pressed, released,
and toggled, these are inherited from the
Q abstract button here and they are
events, they're signals that we can hook into.
Also destroyed and custom context menu
requested. So, we're not going to be
focusing on this at all. What we're going
to be doing is just looking through here
you can set the icon, you can set
position and sizing, you can set event handles, and
whatnot. So let's go ahead and what we're
going to do is just go through some
connections here. Now in C++ it looks a
bit more complicated but in Python it's
basically just running a method where it
has a callback method. So what we're
going to do is in order to access any of
these right here you need to first type
the object's name, in this case it's button,
and then access it like you would access
any class methods anywhere else. So
clicked and then we're going to do
.connect. And PyCharm is
going to complain that connect isn't
found,
don't worry about it PyCharm is just out
of date with pyqt's bindings
I guess. So, anyway, what we're going to do
in here is we're going to pass a
function as a slot. So, think about it
like this, a signal is something that's
emitted from an object so when you click
the button the signal that's submitted is
hey I've been clicked, and then we're
going to connect it to a slot which is
actually going to make
the program able to respond to user
input.
So let's go ahead down here and let's
define another function called
action, well to make it a little easier to
understand I'm going to call it clicked, and
all its gonna do is print out "This
button has been clicked." The method is
actually now called clicked button. And
then up here we just need to type
self.clickedButton, and do not put the
parentheses after putting the
callback method in here, it will break, I'll
show you how to pass arguments
into slots in a moment.
So, first let's go ahead and save this
and now run the file here, and now when
we click the button you'll see each time
we click it it prints out this button has
been clicked.
So, let's try another one here, let's try
released. Whoops...alright, I replaced the wrong
part here. So, button.released.connect
let's run this, what's going to
happen now is when you hit down on the
button it doesn't do anything but when
you lift up it's going to print that out.
So you can have different methods,
pressed.connect(self.pressButton).
Then we're gonna come down here and
pressButton, and
we're going to print out "Button is
being pressed" and I think I want to throw
a variable there, we'll see in a moment. So
we're going to run this and we're going
to press the button, and we're going to
hold it down, and then we're going to
release it and it says the button has
been released. So, it's being held down,
it's been released. So that's a few of
the, a few of the methods within the button
itself, or events that we can hook  into,
you can also set the buttons name. So
let's go ahead and type "Clicked" so we're
going to measure how many times it
has been clicked,, so up here we're going to
set self.counter going to be equal
to 0. What we're going to do is when you
press the button it's going to increase
the counter by one and then print out
the button itself. So, let's go down here
and then let's set self.counter
+= 1, and then self.button
and we need to create this within
the confines of the method not just
within this function. So, let's go ahead and put
self.button and then we're going to
need to access it like that everywhere
we use it. So, now what we can do is
self.button.setText, and we're going
to set it to "Clicked: ", self.counter).
Let's actually remove the space there.
So, let's go ahead and I think we need
to pass a string in there actually.
Alright, setText...so let's turn this into
a string because right now it's an
integer, and then let's run it again and
you'll see each time I click the button
it's now going to count how many times
we've clicked the button.
Alright, so, that's all we're going to do
in this video, in the next video we're
going to learn how to manipulate
the line edit here.