Alright, so, what I'm going to be doing in
this video is teaching you guys how to
cope with data loss. Well, that's just a joke
actually because I just needed to delete all that,
but what we're actually going to be doing is
starting work on our calculator. So, this
is going to probably span a few videos
and then I also want to make a text
editor that can actually save files
stuff, and I also want to make a web
browser. So those are the three projects
we're going to be doing and I think we're
going to learn enough in those videos
that we can end the qt section there. I
was on my YouTube channel and I did a
pygtk tutorial a while ago, just for
the sake of it, and I was under the
impression that pygtk is not supported
anymore. I mean it's pretty obsolete and
I just thought you know that it was
obsoleted, but somebody commented on my
video and told me that it actually is
supported and maintained through I think
it was pygoobject,, or something like
that. So I will check that out and if
that's the case then we can get a fresh
Python binding library for gtk. I'd also
like to do some of that.
So, what we're going to do here we're
just going to focus on getting our
calculator application to run. so we need
to make some imports. So again import sys.
Let's go ahead and import from PyQt5
.QtWidgets we're just going to
import everything. from PyQt5.QtGui
we're going to import everything. And from PyQt5
.QtCore import everything. So those
are our imports, I just wanted to make it
simple so that we don't actually have to
go through each item that we need, so
just import everything and it will be fine.
So what we're going to do is we're
going to create our application. So as
with the last video it's going
to inherit qwidget, so let's go ahead and
type class Application, and it inherits from
QWidget, and then we're going to
initialize the application. And within
the initialization function we're going
to initialize the class that it has
inherited, so super( ).__init__( ). And then we're
going to set the title of our window, so
self.setWindowTitle, and I'm just
going to set mine to "Calculator" you guys feel
free to set yours to whatever you want.
So we've got the window's title set,
nothing would happened when we run this
yet because we're just declaring a
class. So, what we need to do is let's go
ahead and open our application at the
bottom here by running if __name__ ==
'__main__':, let's type app = QApplication, and we're
going to pass in sis.argv.
Our window is going to be Application, and
then we're going to type sys.exit and so
this system is going to make this
application exit when the
method that we passed it has completed,
so it's going to be app.exec. So let's
go ahead and run this file,
and we didn't show it that's right. Alright,
so, let's just type self.show right
in the init function, and there we go,
there's our application. So in the next
video we're going to be talking about
the grid layout specifically, and I'm
going to show you guys a couple of examples.