Alright guys, so what we're going to do
is as with our other videos that we've
done with qt so far we're going to
create an internal method, an instance
variable of the application object that
were creating, and we're going to
initialize the entire application from
within this method rather than the
initialization method. So let's go ahead and
def CreateApp. Alright, and then in
the init function here let's run
self.CreateApp. Now a few videos ago I
talked about different layouts, so we
talked about the vertical layout and the
horizontal layout, but what we didn't talk
about specifically because we're going
to be creating it now is the grid layout.
So I'm going to go ahead and create a
variable called grid, and it's going to
be equal to QGridLayout. Now, I'm going
to create a few buttons here and I'm
going to put them in here just to show
you guys how you can use the
QGridLayout. So let's go ahead and create
button1, and it's going to be equal to
QPushButton and it's going to say "One."
Button2 is going to say Q, I'm not sure why
I just unindented there but don't do
that,
QPushButton and it's going say "Two." And then button3 is going to say
QPushButton "Three." And let's go ahead and
create another QPushButton and it's
going to say "My last button." So I'm going to
save this, if we run it now nothing is
going to happen
let's just run the application, and we will see
that we don't see anything yet because
we haven't told the application to use
the grid layout, and even if we did we
didn't tell the buttons
to go into the grid. So we're going
to do that now, and how we do that is by
going grid.addWidget and this is
going to take a few parameters.
The first one is going to be the object
itself that we're adding, so in this case
it's going to be button1. Now
there's four more parameters, and I'm
just going to type them out and say them,
then I'll explain a bit. So this is row, this
column, this is rows, and this is columns.
So, this is going to say that it occupies 0
rows and it occupies 0 columns, so it's
not going to show it all. This is the
row numbe, so as with programming
the row numbers start with 0, so this is
0, 1, 2, 3. As you can see in my code editor
here there are four rows labeled
0-3. We want to put this in the
first row and in the first column. So,
let's say these are columns there's
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, so there's seven columns on each
row here so 0, 0 is going to be right
there.
Now we need to tell it how many rows it
is going to take up, it's going to be one row and one column.
one row and one column. So think about
this as it's pacing. I'm just going to go
ahead and self.setLayout we're going to
set the layout right now to grid, and
then show it, and then I'm going to show
you guys the application so far. As you
can see there is one grid item there. The
grid magically grows and shrinks to
accommodate how much space it needs, so I'm
going to show you guys that. What we're
going to do is go ahead and add another
widget here, so we're going to have the
second button on the first row in the
second column, and it's going to take up
one and one. So I'm going to save this and run
it again, and you're going to see that
now the row is split into two.
I'm going to go ahead and add the third
button here, on the first row, in the
third column, and it's going to take up one
and one. And then I'm going to add the
fourth button, it's going to be on row
two, in position one, and it's going to
take up one row and two columns, and
you're going to see how this is going to
look just based on that.
So, if we look at our grid we see two
rows as we have defined in the first
parameter after each object that we're
adding. So the first parameter after that that
were sending is the row. First row
and second row right there, or row 0 and
row 1. This is the column, so the first
column, second column, and third column
are these, and then on the second row we
actually see that this one takes up two
columns and that's because the final
parameter here, the number of columns
that it takes up, is set to 2. If I set that
to 3 and reran our application here, you'll
see that it takes up all of the space. So
that's an important concept as well, it's
basically just understanding how you
pack the grid within qt.