Alright guys, so in the next video, or in
this video I guess, what we're going to
be doing is we're going to be building a
web browser, and it's not going to be one
video because there's a lot of stuff to
cover, so it's probably going to be our
second project. So what we need to do
first off, we need to create a project. So,
I'm going to go ahead and create a pure
python project, and I'm going to call it
web-browser. We're going to be
using Python 3.5.2.1,
and yeah. So I guess 3.5.3 is out. I
haven't updated Python in a while, well since I
started doing this course actually.
Alright, so, once we've got our project
created we obviously need to create a
main file, so I'm just going to type main.py as
always, and we're going to start with a
few system level imports and what I
mean by that is just so that you know so we can
interact with the system like OS, sys, and stuff
like that.
So go ahead and write import sys, if that was spelled
correctly that would import properly,
import os. We are going to need json for
later on so I am going to import that, and now we need to
start importing our PyQt stuff. So,
we're going to be adding to this import
as we create new elements within our
application, so for right now we're just
going to do the bare minimum that we can
actually do. So, from PyQt5.
QtWidgets, so here we're going to
open up brackets
and we're going to start with
QApplication, QWidget, QVBoxLayout, QHBoxLayout,
we're not using the grid at all
here. We're going to say QPushButton, QLabel, we're
going to need a QLineEdit for the
address bar, QTabWidget, and in this
video we're going to be talking a lot
about tabs. So what you need to do is,
actually we don't need TabWidget we
need TabBar. And then what we're going
to do, and I'll explain it more in depth
as we go on, we are going to need QFrame,
this is going to be our main window, we
are going to need QStackedLayout, and I
think this is all we need to really
discuss right now. So, basically, with the
QVBoxLayout QHBoxLayout both of
those have all of their contents visible
at the same time, but the QStackedLayout
offers the ability to show a
certain widget that is in it as the main
widget, so you can switch back and forth. So,
we're not going to be using a tab widget
which includes both the tab bar and you
know each individual tabs content that
you can show when you click on a tab,
we're going to be using the QTabBar
specifically because we're going to
have our tab bar on the top, and then our
address bar, and then the tabs content. So
we need those two disconnected in this
way in order for this to work. Now we're
going to say from PyQt5.QtGui
import QIcon, we are going to be using
these, QWindow,
and I think that's all we need but I'm
going to go ahead and write QImage just
case because we might end up
using up using that. And from
PyQt5.QtCore import all, and I
think that's going to be good for right
now to actually get the tabs created and
whatnot. So what we're going to do is
let's go ahead create our main
application, so class App, and it's going to
inherit from QFrame and I'm going to
explain why in a moment. What we need to
do is we need to first initialize, and
we need to initialize the parent as
well, and then we're going to a set the
window title first so self.set...
...
aw.
Reactivate there because PyCharm
is open on my other computer there, so it
doesn't let you operate the
same license on multiple machines at the
same time.
Alright, so, what we're going to do is
self.setWindowTitle and we're going
to set it to "Web Browser" because that's
what we are going to be building. We're
going to set the base size because we
want it to open a certain size so that
it's not you know small, so self.set
BaseSize, and we're going to set it to
1366 x 768, and I'm doing that because I know
that my my other machine like my old
laptop had a resolution like this, no 16
by 9, so this is the first 16 by 9
resolution that pops up at the top of my
head here. And then we're going to just
basically get into it. So, we're going to
drop down here and create our actual
window, so CreateApp, and
this is what we're going to actually do
our stuff in. So we need to call it from
the initialization function, so self.
CreateApp, and then this is going to run
down here. So what we're going to start
off with is setting our main window
layout. So, let's go ahead and write
self.
layout = QVBoxLayout.
Simple enough. What we need to do now we
need to create our tab bar, so let's go
ahead and self.tabbar = QTabBar,
and we can pass arguments into this
to modify the way that the tab bar works,
and we're going to discuss that after,
but for right now this is fine. Now we
need to add tabs. So let me, let's just
add two tabs, I guess, so the tabs that
we're going to add are, they're just
going to have titles themselves. So, let's
go ahead and self.tabbar.addTab, and
it's going to say "Tab 1" and that's really
all you have to do to add a tab to this
type of tab bar. If we were using a
tab widget you would also need to send into
this ad tab method what widget the tab is
going to be responsible for. We're not
going to do that right now we're just
adding the tabs themselves just so we can
see them. Now we need to set the current
index of the tab bar, so this is going to
tell the tab bar which tab is active.
So it doesn't initialize with an
active tab, I don't think, so we're going to set it.
So, self.tabbar.set
CurentIndex, and the the index is
basically which tab in the row
of tabs
by an integer. So this should be tab 0, this should be
tab 1. So we're going to set it to the first
tab there. Now what we're going to do is
we're actually going to create our main,
well we can just put the tab bar
into a widget and then set the
widget, or set the layout to the widget,
so, yeah. What we're going to do is we've
got the layout, it's a VBoxLayout, so
we're going to add the tab bar to that,
and then set the layout of this app
to self.layout which is a
QVBox.
So let's go ahead and write self.layout.
addWidget, we're going to add self.
tabbar, and we're going to say self.
setLayout, and we're going to set it to
self.layout, so this is going to make
everything work. Now what we can do is
break out of here, and I believe we're
all done there, and say if __name__ == "__main__": so
we need to create am app, so app =
QApplication, and we need to pass sys.argv in here,
and then we're going to create a window
from our app class here, and then we're
going to say
sys.exit when app.exec is done
running.
So, let's go ahead and run this...
and I think I forgot to
show something. So, let me type in here
self.show. As you can see we've got our window,
the base size doesn't appear to have
worked, but we've got a window, it's got
tabs, and that's exactly what we want. So,
I'm going to comment something out, and
I'm going to use a tab widget to show
you guys what a tab widget is, and how it's
different.
We're not going to be using it, but it's good to know.
So we need to include QTabWidget, and
then I'm going to comment out this tab
bar declaration, and i'm going to say
self.tabbar = QTabWidget, and
then when we're adding tabs here we need to
actually send a widget as an argument
as well. So if you'll notice here I'm
going to say QPushButton, and the push
button is going to say "Tab 1" and then the
title is going to say "First Tab." I'm going to copy
this, and make that say "Tab 2." So, we're
gonna run this again and this is a tab
widget, and what you'll notice is that
when I use this it
automatically connects the widget, so you
could set the, when you add a tab set
the widget that it gets as a full, you
know, VBoxLayout, or a widget that
has a VBoxLayout and then stuff everything in
there, and then you could make actual
interfaces within each tab. But, we're
not going to do that specifically
because we need the address bar right
here. So, I'm gonna undo that, and this is
what we want for right now. So, in the
next video we're going to talk about I
guess making our
tabs a bit more dynamic.