Alright guys, in this video let's go
ahead and talk about loading up a
stylesheet. Let's talk about writing a
stylesheet and then loading a style sheet
into our application. So, what I'm going to do
is I'm actually going to jump back over
to my github repository here because
I've got a stylesheet written, and I
don't really want to write out an
entirely different style sheet where
it's already written. So, what I'm going to
do is we're going to write a few basic
styles, and then i'm going to just import
this,
ok. So, basically, let's look at something
that makes sense. You can target objects
by their class name, I guess, just like
this. If you have done any
web development you'll think, well that's
like targeting a div or a span, it's a
top-level element. Exactly, that's
essentially what this is. So what we're
going to do is let's go ahead and build,
and then you can import fonts and
everything, it's basically an entire style sheet.
So, Qt
basically allows the ability to use a
modified, slightly more restricted
version of CSS to style it's widgets and
elements, so let's get into that. What we
need to do is down here at the bottom our
QApplication is what we're going to be
targeting, and basically we're going to
be setting the stylesheet on that by
opening a file and then reading the
file itself. So, let's build the file
first. So I'm going to just go ahead and
create a new style sheet, and I'm going
to call it style.css. So
now once we got this style.css
written we can basically just
start to style the application, and so
the first thing that I'm going to do is
just style all the push buttons so
that we can just have something quick
done up. So, basically, just right QPush
Button, and then open the curly braces here.
If you guys don't know CSS it's not
something covering
this course, but there's a ton of web
development courses that you can look at. Or, this will probably makes more sense
if you don't want to go and take an
entire course just to learn a bit of CSS/
Search qt5 stylesheets, and they
actually have a reference right on the
Qt documentation, and it tells you what
widget you can style, and how
you can style them. So, I'm going to say
on the QPushButton that the border is
going to be none, so let's get rid of
those borders. The background is going to
be transparent, and padding, let's set the
padding to 10px. Go ahead and save this. I
haven't uploaded it into my application yet, so
you're not going to notice any any big
changes, and so in order to add the
stylesheet to our application again we
need to target the app variable here
that holds the QApplication, and we need
to just set the stylesheet on it. So
let's go ahead and open a file here, so
with open,
here it's going to be "style.css" and we're
just going to read it as style. We're
going to say app.setStyleSheet, and it's
going to be equal to style.read.
I'm going to save this and load up the
app, and we should notice a different push
button look. And we do, as you can see
our style sheets have taken effect. And
so let's style the tab a little bit.
What I'm going to do is jump back over to
my stylesheet, and you're going to
access this by accessing QTabBar,
that's the actual tab bar itself, and then
QTabBar then use these two little
colons
tab. So on the tab itself we're going to
say background is transparent, border
none, and then we're going to set a border on
the right-hand side and the reason is,
actually let's not set any border right now.
So I'm going to save this, I'm actually
going to put padding 10 pixels, and font
size is going to be 14 pixels. So save
this, and load it back up, and you'll see
that my tab now looks a lot bigger, but
you can't really define it from other tabs
because there's no border or anything. So what I'm going
to do now is style the address bar which
is a QVBoxLayout, it
is but I need to check the overlying
widget there, and I'm going to add an object
name to it I think. It's called the
toolbar so the toolbar is right here, and
there's no name on it yet, so self.
Toolbar.setObjectName, and I'm going to set
it to "Toolbar" Now what we can do with
object names in the CSS file right
here, you can use them as you would use an
ID in CSS. So just put a hash symbol and
then the name of the object, and what
we're going to do here is I'm going to set
the background to white, and border-bottom
is going to be 2 pixels solid, weird
kinda like gray color.
That didn't work,
let me try to figure out why. Alright,
I named it toolbar and that would explain why
it didn't work.
Alright, so when we load it up now we should
see a white toolbar and we do, so what
we're going to do is we're going to set
the selected tab we're
going to set that to white so it matches the
toolbar, and once I get more tabs added
here that'll make more sense.
So, let's go ahead and how we're going to
target the selected we're going to say QTabBar::tab::
selected, and each one of these is
separated by two colons. We're going to
say background is white, and the color of the
text is going to be dark, but when a tab is
not active
the color is going to be only kind of
dark. Now we're going to add border-right,
one pixel solid light gray, and now
you're going to see that this is
starting to look just like CSS. Once I get
multiple tabs you can see that the border on
the right makes sense, but if I'm selecting
this then first tab doesn't have a
border on the left. So what we're going to have
to do is manually add a border only to
the first child, and so it's basically
again just like normal style sheets. In
the same border-left is going to be one pixel
solid, light gray.
Now when I do this you'll see that each
of my tabs looks just about right,
exactly how it is. So, that's how to style
our application. It's really not that
difficult, and you can really make
Qt apps look exactly how you want them to
rather than just that native look,
because when you have a native look it's
neat in some ways to have an application
that looks native no matter what
platform it's running, but for instance
Chrome is not native. If I were to open
Chrome here, which isn't down here right now,
you would notice that Chrome doesn't
look different on
different platforms to enough of an
extent to say, hey, this looks native. You
know it doesn't look native. It's
kind of to match. If you're going to
deploy applications on multiple
platforms and you want a unique look so
that people can identify the look of the
thing with the product itself, you're
going to want them same style on every
platform, and so that's what we've done here.