Alright guys, welcome back. So, what I'm
going to do right quick is just copy my
style sheet from the main repository
here, where is it, right there. I'm going to
copy this into the browser, let me just open
it up in raw,
select all, and something really neat
that I just did, and that I do a lot, is use
keyboard shortcuts. I also don't have all
these icons in here, so I need to remove
these. I think that's the only instance
of the error.
Alright, so, if I restart the application
then it should look fine.
No, it doesn't but that's okay because
this style sheet was built for different
variables. So, but you'll notice the font
is actually roboto. I did something
with the size of the tabs too. So, let me
undo all that.
Alright, so, using shortcuts on your
keyboard actually is a really
essential part of any application
nowadays, and so we're going to be doing
that and we're going to be starting with
QShortcuts, and I'm going to show you guys
how to make one and then you guys can
make other ones for anything else. You
can also look it up if you'd like to. So
what we need to import up here is in the
Qt5 Widgets it's called
KeySequenceEdit, and QShortcut. So, I'm
going to type in here QShortcut and
QKeySequenceEdit, and we need these
two classes in order to actually create
shortcuts. So, what we're going to do is
just create a shortcut that will open a
new tab, so it's going to be a command
tab. I'm not sure, I've never tried
actually on Mac OS where command
takes the place of control on Windows, so
I'm going to try it. If it doesn't work
then I'm going to try another combination
just so we can get something working,
but basically it's really easy to do. So,
let's go ahead and write self.shortcut
NewTab equals QShortcut, and when we
instantiate this it takes a key sequence
which is basically what sequence of keys
we want pressed in order to target the
shortcut. So QKeySequence, and we
actually don't need key sequence edit
we need QKeySequence, where is that?
Did I already import it maybe with the
core? Where did I just write
that? I can't find it. Oh, it's down here in add
tabs. What I need to do is actually move
that way up here in the create app. So
the QKeySequence doesn't look like
it got imported, so I'm not sure if I
imported it with, oh ok, so it's within
QtGui.
There we go. Alright, so, where is, alright.
So we created a new tab shortcut. Now
we're opening up a
QShortcut, we're creating an object from
that, and that takes in one parameter, or two
parameters rather. The first one is a
QKeySequence, and the second one is just
the class name that target's it, so self.
Now the QKeySequence that we're
going to tie it is Cmd+T, and it's
really that easy. If you're on Windows
you're going to type Ctrl+T.
I'm on Mac so I'm going to try to make
this work here. What we need to do is we
need to connect the activated signal of
the shortcut to whatever method
we want to run. So, self.shortcutNewTab.
activated.connect, and we're
going to say self.AddTab. I'm going
to save and run it, and let's see if this works.
I'm going to go ahead and press command T, and
nothing happened.
So let me try, right now let's just Shift+T, and
this is not a good idea because Shift+T
is supposed to capitalize it here if
you're typing something, so there we go.
Shift+T works, Cmd+T doesn't. Let me
try setting this to Ctrl, maybe Qt
is smart enough to recognize well hey
this is not a Mac. So, we should use command,
and it does. Okay, so,
that's how you create a key shortcut
and it can be for any sequence of keys. You
can do for developer tools I use ctrl
shift
i in my Python browser that I already
built. Let's do a reload as well.
self.shortcutReload equals QShortcut,
QKeySequence, we'll say Ctrl+R, and
it's gonna be a shortcut on this
itself. And we're going to say self.
shortcut
Reload.activated.connect to self.
ReloadPage. So if I save this and
run it again
I'm going to press
Command+T, it opens up a new tab, and I'm going
to hit Command+R and you are going to see that it
refreshes it. So what we're going to be
talking about in the next video, I think
actually we've learned everything that
we really need to learn to make a web
browser and to get you guys familiar with
how Qt works. Essentially, you're taking
widgets, you're setting a layout, and then
you're stuffing other widgets into those
layouts. That's essentially all Qt5
is, and you can do really
awesome stuff with it. Now if you had a
icon here, let me just go try and
download a blank image, so logo png.
Sure, let's grab this PlayStation logo. I'm to
save it into my projects,
PycharmProjects. It is in,
what did I call this?
Web-browser.
So I'm going to come in here and I'm going to
save it right here as logo.png. Now when I
jump over here
it automatically picks it up. So what you can
do in the application is you can set the
app icon, so I'm going to run self.
setWindowIcon, and then we're going
to say it's QIcon, and it's going to be
logo.png. This can be a relative
path to the logo file itself. Now you'll
see that the logo got set right here it, it
should also get set on the dock, but I think
with Qt5 on Mac OS you have to do some
different stuff in order to get it to
set on the dock itself. I know
with the web browser
on windows you have to import
ctypes, then you have to run a command
up at the top, and I don't
remember specifically what it is. You
need to setup an app ID, essentially, and
then that will let it set the taskbar
icon from whatever you set right here. So,
I think that's it with Qt5. I hope you
guys enjoyed this and we're going to be
getting to data visualization I think
next, and then we'll come back, we'll
circle back around, to some other GUI
libraries, or I mean this is
probably fine.
So, what we'll do is we'll do some data
visualization and then i would like to
start on making video games in Python.