Hey guys, welcome back. So before we get
into data visualization there's a
few more things I want to cover with
Qt, and these are just to give you a
basic understanding of just a few more
concepts. And then I would like if you guys
wanted to go explore this further to do
so, you are completely encouraged to do
that. So the first thing I want to
talk about is the developer tools. So,
no, link or web engine based browser is
complete without developer tools. In fact,
no browser is complete without developer
tools. So, if you're not sure what I
mean, if I open up Safari here and let's
just go to Google, and I'm going to hit
command shift i, and it should...
ok, it opened up mail. Anyway, I will go into
developer, can I find it in here?
Show Web Inspector? Is that what I want? That's what they call
it. Alright, this is the developer tools.
It looks different in here than it does
in chrome. Safari uses a rendering
engine called WebKit, whereas chrome has
forked that. Chrome used to use WebKit, they forked
it, and they call it Blink now, and so
that's why these are kind of different.
Safari and chrome used to act a lot in
the same way, but now it's getting
different. So what we're going to do is
enable developer tools, and how we're
going to do that is right here before we
show the application we're going to set
environment variable called os, well
actually this is how we're going to
create the environment variable to tell
Qt that we
want to enable remote debugging, or the
dev tools within our browser. So, all you have
to do is type os.environ, and then the
the environment
variables name. So in this case it's all caps,
QTWEBENGINE_REMOTE_
DEBUGGING, and we need to set
that to a port number, or a full IP
address with a port number. In this
case I'm just going to be using a port
number because that's really all you
need to do. So I'm going to set this to 667,
and then when I start the application at
this point you're not going to notice
any big differences. Let me add a tab
here. We go to facebook.com, and I'm going
to jump over here and I'm going to open
another tab, and then we can
actually go to developer tools by visiting
local host at the port number,
ok. http://localhost:677 from whatever port
we've told to use developer tools on, and
it has rejected it. In order to access the
network, see I have had the same
problem here on...
Alright, I got this same kind
problem on linux when using developer
tools, so I'm really not too sure why.
Let me open up Chrome
and see if I can access the developer
tools for my browser from
Chrome.
Alright, so it can't. On Windows that's all
you have to do, let me search this here...
qt5 developer tools not working.
I'm not sure if there's extra steps that we
need to take. I mean additionally we could also
set the command line argument when we
run our application, or just set the
environment variable. So we're going to
try setting this right here, and then
we're going to echo that variable so that
should work. So I'm gonna go ahead and
close this, and then jump back over to
pycharm and run the app again, maybe it's
gonna work this time. No, alright, so
maybe it's being blocked in mac OS
and Linux which is really strange. I will have to search that and
if I can provide an answer for you.
The second thing I wanted to show you is
how to use a splitter. So what we're
going to do is where we add a tab here,
the top level, so we are going to use
QWidget and QVBoxLayout, but the top level that
we're going to do is actually going to
be a split layout.
So QVbox, that's fine actually,
what we're going to do is down here
where we add the content instead of
doing that we're going to say self.tabs[i]. splitter, or splitview, equals
QSplitter. And I need to import that from
somewhere I guess, so
let's go up here and try and find out
where that would be. I would imagine
that's in widgets, there we go.
So, where is that...alright. So what
we're going to do at this point instead
of adding our content to
the top level, we're going to add our
split view. So, instead of content
splitview, and then when I restart the
application you're going to notice that
you don't see any web pages and that's
because we haven't actually put it in there
yet.
All we've got is a splitview with nothing
inside of it. So what we're going to do
is we're going to add our content to the
splitview, so self.tabs[i].
splitview.addWidget, and we're
going to add self.tabs[i].content.
And now you'll notice that it looks
normal again, but what actually happened
is we've created one more level. So
initially we were just adding a
QWidget, and setting the layout to a QVBox
layout, and then adding one item so it
showed like this. Now what we're doing is
we're adding a QWidget, we're
setting the layout to VBoxLayout, and in
that VBoxLayout we're setting a new
object called QSplitter, and we're
inserting the page into there. So what
we can then do is we can then run this
multiple times, and actually add an
instance, it will add it's own self
again twice here. So, normally you would
add two different objects in there, and I think
we'll have to add two different objects.
Actually, so, I'll say content one and
then we'll go and reconnect content one
here from these two different things. So, there we
go.
Now you can see that I've got two views
here and I can split them, so
this should be interesting, you know, you
could set up devtools here, and you can
change it from horizontal, or vertical
to horizontal as well, and all you're
going to do for that is you're going to
set the splitter. So, self.tabs[i].
splitview.setOrientation, and
it's going to be Qt.Vertical. It's
going to be an orientation, so either
horizontal or vertical, and when I
run the application again you're going
to see that I've now got a vertical view
here rather than a horizontal
view. And so that's how you can use
QSplitter, and you can use this in a lot
of interesting ways. You can actually
modify it once it's created. You could add to the
splitter a row of buttons, and the
buttons could be connected to control
the orientation, or if it shows, and stuff
like that. So, I'm pretty sure that's all
we're going to do with Qt here. I
know we're doing data visualization, and
we're initially going to be exploring a
library called matplotlib to do that,
but I also understand that the Qt
framework has a charting library as well.
So we might actually circle around and
come back to Qt here in the next little
bit in order to do some data
visualization.