Alright guys, welcome back. What we're
going to get to now is just playing
around with the tab bar itself and I'm
going to show you guys how we can do
different stuff with it, because this is
going to be essential for going through
the rest of this video. We're going to be
using this tab bar and there are certain
things you can do with it, and this is
actually going to lead right into the
next video where we're going to talk about
custom window events. So at the bar here, if I put my
application here, you'll notice that
there's tabs, they're static, I gotta shut
down my PyCharm on my other machine I guess.
Alright, so, yeah those tabs are static, you
can't really do anything to them, so what we
can do is set some arguments when we
create the tab bar here. So the two
that we're going to be talking about are
movable and closable. So the two
arguments we need to pass in are movable
equals true, and tabsClosable equals
True. I'm going to save this and rerun our
application, and you're going to see that
now I've got these clothes icons and we
also can rotate the tabs I guess. So,
what you need to do you in order to
close the tab here is you
need to hook into an event, so signals
and slots. So what we're going to do is
we're going to connect tab close requested to our
custom method that will actually remove
the current tab. So what we need to do is
go self.tabbar.tabCloseRequested, and
this is a signal so you don't put
parentheses or anything,
.connect and we're going to connect
it to self.CloseTab.
I'm going to drop down here and I'm
going to define close tab, and this
takes in a parameter, I believe, we will
see in a moment. Maybe this isn't the one that
takes a parameter. Let me just print
out i and let's see if it does automatically send
the index of the current tab, or
the tab that has requested to close, and
it doesm cool. So, yeah, this connection
here automatically sends the tab that
should be closed, and then all we're
going to do is we're going to self.tabbar.
removeTab, alright.
Then pass in the index number of the tab you want to remove.
You want to save it, run the application
again, and there for some reason base size
come in there which is so strange.
Oh, let me create the app and then set
the base size, I think that's the problem,
there we go. So now when we close the tab
it actually closes. For some reason the window
there is jumping, I am not really sure why, we will figure
that out.
So, we can move the tabs, and close
the tabs, and we're also going to need a
way to add tabs, so what we're going to
do is we're going to create a window
border that we're going to add the tabs
to, and we're also going to add the close
button for the window. So this is going
to be a custom window border, it's not
going to have the native one, because we
don't want that we want
our window, our web browser, to have
tabs at the top. So, to explain that a bit
better what I'm going to do is we're
going to add widgets to the main
interface, so down here where we add
stuff to the layout, which again is a QVBoxLayout,
we're actually going to add first an address bar,
and then we're going to add the stacked
layout itself. So what we need to do for
the address for is we're actually going
to subclass that because we're going to
when you add a tab or when you press on a tab,
or when you press on the address bar,
it's going to automatically select all
of the content from within the address
bar. So class AddressBar is going to
inherit from QLineEdit, then we're going to
define init which is basically just
going to say super init, and then we're
going to define mousePressEvent, and so
basically if you want to modify events
for a widget or a class that comes
packaged with Qt, what you need to do
is you need a subclass it and then create a
method called what the event is called,
and then you can do whatever you want.
So we're going to say self, which is
the line edit, and we're going to say select
all. So that's the only reason we're really
subclassing that. So what we're going
to do is we're going to create the
address bar here, so I'm going to add
some comments here just to keep things
organized.
I'm going to say self.addressbar
equals AddressBar. And now what we're
going to do is we're going to add the
tab bar first, then the address bar, and
actually what we're going to do is we're
going to create a QHBoxLayout. So,
let's go ahead and create, what we need
to do first okay is add a H, we need to
add a widget, and then add the HBox
Layout to the widget, and then add the
address bar because we're also going to
be adding buttons like back and forward
buttons, so you guys will see what I mean
here. So self.Toolbar equals QWidget,
and then self.ToolbarLayout is going to equal
QHBoxLayout, and now what we can do is we
can add layout,
well we're going to set toolbars layout
to this toolbar layout. So self.Toolbar,
yeah that's right, setLayout, and it's
going to set to self.ToolbarLayout.
Now we're going to add our address bar
to the toolbar layout. So self.ToolbarLayout.
addWidget, we're going to add a self.address
bar/
Okay, so, now we've got our toolbar widget
that we can then throw into
the main layout under the tabbar. So self
.layout.
addWidget, and we're going to
add self.Toolbar. I'm going to save this and run
the application again, and now you're
going to see that...
...
Alright, so, let's go ahead and try that
again,
there. So if I click you see that it
selects all which is what we did when we
subclassed the QLineEdit there. Now
things still don't look right because
there's a lot of space in here,
so what we need to do is we actually
need to set the spacing to 0, and the contents
margin. So we're going to say self.
layout. setSpacing going to be 0, going to
refresh, and we're going to see that some spacing has
been removed, and then self.layout.
setContentsMargins(0, 0, 0, 0) and this is one for
each side. Now this has removed more
margin as you see there.
So, what we need to do at this point, so
we've got our address bar, we've got our
tab bar, but what we're going to do is
we're going to create a custom window,
and we're going to be doing that
actually in the next video.