Hey guys, I just recorded this video and
it was like 28 minutes, and then I
accidentally deleted it without saving
it. So, at least this time around I should
be able to make it quite a bit shorter
because i had a problem last time it was
really, really stupid problem, but you
guys won't see it, so that's neat. Alright, so, at this
point we have our application created,
and we have tabs created that we're able
to move around, and we've got an address
bar, but nothing does anything yet. So in
this video what I'm going to do is get a
stacked layout loaded in here, and get
web engine loaded. So, we need to talk
about the stacked layout a little more. When,
where is that? Stacked layout, it's not there.
Alright, so, I have not created it yet. So
what we need to do is we need to create
that, and how we're going to do that is
we're going to drop down
here a few lines and we are going to say set
main view, and down here we're going to
say self.container = QWidget,
and this is going to be added after the
toolbar. So you've got the tab bar, and you've got the
toolbar, and then you'll have this widget
which is going to have the stacked
layout inside of it. So container.
layout = QStackedLayout. Now we
need to set the containers layout to the
event handler, so self.container.
setLayout equals
self.container.layout. So, again we're
just telling this widget to use the
QStackedLayout. So when I save and
run the application, nothing happens
because we haven't actually added it to
the main window yet. So let's go ahead
and say self.layout.addWidget, and
we're going to add self.container.
Now this is being added after the
toolbar,
so it's under it because we're using
a vertical box, and as you can see that cleared
up a lot of spacing issues right now. So
you can see that it works but you can't
really see the stacked layout because we
actually didn't put anything in there
yet, and so that's what we're going to get
to now. We need an ad tab button and we
need to add that to the toolbar. So,
New tab button, so we're going to say
self.AddTabButton = QPushButton,
and it's going to just have a plus sign
for now. We are going to go through
here and put icons in here on the
toolbar buttons, but for right now we're
going to use plain text just because it's
easier, and then i'll show you how to set
icons and load icons at a later point. Now what
we need to do is connect AddTabButton.
clicked.connect and we need to
point it to the method that's actually
going to add tabs, and so that is going
to be called AddTab, which we're going to
have to create. So for now let's just create that
just to have it created, and we're just going to
pass. Now we need to add that into the
tool bar itself, so self.ToolbarLayout.
addWidget, and I'm going to add
self.AddTabButton. I'm going to save
this, run the app again, now you're going
to see there's a new tab button but it
doesn't do anything yet, so let's make
it do stuff.
Let's go ahead and delete the tabs that
we've got created right now just because
we're not going to need them,
we're going to be are calling AddTab
immediately so there is always a tab
active. Now we need to create a few
variables, and let's create them right
here. So,
it's for keeping track of the tabs and
the corresponding tab content, because
they're separate object. So, self.
tabCount = 0, and then we're going
to increase that each time a tab is
created and then use the tab count
within the object name, and we haven't
talked to the object names yet so that
is going to be fun. And then we need a
second variable called self.tabs, and
that is going to contain not the tabs
themselves but every widget that belongs
to a tab.
So the tab objects not the tab in the
tab bar. So, when we add a tab the first
thing we need to do is get the tab count,
so self.i equals self, not self.i,
i = self.tabCount. And then we need
to start adding stuff to the self.
tabsList. Now how we're going to do this
is we're going to append a QWidget to it,
and then use this index number
to access that widget. So, self.tabs.
append(QWidget( )), just like that. Now we can
modify that widget itself by calling
self.tabs[i], and then this is
going to access that QWidget, so we
can treat this little bit of code here
the same as a QWidget because it's
targeting a QWidget. So we're going to
set layout first, and that's going to be
equal to QVBoxLayout. And then we're
going to set the object name and I'm
going to demonstrate why it's important,
but i'll demonstrate that later. So, self.
tabs, and the tab we just
created, the QWidget that we just created,
we're going to set object name and we're
going to set it to "tab"
+ i,
and we actually need to convert that
to a string before we use it. Now we're
going to create an attribute for the
QWidget called content, and the
content is going to be the QWebEngine. So
before we even do that we need to now
import WebEngine. So from
PyQt5.QtWebEngineWidgets import everything,
and then we're going to scroll back down
to our add tab method here, and we are
going to create the web engine view
which is the actual object that the
page is going to be loaded into, and its
really simple to do. So let's just go
ahead and write self.tabs current
tab content equals QWebEngineView,
and that's an object so open a parenthesis.
And then we're going to load google
immediately into this view. self.tabs[i].
content.load, we need to create a
QUrl.fromUserInput, and then just type
"http://google.com" So, QUrls
you're able to run this method on it
as soon as you declare it here,
this method is going to convert text
into an actual QUrl that Qt can
then use to do stuff, and now we need to add
this content to the the tabs layout
itself, and again this is a QWidget and
so it can be shown and it can have a
layout set on it, so we access this
object again by typing this. So let's go
ahead and set the layout, so self.
tabs[i].
setLayout, and we're going to set it to self.
tabs[i].layout. I'm going to comment
this here so you guys will have an easier
time following along, set top level tab from
list to layout. Alright, now we need to
add the content to the layout itself so we're going to
do that here,
add webview to tabs layout. We're going
to say self.tabs the current tab, layout.
addWidget, and we're going to add self.
tabs current tab content. Now we're
almost done, I promise guys, so what we
need to do is we need to set the
container which is the stackedlayout
right here, we need to add this widget,
the the QWidget that we've
stuffed into the tab, we need to add this
to the container, and then we need to set
the current widget to the widget that
we've just added, and how we're going to
do that we're going to just type out
self.container.layout.addWidget
and we're going to add self.
tabs and the current tab. So, again this
basically equals a QWidget which we've
defined here. And then self.
container.layout.setCurrentWidget, and I'm
going to set it to self.tabs and
the current tab. Alright, now we need to
show the tab at the top of the screen
like as an actual tab. So, this is going
to be a bit easier, set the tab at top of
screen. self.tabbar.addTab
and we're going to add "New Tab." And then
what we need to do is remember up here
where we set the object name of the top
level widget right here, we set that to
tab and then whatever number of tabs it
is, so what we're going to do is we're
going to set the data of, and let me show
you.
So this tab right here when we click it
we need to be able to tell the stacked
widget which widget to show. Now that's
fine but there's going to be a problem
when we do this it won't know,
like it actually changes the index
number of this, so if we say get a
current index of this this is now going
to be 0, if we drag it over here it's now
one, but the content, the QWidget within
our tabs list didn't change, so it's
going to show the wrong content. So what
we're doing is we're setting an object
name and we're going to use the object
name so we need to actually tell the tab
what you know basically what object
name it should control, and so we're
going to say setTabData, and we're going to
say "tab"
and then the index number here,
and then we need to set the current
index to this current tab. So self.tabbar.setCurrent
index and we're going to say this
right here. So, go ahead and save...
set the tab data, oh, alright. To set the tab data you need
to tell it what you know is the
index number of the tab you want to
modify, so there we go.
If I add a tab you're going to notice
that we haven't actually built
functionality for switching tabs so it
is constantly shows whatever tab was
loaded first, so we need to do that and we're
going to do that in the next video.