Hey guys, before we get into switching
tabs and stuff, one thing that i actually
forgot
in the last video is here we actually
need to increase self tab count at the
end of each instance of adding a tab. So,
just jump up here and write self.tabCount
+= 1. Now what we need
to do is be able to switch tabs, so we
actually need to hook into that when you
click on tabs. So right here we need to
write self.tabbar.tabBarClicked.
It's a signal so remove those brackets
and type connect. And here we're going
to say self.SwitchTab. Now as with
the close tab we don't need to send
anything else with the method. It's
automatically going to receive an index
number of which tab you clicked. So let's
drop down here and create the switch tab
method. So, def SwitchTab, and this is
the index number of the tab we want to
switch. So, what we're going to do is
we're going to, I'm going
to show you guys the wrong way how to do it
so that you guys will understand
why we're doing it this way. So we have
a tab, you might think we'll just
be able to set the current widget by
that, and so what we'll do is self.
container.set.layout,
sorry about that,
.setCurrentWidget and we're going
to set it to self.tabs[i], and
that is the widget itself as we did here.
This isn't going to work even though
it is getting the index number there and
I will
show you guys what happens. So we've got one
tab, this is tab 0. So now I'm going to do
stuff in this tab and this page is
different. Now I'm going to add a tab, and
you'll see that it did show a new tab,
and now I'm going to say YouTube, and
I'm going to go to YouTube in this tab.
So tab 0 is the Google results and tab
1 is YouTube, and if I switch
tabs it works. See that works very well,
however the the index number of these
tabs updates when you rearrange the tabs.
So if I take tab 1 and make it tab 0,
now it's going to show tab zero's content
because it has become tab 0. And so what
we need to do is we need to get the
object name. That's why we're using object
name to make sure we're getting the
correct thing. So, we need to get the tab
data of the tab that was clicked. So, td
for tab data equals self.tabbar.
tabData, and we need to just pass in
the index number. So this is going to
return the object name of the object
that we want to switch to. So as you can
see tab and then td. I'm going to
print this for you guys so can see that it
doesn't matter if we switch tabs,
it's still going to recognize it. So, add
a tab, so tab one is now just the google
results and tabs 0 is, well just google,
and tab 0 is the actual tabs. So as you can
see when I click on it down here it
said tab 0 because that is tab 0, tab 0
equals the google results. When I click
on this it says tab 1 because tab 1
equals the google page that has no
results. Now when I drag it this still says
tab one, and that's because we set
that data. So it doesn't matter how you
rearrange them, it's always going to
have a static
tab data. So what we're going to do is
we're going to set the tab contents,
well I'm going to write this out, tab
content equals self.findChild.
And then the first argument we pass
through here is what kind of child
we're looking for, what type, and the
type is QWidget.
The second thing we need to pass through
is the name, the object name, of the thing
we're trying to find, and so that is
going to be tab,
actually it's just going to be straight
up the tab number as defined here in this
variable. So, let's just type td or tab
data. I'm going to make these variables more
intuitive here.
So, what we're going to do is use this
now which has the correct tab content
stored in this variable, we're going to
use that to switch tabs. I'm going to save
this and refresh our application, and
you're going to see that it works
exactly how we want it to now. So this is
the page with content in it,
ok, it's going to be YouTube, well I can't
use that yet, right.
So we all right we're set up.
Ok, that was a...
I clicked on something wrong
there.
Let's try this again. So this is the
result,
this one's going to be YouTube,
there. Alright, let's open up one more
and go to digg.com.
Alright, so, now we've got tab 0 is google,
tap 1 is YouTube, and tab 2 is digg. So
now when I rearrange this tab 1
becomes digg. This now has an index number
of one, but it's still correct in loading
the correct content,
and that's exactly what we want. So,
that's why we're doing object names when
we switch tabs so we can get the correct
object. And think about it like this,
if you have ever done anything with web
design when you set an ID on an HTML
element that's essentially the exact same
thing that is happening here.