Alright guys, so, what we're going to do
now is actually make our address bar
work, and how we're going to do that is
we're going to create a method called
browse to, and we're going to hook into
that and we're going to connect that to when
enter is pressed in the address bar. So,
let's define a BrowseTo, and the first thing
we need to do is get the text
within the address bar. So we're going to
say text...
yeah, text = self.addressbar,
that's lowercase, text is it?
Yeah, let me print that out and let's try and,
well what we need to do now is hook into
address bar, here it is. So,
self.addressbar.returnPressed, we're
going to connect that to self.
BrowseTo, and again remove the
brackets when you're connecting the
signals, unless you use a lambda which we
don't need to use. So, I'm going to type
and hit enter and we are getting the
text from the address bar, that's
exactly what we need to get. So, what
we're going to do is we need to get the
index number of the current tab, then get
the tabs data, and then get the widget
to load into. So how we're going to do
that is what we're going to do is say
i = self.tabbar.currentIndex,
and then tab is going to be
equal to self.tabbar.tabData and we're going to
pass in i so we can get the name, and
then we're going to say wv for webview is
going to be equal to self.findChild
and remember the first parameter is the
type, so QWidget, and the second is the
actual name, so tab. QWidget the W
needs to be capitalized, there we go.
So, what we've got here is a progression
we're getting the index number of
the current tab, then we're getting the
tab name from that tab, and then we're
getting the webview that's associated
with that name because the object name
of the tab content is that. So,
actually content because this is going
to be the QWidget, right, and this is
going to be the content object within it.
So, now what we can do is we can say wv.
load, and then we go QURLfromUser
Input, and then we pass text in there.
Alright, so, well we want to do a little
bit of modifying first, so let's create
another variable called url. So, if "http"
not in text this means it's either going
to search or it's going to need to be
formatted, so we need to do another check.
if "." not in text we can now tell
that it is a search, so url = and
for what we're going to do here we're
gonna bring up
this and then we're going to go to Google, and I'm
going to get the URL that we need to use
to search on Google, and as you can see
it's right there. So I'm going to copy that
over here. So url is going to be that plus
whatever we searched for,
else we're going to format URL. So, url
equals HTTP plus text.
If HTTP is in text, we just need to say
url equals text. So now we've got three
functions that are happening here with
the address itself. So I will load it up and
then I'll explain more. So we've
already got a tab, what I'm going to do
is go to youtube.com, and as you can see
it's formatted the URL to allow me to jump
over to youtube.com. But, if I search
for, or if type, how to make pizza
it recognizes that there's no HTTP
there's also no dot in there, so it's not
a URL and we could use regex to get the type,
or match it to really test it if it's URL, but
this is just a more simple for right now.
So, that's going to search but then also
if we go http://youtube.com it already
knows that we've got HTTP in there so it
doesn't prepend that to the URL. So that's
working now I want to talk about signals
of the actual web view, and I'm going to
do that the next video.