Alright guys, so this gets a little
confusing, so I'm going to try and step
through it. I'm going to try to also use variable
names that explain things exactly how I
think would make most sense.
So if you guys remember, and I want to
make a little comment here under add tab,
I've changed this, alright, so we can
keep the number of it's initial position.
So, go ahead and create a dictionary and
the first key is object, and then
that's the tab of the number, so it
should tab 0, tab 1, etc. based on
how many times this tab count has
increased. And then the second key is
going to be initial and that values is i, so
I have changed that. What we're going to
do, I'm going to erase this, I'm going to
create a comment kind of as a helper, and why don't we do this. So, basically what
we've done here is we've set tabs object
name, so self.tabs[i].objectName equals
tab1, and then the tabbar self.
tabbar.tabData(i)["object"] that is
equal to the same thing, or it should
be. This is going to get the tab itself that
controls this tab object. I'm going to
copy this because what we're going to do
is we're going to connect some web view
events, basically. So, we want to
be able to update the tab's title text
every time the title of the page changes.
Now, we're in luck because web view
actually emits that signal. So, let's go
ahead and type self.tabs[i].
content.page, actually titleChanged.
connect, and we're going to reference, we
need to use lambda because we need to
pass through this index number here as
that is tab, you know we can get the name
from it. So, lambda: self.Set
TabsText, and we're going to send the index number
through. So what we need to do is jump down
here under our browse to method
and create that, so SetTabTitle. So,
what did set it to? SetTabText.
Alright, I'm going to paste my comment
here, because what we need to do is we need to
get the object name of the tabs content
itself. So this is how we're going to get
the object name, we just you know extract
object name. So,
tab_objectName = self.tabs, and
then you know whatever tap admitted the
the signal, and then object name. And then
what we need to do is we need to set a
for loop here, why is this, oh it's just one
too many lines.
Alright, cool, whatever. What we need to do...
alright let's ignore that.
I'm violating so many pep guidelines
right now it appears. Remember set tab
text method should receive your next
number there. So, this is for example
going to be tab1, that's what this is
going to return, that's the tab object name.
So now we need to basically iterate
through each tab, and then check if the
tab data object key in the dictionary
equals the tab name. So how we're going to
do that is we're going to do a pretty
standard thing here in Python, we're
going to set a count variable equal to 0,
so it's going to start at the beginning of
the list, and we're going to set running
equals true. And then while running what
we need to do is we need to get the tab
data of the tab, and
it's going to iterate through tabs so
it's going to return a bunch of tab data
here until it finds the correct one.
So, I'm going to say tab_data_name
equals self.tobbar.tabData, and
then we pass through count. Now what we
need to do we need to set a cut off
limit for right now, we can remove this
later. So if count is greater than or
equal to 99 we need to set running to
false. Just quit out of here, and then what
we're going to do is if tab_name equals
tab_
data_name, it's going to get the actual tab so object name
right there.
Sorry, I coughed there.
Alright, so tab object name right there
and I'm just going to set this up to tab_name just to make things simpler. So we've got tab_name
which is extracted from the actual tabs
list, and then we've got tab_data_name
which is iterated through the tab bar
itself. Now we check if tab_name equals
tab_data_name, and then the objects
within the data. If that equals each
other we've got the correct tab and we
now need to update the title text. So
what we're going to say is self.tab
bar.setTabText. Now we know that
the count variable is correct at this
point, so then we just need to set it to
the to the web views title. So, newTitle
is going to be equal to self.find
Child, and then we're going to find
QWidget with the name of tab_name, and then
content.title. So this, for example, when
the signal's emmitted on the web
view itself, this right here is going
to be set to the new title. So then we
just pass the new title into the set
tab text, and it should work. Now at this
point we need to set running to false so
that the while loop stops, but if they
don't match we need to increase count by
one. So if I run this, and again all this
is caused because we can move tabs, so
you can see that the tab title was set
correctly. Now if I go to facebook.com
for instance, it can see that this is set
correctly. Now when I add a new tab, I'm
really not sure why this jumps around
i'll try to figure that out,
and I go to youtube.com this one updates
correctly. Now if I switch them, switch back
to the facebook one, and go to google.com
you'll see that the correct one switches,
and again that's because we've got the
tab name extracted from the actual tab
that emits the signal that the title
has changed. And then we iterate through
all the tabs until we find one where the
tab data name object name actually equals
the tab name, and then we know
ok there's a match so this works. So that
was the big thing for this video, we're
going to cover more about how to
interact with web engine here soon.
This is probably just the most difficult
thing we're going to have to do.
Everything else is a lot simpler.