Alright guys, what we're going to do is
actually modify the set tab text method,
so we can also set the icon at the same
time. So what we're going to do is we're going
to pass through another parameter here
and it's going to be a type, so this is
going to be title, and then we're also
going to send it through as icon for when icon
changes. So, self.tabs[i].content.icon
Changed.connect, I'm going to open it with
lambda and say self.SetTabContent.
Change this as well, and we're going to send it
through with the index number, and this
is going to be called icon. So, we are
going to add some conditionals to this
method here to basically determine if
it's title or icon, because most of the
functionality of those two changes are
the same. So let's also pass through
types. So, if type equals title, and we
also need to update the method name to
content so it's now set tab content, so
if type equals title do that.
elif type equals "icon": set newIcon
equal to self.findChild(QWidget,
tab_name).content.icon, and then
we're going to just update the icon in the same way.
So the tab bar has icons that you can
set, so setTabIcon.
The index is going to be a count, and
then the new icon that we are going to set is
newIcon, and it's in a QIcon format.
And then regardless of which type it was
we set running to false. Save this, run the
app again, and we should get an icon
there, and we do. And this should also
work when we go to Facebook, it should load up
Facebook's icon, put it in the correct tab, and
it does. So, that's what we want to do
here and we also want to remove some of
that space. So let's go up here, and I
believe it's in the tabs
virtualbox layout. So let me go ahead and set self.
tabs[i].layout.setContents
Margins, and 1, 2, 3, 4 and
there's four zeros for west, north, east, and
south. That looks a bit better. I need to
find out why it's jumping there, I think
it's because up here...
let's move that,
open up a new tab...I don't know why that
set based size would make it jump
on Mac OS because it doesn't do the same
thing on on Windows. So, I'm really not sure,
but what we're going to do is set
minimum size there so that it can only
be a minimum size of say 1366.
So self.setMinimumSize, it's going to be 1366 x 768, and
then let's go ahead and open it. Does it
jump around?
No, everything looks like it's working. So now
I'm going to set the base size,
maybe it was just both of those weren't
set, so hopefully this sets it correctly.
There, looks better.
Alright, so, what we're also going to do
here we're going to clean up one other
thing, and that's just the tab bar
here. Alright...
so we also have to do some more checks there.
Basically, when we added this call
right here we would check that, rather
than just getting the tab. We were
actually getting something else
further, and so what it's doing is when
you click on the tab bar anywhere
you know it switched tabs. So, what we're
going to do is you can set draw base, so
self.tabbar.setDrawBase, and
we're going to set that to false, and that's
going to not draw that little
area right here. And so that's all
we're going to do right now. In the next
video we're going to be adding some more
webview functionality.