Alright, so, now what we're going to do is
add some more functionality when it
comes to actually modifying the web view
of the current tab, and how we're going
to do that is we need to find our
toolbar here where the address bar is
and we need to set some buttons. So, set
toolbar buttons. So for instance we're
going to have a self.BackButton, and
that's going to be equal to QWidgets.
QPushButton actually, and for right now it's
just going to show a left arrow.
And then self.ForwardButton = QPushButton
button, and it's going to show a right
arrow. And what we need to do is now
connect these two methods that will make
the current web view go back and forward,
and so self.BackButton.clicked.connect and
we're going to connect it to self.
GoBack.
Same thing for forward. self.Forward
Button.clicked, going to connect that
signal to self.GoForward. And we
don't need to worry about what tab
we were on when we clicked these buttons
because these are global buttons, but we do
need to get the active tab once these
are clicked. But, before we even do that we
need to add the buttons to the toolbar.
So, self.ToolbarLayout.addWidget, and we're
going to add self.BackButton. And then
under that, self.ToolbarLayout, add
Widget, and we're going to add self.
ForwardButton. So I'm going to save
this, and basically at this point we
should have a toolbar that has a back
button, a forward button,
an address bar, and the add tab button. Let's go
ahead and run the application, and we
actually need to create these methods
before it will work.
So let's drop down here, and let's just
create them, I guess. So,
GoBack, pass, and def GoForward, pass. It
would be awesome if I could type today. I
must be sitting angled just
incorrectly. So as you can see now we've
got a back button and a forward button
there actually rigged to the
functions that we just created, but they
don't actually do anything yet. So what
we need to do is get the current tab, or
active tab when we click these, and we
need to get the object with the object
name equal to this tab data object, and
then we can tell this web view to go back.
So, it sounds more complicated than it is,
but all it is, is active index, so this is
going to be the active tabs index number
is self.tabbar.getCurrentIndex, or
just currentIndex.
So this is going to tell us what tab is
currently active. Now at that point we
need to get the tab name, so it's going to be
equal to activeIndex, actually
equal to self.tabbar.
tapData(activeIndex),
and then object. So this is the object
key within the tab data property. And
then what we need to do is we need to
get the object of the tabs, so tab_content
equals self.findChild, we're looking for
a QWidget with the name tab_name, and then
we're going to access content here. So,
this is the actual web view, and then all
we need to do is type tab_content.
goBack. Let's go ahead and restart this, and
let's start by going to a few websites.
So the first one we're on is Google, let's go to
Facebook, let's go to YouTube, and let's
go back...webengine, okay. We actually need to
access page in here. So the web engine
view
has a property called page which is
equal to a web engine page, and with a
web engine page you can do stuff like this. So, let's go
ahead and load this, no. Is it just called
back?
I got something wrong. I might have to search this
here in a moment.
Ok, if this doesn't work, if it isn't in
the actual content, then I'm just going to
go ahead and search it.
Okay, that looks like it works. So,
facebook.com, and then hit back, and it goes
to Google. Alright, now the address bar
doesn't update yet and we're going to get to
that in a moment as well. I just want to make
sure this works. So, we're already on
Google so let's go to youtube.com, and
then once we're on youtube.com let's go
to digg.com. Now if I go back it goes
back to youtube, and then to Google. So
that's working. Essentially, the forward
method is the exact same. So we get the
active tab's index number, then we get the
name of that tab that we need to
actually get the content from, so self.
tabbar.tabData, and then the
tab data we're trying to access is of
the active tab, and then we get the object
key value of the tabs data. Now let's get
tab_content equals selfs.findChild,
QWidget, tap_name.
content, and then tab_content.forward.
So, if I go to facebook.com, and then
youtube.com, now I should be able to
navigate between these however many
times I want simply by using the back
and forward buttons. And it looks like
that is the case. However, the address
bar still isn't getting set. Before
we do that I want to talk about the
reload function, and so let me come up
here to the buttons. We need to create a
reload button, so self.ReloadButton, and
it's going to be equal to QPushButton,
and for now it's going to be a capital
"R" because we're not going through and
adding icons to these buttons. We will go
over that at some point I'm sure.
So, when you click the reload button
we're going to connect that to self.
Reload, ReloadPage. And then drop
down here to under the back and forward
methods, and let's define ReloadPage,
and the same thing the active tabs
index equals self.tabbar.
currentIndex. The tab_name is going to equal
self.tabbar.tabData of the active
index, and the tab data we're
specifically interested in is it's object
key value, and then tab_content equals
self.findChild,
QWidget we are looking for with tab_name,
and we're looking for the content
attribute, and then tab_content.reload.
So, I think we need to add that button
to the toolbar as well, I don't think we did that.
So self.ToolbarLayout.
addWidget(self.ReloadButton).
Save this, re-run our application, and we
now have a reload button. If I click it,
it reloads, and that's all for this video.
So, I look forward to seeing you guys
again, and let's get into more stuff with
web view.