Alright guys, welcome back. So what you're
looking at right here this is basically
the work-in-progress browser that I had
built in Python, and essentially what
we're aiming to do here in this course is
alot of the functionality of this browser
has been completed, and what actually
happened was I realized that
building a web browser in Python is not
necessarily the best idea just because
it's really difficult to deploy, because
it's Python. So, what I've done is
actually started rebuilding this in C++ and
it's called the Eden Browser. If you
guys want to see it, or see the
material design browser in Python, I
mean all that is here, you can go into
source and you can look at the entire
browser's code which is pretty neat. And
you can custom style Qt
applications, and that's what we're going
to be covering I think in the next video,
and this is a draggable custom window
border, and these buttons are all custom, and
I'm going to show you guys how to do
most of this and we're not going to
focus on importing dev tools, but you
guys can check out the source code that
I have on the GitHub account. And then
also if if you want to see the new C++
version it's called Eden Browser, it's
right here, and if you guys want to learn,
if you like Qt so far, and you want to
learn it and be able to deploy apps easily,
and you're thinking about learning C++, I
might be putting together that course in
the near future as well. So, if I do
I'll set a notice in this course
just in case you guys want to check it
out.
So, what we're doing for this video is we
are going to, if I start the app here,
where we left it off this updates, the tabs
update correctly, but the address bar doesn't.
So there's a signal in the web view
the same as title changed or icon
changed, it's just called URL changed, and so what
we're going to do where our add tab method is
here we're going to basically
copy this line except we're going to set
the URL in the address bar, instead of
the icon or title. So, let's go ahead and
type self.tabs, and this right here
is the main QWidget which has the
web browser in it, or the web view.
Content is the web view itself and so the
web view, the web engine view right here, is
what emits the signal URL changed.
So, then I'm going to connect that, we're
using lambda so that we can also send
through parameters, again, we're gonna say
SetTabContent, and we're going to send
the index number, and then we're going
to send URL as the type. Now in the set tab
content what we're going to do right
here at the top, we're going to basically
just...we're going to check if the
active tab matches this tab. So, let's
get the active tabs working name, I guess
we'll call it, so current_tab equals
self.tabbar.tabData, and we're
gonna say self.tabbar.current
Index. Then we need to target the
object and that's going to give us the name. So,
we can basically say if
current_tab equals tab_name and
type equals, what was it, "url": So
that's our condition here. So if the
current tab is equal to the active tab
then we know that we're on that tab, so
the address bar should be related to
that tab, and it should update when that tabs
content changes. So, we're gonna go ahead
and set the address bar, so let's go
ahead and get the URL of the tab. So, self.
tabs[i].content.url, or do I
need to get it?
I need to find the
child, so self.findChild. It's going
to be a QWidget with the name tab_name,
and then we're going to access content.
url, and this is going to return a
QUrl which we need to convert toSting.
So, this is the new url, and then
we're going to say self.addressbar, lower
case, setText, and the text is going to
be new_url. We're going to save this, and
now it's still going to run this.
So what we need to do is put thatn in an else
statement, or we could just return false
here. And if we return it's not going to
do anything else. Let's go ahead and
restart the application, and now you'll
see that it updated in that tab. So when
I open this tab, oh
we're going to go over QShortcuts
soon too. So, facebook.com we'll see that that's updated
here, and when I switch tabs it's still
updated. So what we need to do is we need
to hook into the switch tab method and
we need to update the URL every time we
switch tabs as well. So, here's the switch
tab method, so let's go ahead and get the
URL of the
tabs content. So new_url equals
tab_content.url.toString, and
again the tab content itself we're
actually going to need to access content
within tab content. So this should
really be called tab widget, because this
right here that's highlighted that is a
QWidget, it's not the content. So, let's go
ahead and this is now going to focus in
on the web engine view, it's going to get the url,
it's going to convert it to a string so that
we can do stuff with it. So, now let's go
ahead and change the address bar. So
self.addressbar.setText
is equal to new_url. Go ahead and save this,
and then the application, and I'm going
to switch the tab here to facebook.com. Now
Facebook here has it's URL but when I
switch to Google you'll see that it updated
correctly, and it doesn't matter how I
drag these because we resolved all
that dynamic numbering of the tabs, we
solved that problem in one of the
previous videos. So that is how you do
that. Now it's starting to look like a
more complete browser.
We've got back and forward functionality,
we've got refresh functionality, do we? I
think we did do that, one sec...that would be down
here.
Yep, ok. So it did reload,
it's just nothing changed so nothing
updated. We've got a tab button. So, 'NoneType'
object is not subscriptable...
Ok, so, what this basically is
doing right here when we click the tab
bar, if we click it in a place where there's
not a tab, none of our methods can run. So,
when we, what is it?
I guess I would just call self add tab.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to say,
not add tab it would be
switch tab, that triggers switch. So
what I'm going to do is I'm going to say if
self.tabbar.
...
tabData.
So this is going to make it basically if
there's tab data then we know that we've
clicked on a tab, so we should run this.
Otherwise, it shouldn't run, and it
shouldn't crash, and as you can see it's
not, but our switching tabs should still
work, and it does, but now when we click
on the tab bar that's not on a tab we don't
get that error. So, now we've got a
working address bar too. What we're
going to be doing in the next video I
think we're going to be talking about
styling things, so we can get that done,
and then we'll talk about shortcuts and
stuff like that.